Haul out the holly
we're headed home so we can
start to celebrate.
Fill up the stockings
we may be rushing things but
we can hardly wait now.
For we need
a little Christmas
right this very minute
candles in the window
carols at the spinet.
Yes, we need
a little Christmas
right this very minute.
It hasn't snowed
a single flurry
Fozzie, we're all in a hurry.
Guys, this is the best
idea we've had in years.
Christmas at my mother's farm.
Sounds great Fozzie, but don't you think we
should have called your mother.
To let her know we were coming?
Oh, how little you
understand bears Kermit.
My mother loves surprises!
- Good thing. She's in for a beauty.
- Surprise, surprise!
You see, I know what she
is doing this very second.
There she is in the
old farmhouse
on the snowy hill,
nice and cozy by a roaring fire.
Oh, the Christmas
decorations will be up...
And ma will be in her
rocking chair, knitting...
And feeling just a little sad,
that she's all alone
for the holidays.
Well, the plane leaves for
California in three hours.
Ho-ho, Christmas in Malibu!
Ah, I'm going to lie on the
beach and catch some rays.
Wocka, wocka!
Oh, this is going to
be such a surprise!
Haul out the holly
turn on the
brightest string of
lights we've ever seen.
Slice up the fruitcake
it's time we
hung some tinsel
on that evergreen bough.
For we need a little music
need a little laughter.
Need a little singing
ringing through the rafter
and we need a little
slappy happy ever after.
We need... a... little
Christmas
now.
Well, I think I have everything.
Yes, the airline ticket,
my suntan lotion, the...
Come in!
Hello! Is this Grizzly Farm?
Oh, you must be the renter.
Come in, come in!
Yes, yes, I'm doc.
Are you my landlady?
No, Sprocket, I didn't know
I was renting from a bear.
Oh, mind your step!
Be careful. There's an
icy patch there. Oof!
I'm so glad there's someone going to be
staying in the house while I'm gone.
Yes, well, Sprocket and I...
He's my dog, Sprocket.
We're certainly delighted
to be renting the place.
We've been wanting to spend a nice,
quiet Christmas in the country.
You've come to the right place.
Put your things in the bedroom
- at the top of the stairs.
- Thank you.
Now who could that be?
Ta-da! Merry Christmas!
- Son!
- Mom!
Ahh!
- Oh, it's so good to see you.
- Well, what the... a surprise!
No, no, the real surprise is...
- I brought all my friends with me!
- What?
Come on, everybody!
Merry Christmas!
Be careful of the icy patch.
Yeah, that's terrific!
Yeah. Come on!
- Hey, aren't you glad to see us all?
- Whoa!
- Well, I should say.
- Excuse me, Mrs. Bear.
Remember me? I rented this place
to have a nice, quiet Christmas.
Peace on earth! Give me present.
- Arf arf arf.
- Argh!
Be careful, Sprocket. These could
be from some foreign planet.
Actually, they're
from television.
I recognized Fozzie's
weirdo friends.
Yeah. We're proud of it too.
Heh-heh-heh!
Why am I here?
Tell me, Sprocket are these anything
like these Fraggles...
You keep telling me about?
Come on, come on! Mom, I
want you to meet someone.
This is my boss, my friend,
- my inspiration,
- aw!
The one who gave me my big break
in the show business, Kermit.
Oh, yeah, the lizard.
Uh, well, frog actually.
Listen, Mrs. Bear, I know there are an
awful lot of us here, so I just...
Don't you worry about it.
- There's plenty of room for everybody.
- Excuse me.
You promised me a nice,
quiet Christmas.
You think you're disappointed.
I just took three months of
surfing lessons for zip!
Telephone!
- Telephone!
- Uh, that's just animal.
- Hello, hello, hello! Give me present!
- Joyeux Noel, Kermie.
Oh, pig.
Uh...
Hello? Uh, piggy?
Kermie, my dear Cher, it's you!
Yes, piggy, it's me. Hey,
listen, where are you?
You were supposed to come
to the farmhouse with us.
I know, Kermie,
but I forgot about a teensy-weensy
photo session I just scheduled.
Now give me more over the
shoulder, honey. Hold it.
- W-well, hurry up.
- Do not worry so, my little green hunk.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Couldn't be nicer.
Thank you. My chauffeur Jerome
is ready to whisk me away...
Into your arms at the farmhouse. Ha-ha!
Oh, beautiful! Beautiful!
I must go now. I'm rather busy.
See you soon!
- Hmmph! Okay, bye.
- Kissy-kissy! Bye-bye!
- Oh! Oh, now do that pouty thing!
- Oh, yes.
Do that pouty thing! Oooh!
Oh, fabulous!
You'll find more
bedrooms up the stairs.
Those are our bedrooms!
We rented this place.
Not more!
Fozzie, get that door!
Okay, mom! Up the stairs.
Up the stairs.
- Swedish chef!
- Fleula yule!
Whoa!
Watch out for that icy patch there.
Ja.
Genghis fur her der
gobbla-gobbla-gobbla torkey.
You mean, you're here to cook the
Christmas Turkey for us.
Ja, ja!
Let's go to the kitchen.
♪ Gunghis bird der gunghaberg ♪
♪ La la la la la-la ♪
♪ La la la la la-la la ♪
Now, where did my little
chickiepoo Camilla get to?
I'll get it! Ha-ha! Yes?
Hi there!
Oh! Y-you're a Turkey!
Of course.
Come on outside. We got to talk.
Chicken in da cooking.
Sure, there are rats and chickens here.
We always have
rats and chickens.
You're in the wrong place
at the wrong time now.
Take a walk, fly south for the winter.
Anything!
I was invited for Christmas by
some guy who spoke Swedish.
Oh, brother.
Had a white chef's hat on.
Sounds like a nice vacation.
Mm-hmm. Listen, that guy is a chef.
Don't you realize...
It could be very dangerous
for turkeys around here?
Not to worry. I'm a survivor.
Now, where's my room?
If you're not careful,
it'll be in the oven.
So long, Bucko. Heh-heh!
See you at dinner!
What seems to be the
trouble, Fozzie?
Well, you see, Kermit, the chef is
a little bit angry...
Because of all the rats and
chickens in his kitchen.
How about we send them to his
bedroom instead?
Oh, ja, chicken en da rat in
the bunksa-bunksa.
All right, let's go. Come
on, head 'em out! Okay.
- Up to the bedroom. Up to the bedroom.
- Yes, here we go, guys.
Whew, another crisis solved. Boy,
there sure are a lot of us here.
Well, the whole family's
starting to come together.
We always come together
at Christmas.
Yeah. Life would just pass in a blur if
it weren't for times like this.
Hmm?
Jingle bells jingle bells
jingle all the way.
Oh, what fun it is to ride
in a one-horse open sleigh.
Jingle bell, jingle
bell jingle bell rock.
Jingle bell swing and
jingle bell ring.
Snowing and blowing
up bushels of fun.
Now the jingle hop has begun.
Jingle bell, jingle
bell jingle bell rock.
Yeah!
Jingle bells chime in
jingle bell time.
Ooh!
Dancin' and prancin' in
jingle bell square
Square!
In the frosty air.
What a bright time
it's the right time
to rock the night away.
Away!
Jingle bell
time is a swell time
to go riding in a
one-horse sleigh.
Giddy-up, jingle horse
pick up your feet.
Jingle around the clock.
Mix and mingle in
a jingling beat.
That's the jingle bell rock.
Go, Zoot!
Aah!
So... giddy-up, jingle
horse pick up your feet
jingle around the clock.
Mix and mingle in
a jingling beat
-  that's the jingle bell,
that's the jingle bell,
that's the jingle bell rock.
That's the jingle bell rock!
Ooh! Ha-ha! Yeah! Ha-ha-ha-ha!
You got it. Ha-ha-ha!
Timber!
That's going to be a
terrific Christmas tree.
Just bring it inside, guys.
Thanks.
- Yo, Fozzie! I finally made it.
- Hey, Rowlf, welcome.
You're late.
I've been chasing a
truck all the way,
and boy, am I exhausted.
- I get it. Truck, exhaust. That's funny.
- Yeah, that's a dog joke.
- Go inside and tell mom that.
- Gotcha.
She loves canine humor.
Okay, boys, put it over
there in the corner.
- Come on, doc, let's get this holly up here.
- Oh, Mrs. Bear!
I've been chasing a
truck, and boy... whoa!
Oh, my! I guess Fozzie didn't
tell you about the icy patch.
Yeah, I guess he didn't. Anyhow,
my name's Rowlf the dog.
- I've come for the holidays.
- More? More people?
I'll go out and see if there's
a spare pillow in the kennel.
Arf arf.
Woof, woof!
Yeah, bark bark.
Don't you just hate it when
you can't speak the language?
A-ha, just what I was looking for.
Look at this little beauty.
Woh ho! Boy is this piano out of tune.
I love out of tune pianos.
♪ Boop pe do pe do pe do pe do. ♪
♪ Just hear those sleigh bells jingling, ♪
♪ Ring-ting-tingling too, ♪
♪ Out hear it's lovely weather ♪
♪ For a bear and a snowman like you. ♪
♪ Out here the snow is falling ♪
♪ And friends are calling, "yoo hoo." ♪
♪ Come on, it's lovely weather ♪
♪ For a bear and a snowman like you. ♪
Hay, that's pretty good
harmony for a snowman.
Actually I'm a snewman.
What's a snewman?
Nothing a snew man. What's a snew with you.
♪ There's a Christmas party
at the home of Fozzie bear, ♪
♪ It'll be a perfect party
with my friends all there. ♪
♪ We'll be singing the songs we love
to sing without a single stop, ♪
♪ At the fireplace while we
watch the chestnuts pop; ♪
Pop-pop! Pop-pop! Pop-pop!
Pop-pop!
But seriously Fozzie, what do you
think of the weather we're having?
It's so cold... how cold is it?
It's so cold, that when I
opened my refrigerator
this morning, there was a polar bear
inside trying to keep warm.
But its always cold at Christmas.
Ah Christmas, time for Santa Claus
and his eight prancing reinbear.
That's reindeer.
No, that's snow, darling!
♪ Out here the snow is falling and ♪
♪ Friends are calling "yoo hoo." ♪
Yoo hoo. Yoo hoo.
♪ Come on, it's lovely weather for a ♪
♪ Christmas together with you. ♪
Man you guys are the funniest
comedy team in the business.
Really?
Stay right where you are.
Kermit!
Ha-ha! Kermit!
Ker...
Kermit, where are you?
In the kitchen, Fozzie.
I got some wonderful news!
Kermit, let me tell you
about this new act I found.
- I, uh... listen to this.
- I'm listening.
I was outside
building a snowman...
- Just a second.
- Kermit, wait, wait, wait.
Kermit, see...
Hello. Emily bear's residence. This
is Kermit the fro... oh, hi, piggy.
Joyeux Noel, Kermie.
I just wanted to tell you...
I have an itsy bit of
Christmas shopping to do...
Before I come out
to the farmhouse.
But, piggy, tonight's
Christmas Eve.
Not never you fear, dear.
I shall be there soon. Ta-ta.
Ooh, green fuzzy
flipper slippers!
Oh, divine! Have them gift-wrapped.
Ah, ha-ha!
Kermit, n-now can I tell you
about my new act?
I'm all ears.
Now, what can that be?
What does he mean he's all ears?
Frogs don't even have ears.
This is my dog Sprocket.
He is not a Christmas Turkey!
Dis make a gobbla-gobbla
faire furnousse.
I don't care if the Turkey
says the dog is a Turkey.
The dog is not the Turkey. The
Turkey's the Turkey, you Turkey!
Come on, Sprocket.
Dis make a gobbla-gobbla
goofy woofy.
Heh-heh-heh-heh! This
is starting to be fun.
Whoa! Speaking of fun,
hey, mama, how ya doin'?
Hey, Kermit, look what I have!
It's home movies!
I found this old
film in the closet.
It's the very first Christmas the
Muppet's ever spent together.
Great! I haven't seen
that film in years.
Turn off the lights and
roll the film!
Shh!
♪ You better watch out, ♪
♪ You better not cry ♪
It's Miss Hamhocks,
when she was just a little sausage roll.
♪ Santa Claus is coming to town. ♪
♪ He's making a list ♪
♪ And checking it twice. ♪
You were still in diapers in those days.
Ma!
♪ Santa Claus is coming to town. ♪
Oh look there's Rowlf
when he was a wee puppy.
Not so wee. I was paper trained.
♪ He knows when you been bad or good, ♪
♪ So be good for goodness sake. ♪
What a handsome little devil I was
♪ you better not cry. ♪
♪ You better not pout
I'm telling you why. ♪
Why?
♪ Santa Claus is coming to town. ♪
Oh, animal.
Aw, animal!
Yep, some things never change.
Oh, that was fun.
Even weirdos are cute
when they're babies.
I knew you'd learn to love us.
I didn't say that.
What's that?
I tell you, chicken little,
you're my kind of poultry. Ah.
Camilla! What's going on here?
Ooh, you got some drumsticks
there, my fine-feathered mama.
B-b-but Camilla's my girlfriend.
You got to be kiddin'.
You're not even a bird.
Nobody's perfect.
Come on, Henny
Penny, let's me and you,
go out to the farmyard for a little
friendly scratchin' and squawkin'.
All right, cut! That does it.
Let me at him.
I'm gonna rip off his waddle.
You and what other nerds?
Come on, put up your
wings, Turkey toes.
Why you... you're pullin' my
leg, hose nose.
I'll be pullin' your
wishbone, cranberry breath.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Hark, what do I hear?
- You hear me about to make some Turkey hash.
- No, no, listen!
Methinks me hears carolers.
Here we come a-caroling
among the leaves so green
here we come a-wandering
so fair to be seen
love and joy come to you
and to you glad tidings too
and god bless you and
send yo a happy new year
and god send you a
happy new year.
It's the sesame street gang.
- Merry Christmas from sesame street!
- Merry Christmas!
Deck the halls with boughs of holly,
♪ fa la la la la, la la la la. ♪
♪ Tis the season to be jolly, ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la. ♪
♪ Don we now our gay apparel, ♪
♪ Fa la la, la la la, la la la. ♪
♪ Troll the ancient yule tide carol, ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la. ♪
Okay, Ernie, you're next.
♪ See the blazing yule before us, ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la. ♪
♪ Strike the harp and join the chorus. ♪
I will not sing this song.
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la. ♪
While I count the
yuletide treasure,
♪ fa la la la la, la la la la. ♪
Your turn, hairy monster.
♪ Fast away the old year passes, ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la. ♪
♪ Hail the new, ye lads and lasses, ♪
♪ Sing we joyous, all together, ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la. ♪
Deck the halls with
boughs of holly,
'tis the season to be jolly,
-  fa-la-la la-la.
Fa-la-la la-la la-la
la la.
Oh, that was fun. I love carols.
It's nice to have everyone here. You can
feel the peace of the holiday season.
Wow!
Whoa! Whoa! Watch out.
Well, doc, you know
what this means.
Sprocket and I will have to give up
our hammock in the attic, right?
Either that or build bunk-beds
in the broom closet.
Sprocket, go get me
a hammer, will you?
- Hi there. Hey, we're Ernie and Bert.
- Yeah.
Well, hi there yourself.
I'm doc.
Did you know that "doc" starts
with the letter "D"?
Why, yes.
- Yes. "Yes" starts with the letter "Y."
- Yeah.
- True.
- And "true" starts with the letter "T."
What is this?
Where we come
from, this is small talk.
Whatever you say. It's
nice to meet you,
but I've got to go and
build some bunk-beds.
Bunk-beds! "B" words.
Hey, hey, hey, no, you got me wrong.
I-i-I'm a dairy cow. Moo!
No, no, no, Du bis borgey.
All right, okay, I'm a IIII-I'm a...
I'm a birdie, I'm a birdie. I'm a
seagull, all right?
No, no, no. Gobbla-gobbla.
Okay, all right, I
admit it, I admit it!
The jig is up!
Here I am, the Christmas Turkey.
Ee-toscus nu!
Ow! Hey! Watch it
there, will ya?
Oh, yeah, yeah, I
recognize it now.
This is... thi... this is the
traditional fitting, right,
to see if the roasting pan is big
enough for the nice fat bird.
Ja, ja, ja, gobbla-gobbla
torkey fitsky witsky.
Of course, uh, before
we go any further,
uh, there is one thing I
think you should see.
Numisbiscus
gobbla-gobbla snooze?
If you think I'm a nice
fat bird, look at this!
Oy, York!
Nushna gobbla-gobbla humonga!
Ain't it the truth.
Heh-heh-heh-heh! Mmm!
Hey, everyone, quiet down.
There's a bulletin on TV.
≡⌁ and now for this news flash. ⌁≡
≡⌁ the worst blizzard in 50 years is
approaching us at a great rate. ⌁≡
≡⌁ the weather service reports that
barometers are falling sharply. ⌁≡
≡⌁ oh, no! Aah! ⌁≡
he's right! Look at the snow.
One snowflake, two snowflake,
three snowflake...
But miss piggy's out there in that storm.
Five, six...
All right, the huge canary sleeps
in the attic with the cookie eater.
Check.
The blue monster said
he'd sleep in the bathtub.
- Check.
- And, uh,
Ernie and Bert will bunk
out with the lizard here.
Uh, frog. Kermit the frog.
What about Oscar?
I'll be nicely miserable
in my trash can here.
Hey, maybe I could bunk
out here with you.
I never had a rat in my trash can before.
That might be nice.
Hey, everybody, look what I've got...
Christmas cookies!
Cookie!
Oh, thank you.
Who was that strange
blue creature?
That my kind of fella.
Hey, everybody, it's time to rehearse
for our sesame street pageant.
It's called 'twas the
night before Christmas.
- Come on out, Bert.
- I won't.
- Come on, Bert.
- Ernie, please don't make me.
Oh Bert, listen,
everybody's waiting.
Ernie, why must you
always humiliate me?
Come on, somebody has to play mama.
And you lost the toss.
- All right, well, just get it over with!
- Okay.
'Twas the night before
Christmas by clement Moore.
Hit it, Rowlf.
"'Twas the night
before Christmas..."
"And all through the house not a creature
was stirring, not even a mouse."
Cue the mouse.
I'm here! I'm here!
Cute little Grover mouse is here.
What's the bowl for?
Oh, uh, so you can see
that I am not stirring.
Note how the hand never
touches the spoon.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, public. Thank you.
This is great.
Oh, aren't they adorable?
Hey, don't encourage them.
"Mama in her kerchief...
" That's you, Bert.
I know, I know.
"And I in my cap had just settled
our brains for a long winter's nap.
"When out on the lawn there
arose such a clatter,
I sprang from my bed to
see what was the matter."
Open the curtain!
Monsters as reindeer?
This is crazy!
Wh-where's Santa Claus?
Don't worry, Bert,
we're getting to him.
"With a little old driver
so lively and quick,
I knew in a moment it
must be Saint Nick."
Hello!
Is nothing sacred?
Now wait a minute.
Who let the two-headed
monster be Santa Claus?
But he said he'd never
been in a play before.
I mean, they said it.
Both of them said it.
Just go to the big finish.
Will you, please.
"But I heard him exclaim
ere he drove out of sight,
mewwy chwi-mah to aww and
to aww a good nigh!"
Merry Christmas to all,
and to all a good night!
Close the curtain!
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Sorry to break up your fun in here,
but have you folks seen the weather?
- There's a real storm out there.
- Oh, lordy,
I haven't seen a sky like that
since the blizzard of '41.
I tell you, Mr. Lizard,
it's a good thing
all your friends are safe and
warm inside the farmhouse.
Yeah, but... all my friends
are not safe and warm.
Sorry to hear that it's...
Cold enough out there
to freeze your Winnebago.
- Hello?
- Hello, Kermie.
I've finished my shopping.
Unfortunately, Jerome got the
limo stuck in the snowbank.
So, I'll just have to catch
a taxi to the farmhouse.
Listen, piggy, there's a
terrible storm outside...
And I really think it's
too dangerous to travel.
So why don't you wait for the
storm to end before you join us?
Nonsense. And miss my
Christmas Eve with vous?
It's just a little bit of snow.
See you soon! Bye-bye.
Yo, taxi!
Aah!
My... oh!
Oh! Oh!
Aaah!
I'm sure miss piggy
will be all right.
Kermit?
Kermit, y-y-you look worried.
I know exactly what you need.
- Comedy.
- What?
Yeah, come on.
Now's the time for you
to meet my new partner!
Who's your new partner?
- A snowman.
- The heck you say.
Yeah, yeah. Come on outside and
we'll do our act for you.
Outside? It's too cold to go outside.
- It's not cold.
- It is cold!
It's not cold.
Can I come in and warm up?
Okay, so it's cold.
I'm Kermit the frog. You must
be Fozzie's new partner.
I'll say. We're terrific.
Yeah, yeah. Come on!
You are coming in a snowman,
but you are going out a star.
Hey, everybody, would you
like to see our new act?
We'd love to see your act.
In fact, we'd hate
to miss your act.
In fact, we'd love
to hate your act.
Statler, Waldorf, where'd
you guys come from?
They're friends of mine, Fozzie.
They come visit me every Christmas.
M-my own mother is
friends with you guys?
These two comics are
made for each other.
The snowman is ice cold,
and the bear's not so hot.
Oh, please.
After all, there's no
business like snow business.
Come on, ignore them.
Snowman, do the straight line.
- Okay. Hey, Fozzie!
- Yes, Mr. Snowman?
Did you hear about the church
that burned down?
Holy smoke!
That was our best joke.
That does it, Fozzie.
Forget the act.
I'm startin' to melt.
It's too hot in here.
Well, you know what they say.
If you can't stand the heat,
get out of the farmhouse.
Oh, come on. You'll be
okay on the back porch.
Boy, that storm is
really getting worse.
Yeah, I hope miss piggy is okay.
There is one worried frog.
Aha! That's one. One worried frog.
He's not the only one.
That's two. Two worried frogs.
Search me. More small
talk, I think.
Hey, I'd better go out
and get some firewood.
Corka doon.
Hi there.
Did you wish to talk to me about
something, Mr. Cook, sir?
Oh, ja, ja, ja.
- Ungus sher doo.
- Gee, nice kitchen.
Hey, are you gonna have cranberry
sauce and mashed potatoes?
Ja, ensperging Bern.
- Oh, boy.
- Yengis Bern da goobla-goobla.
I just want to hear
about the whole meal.
Oh, yerngus sperg...
But first, I want to give
this little present to you.
Ebit her?
It's chocolate-covered birdseed.
I made it myself.
Engus sperg da merga mor?
I wanted to give it
to you because, well,
I know that you're from Sweden and
it must be hard for you because
you're away from your family
and loved ones during the holidays.
Ja.
At Christmas, there are
places and people and things
that become very, very special.
Chestnuts roasting
on an open fire.
Jack frost nipping
at your nose.
Yule don smert egon
sverda gon mer.
Es sblergon yeber Eskimos.
Everybody knows a Turkey
and some mistletoe,
yegon glerkon smernay ew.
Although it's been said
many times, many ways,
merry Christmas
fleula yule.
Merry Christmas
fleula yule
-  to you.
-  a vu.
Now there, Mr. Cook, tell me...
Exactly what are you going
to fix for Christmas dinner?
Ohhh, uh, ooh, oh, um...
Skraper vie don cranen boochers.
- Shredded wheat and cranberry sauce?
- Ja.
My absolute favorite.
Ja.
Ooh, going to be lots of snow
for me to shovel tomorrow.
Uh, it's getting worse
and worse out there.
Aren't you glad you're in
here all warm and toasty?
I just wish miss piggy were.
Okay, when I yell
"three," gun it!
One, two, three!
You're really worried about your
friend, aren't you, Kermit?
Hmm? Oh, well, uh,
yeah, yeah, a little.
I'll tell you what. I'll
go out looking for her.
Really? But you've never
even met miss piggy.
We never met any of you
until a little while ago.
And now we're friends.
See, Sprockey and I were gonna spend
Christmas alone, but this is better!
Now, what's your
friend look like?
Well, uh, to begin
with, she's a pig.
Well, up to a short while ago, I
would have thought that strange.
I'll give it a try.
Gee, thanks, doc.
You'll be sorry. It's cold
enough to freeze your Winnebago.
What a sweet guy.
Uncle Kermit?
Robin? Where are you?
In the cellar.
What are you doing down there?
I made a discovery.
Oh, yeah? What are
you talking about?
Remember telling me about Fraggle holes?
Uh, yeah. So?
And how if I ever found
one, we could go into.
Fraggle rock and maybe
meet some Fraggles?
Uh, so?
Is that one?
Ooh, look at that. Well, it
certainly looks like one.
You never know where you're
going to find these things.
Can we go in, uncle Kermit?
Well, maybe just a little ways,
see if we can meet anyone.
Watch your step, Robin.
Gee, it's kind of scary.
These are beautiful caves. Oooh!
- Hey, uncle Kermit, wait up.
- Hmm? Okay.
Do you think this is
really Fraggle rock?
Well I don't know but
if I were a Fraggle,
I think this is the kind
of place I'd hang out.
Wait a second.
I thought I heard something.
Guess not.
Well, anyhow.
Oh, uh, uh, well, uh, hi, there.
- Hi, yourself.
- Hi.
- You're Fraggles.
- I'll say.
- But you're not.
No, I'm Kermit. This is Robin.
We're frogs.
Oh. What's a frog?
- They're frogs.
- I'll say.
Don't touch 'em. Frogs are
probably noted germ carriers.
Well, actually, we just came down here
to wish you all a merry Christmas.
- Oh, thank you.
- That's nice.
- What's Christmas?
- Yeah.
- Oh, don't you have Christmas?
- No.
That's when you gather together
with the people you love...
And you wish each
other peace on earth.
Oh! Oh, we have a
time like that.
Yes, we do. As a matter of fact,
we're celebrating it right now.
We give each other presents. I'm
giving goober this nice yellow pebble.
And I gave Mokie that
pebble last year.
And I gave it to red
the year before that.
And I gave it to you, Wembley,
That pebble's been
a gift 37 times.
- Thirty-seven times?
- Yeah.
-  la-la-la la la
-  la la la
-  la-la-la-la la la
la-la-la la la   la la la
la-la, pass it on..
When it's nice and bright
and it brings delight.
Let your heart choose right got to...
Pass it on..
When it feels real good
like a feeling should.
When it's understood got to...
Pass it on..
When you're giving love away
love will come again to stay.
What you give is what you
gain when you... Pass it on..
When I give a gift to you I
know you're gonna give it too.
That's why giving's what we do as we...
Pass it on..
Pass it on.
Pass it on.  pass it on.
Wish upon  wish upon
all the good things that you do.
Pass it on.
Pass it on.   pass it on.
When it's gone,  when it's gone
it will bring good luck to you.
When you're giving love away
love will come again to stay.
What you give is what you
gain when you... Pass it on.
When I give a gift to you I
know you're gonna give it too.
That's why giving's what we do as we...
Pass it on.
And that's the way
Fraggle presents work.
I love it!
Oh, goober, I almost forgot.
Huh?
I want you to have this pebble.
So, here.
Wow! Oh!
Oh. Ah. Thank you, Mokie.
Hey, listen, Fraggles, this has all
been great, but we got to be going.
Oh! Oh, what a shame.
- I'll say.
- No, wait, wait, wait.
Robin, before you go,
I'd like you to
have this pebble.
Wow!
Gee. Well, merry
Christmas, Fraggles.
Merry Christmas, frogs.
Bye! Bye!
- Bye!
Gosh, that was fun.
Yeah, well, it's nice to be
with friends at Christmas.
Kermit, we hear shouting outside.
It could be miss piggy.
Oh, well, let's go.
Anyone see her out there?
Well, at least the storm
has eased up a bit.
Chef, why don't you
make some hot soup?
And, Mrs. Bear, would you put
some extra blankets on a bed?
- Wait a minute. There she is!
- What?
Yeah, and she don't look bad...
For a pig.
Oh! Merry Christmas, Kermie.
Am I late?
I-I-i don't know how to
explain this, Kermit,
but I was searching through
the snow and suddenly...
There was miss piggy with
this costume for me.
You don't have to explain, doc.
If there's one thing piggy knows,
it's how to make an entrance.
♪ Oh, there's no place like ♪
♪ Home for the holidays, ♪
♪ 'Cause no matter how far away you roam, ♪
♪ 'Cause no matter how far away you roam. ♪
♪ Far away you roam. ♪
♪ When you pine for the sunshine ♪
♪ Of a friendly face. ♪
♪ For the holidays, you can't beat ♪
♪ Home, sweet home. ♪
♪ If you want ♪
♪ To be happy in a million ways. ♪
♪ For the holidays, you can't beat ♪
♪ Home, sweet ♪
♪ Home. ♪
Ahhh!
Careful of the icy patch.
Ok mom. Hay everybody come in.
Hey, everybody.
Everybody, quiet.
My mother has an announcement.
Thank you, Fozzie. I'd like
to welcome you all here.
You are all here, aren't you?
I think so, yes.
Oh, good, because I'm afraid
we're running out of room.
Two of you will have to sleep hung
on hangers on a hook on the wall.
- What a fabulous idea!
- Love hanger. Love hanger. Ahh!
It's the only way animal
ever sleeps, ma'am.
See, mom, I told
you it'd be easy.
They're weirdos, Fozzie.
- Yeah?
- But...
They're nice weirdos.
Yeah.
Well, everybody, it's Christmas
Eve and the tree is trimmed.
So it's time for our annual carol sing.
Take it, Rowlf.
-  happy holiday,
-  happy holiday.
May the calendar
keep bringing
happy holidays to you.
-  happy holiday,
-  happy holiday.
May the merry bells
keep ringing
may your every
wish come true.
Ding, dong merrily on high
in heaven the
bells are ringing.
Ding, dong verily the sky
is riven with angels singing.
Glo-ooo-ooo-ooo-ooo-ooo-Ria
hosanna in excelsis.
- What's that?
- It's pretty.
- Let's go see, eh?
- Yeah!
I saw three ships
come sailing in
on Christmas day,
on Christmas day.
I saw three ships
come sailing in
on Christmas day
in the morning.
And what was in those
ships all three
on Christmas day.
On Christmas day.
And what was in those
ships all three
on Christmas day
in the morning.
Good king Wenceslas looked out,
on the feast of Stephen,
when the snow lay round about,
deep and crisp and even;
brightly shone the moon that night,
tho' the frost was cruel,
when a poor man came in sight,
gathering winter fuel.
The holly and the ivy,
when they are both full grown,
of all the trees that are in the wood,
the holly bears the crown.
Oh, the rising of the sun
and the running of the deer,
the playing of the merry organ,
sweet singing in the choir.
I'll be home
for Christmas.
You can count on me.
You'll have snow
and mistletoe
and presents on the tree.
Happy holiday,
happy holiday,
happy holiday.
Happy holiday.
May your calendar
keep bringing
happy holidays to you.
♪ Here we are as in olden days ♪
♪ Happy golden days of yore. ♪
♪ Faithful friends who are dear to us ♪
♪ Gather near to us once more. ♪
Piggy?
♪ Have yourself a merry little Christmas. ♪
♪ Let your heart be light. ♪
♪ From now on our troubles ♪
♪ Will be out of sight. ♪
♪ Through the years
we all will be together ♪
♪ If the fates allow. ♪
♪ Hang a shining star
up on the highest bough. ♪
♪ And have yourself a merry
little Christmas ♪
♪ Now. ♪
Caroling, caroling now we go
Christmas bells are ringing.
Caroling, caroling through the
snow Christmas bells are ringing.
Joyous voices
sweet and clear,
sing the sad of
heart to cheer.
Ding, dong, ding, dong
Christmas bells are ringing.
Caroling, caroling
near and far,
following, following
yonder star.
Mark ye well the
song we sing.
Gladsome tidings
now we bring.
Mi, mi, mi, mi.
Christmas bells are ringing.
♪ I heard the bells on Christmas day ♪
♪ Their old familiar carols play, ♪
♪ And wild and sweet the words repeat ♪
♪ Of peace on earth, good will to men! ♪
It's in every
one of us
to be wise.
Find your heart
open up both your eyes.
We can all know
everything
without ever knowing why.
It's in every
one of us
by and by.
It's in every
one of us
by and by.
Old friends, new friends
home with the family.
We'll be together
at Christmas.
Snowflakes, sleigh bells
bringing back memories.
We'll be together
at Christmas.
Some things change
with passing years.
Let this feeling stay.
Old friends, new friends
hoping we'll always be
here with each other
together on Christmas
day.
You know, miss piggy, I think it's
time I gave you your present.
Oh, really? Oh, tell me,
what is it, what is it?
Well, your present is... a mink.
Ahh! A mink!
- A mink.
- I've always wanted it.
Where is it? Where is it? Where is it?
Uh, Maurine. Hi, I'm
Maurine, the mink.
What?
She said, "hi, I'm
Maurine, the mink."
I heard her! I heard her! Mmm.
Well, this is, this is the mink?
My mink? Of course.
Oh, miss piggy, I've seen
everything you've done.
I'm your biggest fan. I worship
the ground you walk on.
- What a wonderful present!
- Yeah.
- Speaking of presents, Grover,
- huh?
I'd like you to have
this Fraggle pebble.
T-this Fraggle pebble
here is for me?
Oh, I just love Christmas.
- Ho, ho, ho! Merry Christmas!
- Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas, everyone.
We wish you a
merry Christmas;
we wish you a
merry Christmas
and a happy new year.
Well, they certainly seem to be having
a good time, out there, Sprocket.
Yeah, I like it when
they have a good time.
But I'll tell you what.
Somebody's got to do something
about these dishes, Sprocket.
Come on.
I'll wash and you dry. Okay?
So bring it right here.
Good tidings to you
wherever you are.
We wish you a merry Christmas
-  and a happy new year
- Kermie, look up, dear.
-  we wish you a merry Christmas;
- uh-oh.
- mistletoe.
We wish you a merry Christmas
merry Christmas, Kermie.
And a happy new year.
Ah, merry Christmas, piggy.
Merry Christmas, everyone.
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas. Merry
Christmas, all.
The end...