In a cold world,
all the watches started to freeze.
The sun came and went between blizzards
and gusts which erased all bearings.
In this world lived a fire
and in this fire,
two lovers found a home.
All right.
The volcano is ready, waiting for us.
Yes.
Okay.
Katia?
This is Katia,
and this is Maurice.
It's 1991, June 2nd.
Tomorrow will be their last day.
They will leave behind samples.
Words.
Hundreds of hours of footage.
Thousands of photos.
And a million questions.
The Muana Loa.
They meet 19 years ago.
In 1966.
There is no definitive account
of this first encounter
and the visual record
of their budding romance is sparse.
There is this photo...
and these rose-tinted moments
a few years later.
Parts of Katia and Maurice's story
remain lost to time.
As in love, there are mysteries.
You fall hard for what you know.
Harder for what you don't.
In one story, Katia
and Maurice meet by chance on a bench
at the University of Strasbourg.
In a second,
they meet at a new film
by renowned volcanologist Haroun Tazieff.
The most detailed account
is a blind date at a café.
They bond over their first loves,
Mount Etna and Mount Stromboli.
Katia, a rebel who was sent
to a school for unruly girls,
convinces her parents to take her
to Italy's volcanoes.
Maurice would return to Stromboli
at age 19,
feeling at once ecstasy and loneliness.
Katia understands
this loneliness.
It is also hers.
Growing up in the rubble
of postwar Alsace,
the world felt to them unsafe, uncertain.
They take refuge in the mysteries
of the natural world.
Dreaming,
just 20 kilometers apart.
The Vosges and Rhine fault lines
shifting imperceptibly beneath them.
At the end of this version,
the café closes and it begins to rain.
They will never
leave each other.
November 19th, 1967,
a U.S. fighter plane
drops two snake-eye bombs
along the South Vietnam border...
the territory once colonized
as French Indochina.
One week later,
Katia and Maurice join anti-war protests
in Paris.
The next day, they show up
on the front page of L'Humanité.
But human pursuits
of power begin to feel vain and absurd
next to the power of the Earth.
It's also
the plate tectonic revolution,
and the field of volcanology
is finding its form.
They devour
each hypothesis, each myth.
Everything that has been gleaned so far
from the archives of the Earth.
The truths...
the fragments...
the questions.
They wonder what forms
and re-forms the world.
To these mysteries they long
to get closer.
With just enough grant money
and a donated car,
Katia and Maurice
go seek Iceland's volcanoes
with their friend, Roland.
Katia is the geochemist,
Maurice the geologist.
Alone, they could only dream of volcanoes.
Together, they can reach them.
Except the car breaks down
27 times.
Then crashes.
And Maurice gets
into hot water.
Here is an actor
reading Katia's account.
Undeterred,
they spend the next few summers
studying their mutual friends,
Etna and Stromboli.
They also bring along more human friends.
L'Équipe Vulcain, they call themselves.
Katia and Maurice are after
the strange alchemy of elements,
the combination of mineral, heat,
gas and time that incites an eruption.
What is it, they ask,
that makes the Earth's heart beat?
Its blood flow?
They study, examine and question.
Katia and Maurice begin
to learn the secrets of the planet
that few others know.
Understanding
is love's other name.
1970,
Katia and Maurice marry
in a small ceremony in Alsace.
They honeymoon
on the volcanic island of Santorini,
believed to be the secret location
of Atlantis.
Katia and Maurice decide
they will not have children.
“From here on out,
life will only be volcanoes,
"volcanoes, volcanoes,” Maurice says.
The young field of volcanology
has found two young stars.
The camera loves them.
And they love their own cameras back.
Photography
is a means of remembering, revisiting,
stretching their time with volcanoes.
This photo shows
the parabolic trajectories
of volcanic bombs ejected from Stromboli.
This one shows how lava
is stretched into glass wool
called Pele's hair.
And this shot helps visualize
plate tectonic theory.
Volcanology
is a science of observation.
The closer they get, the more they see.
The very instant
a volcano wakes up,
these weirdoes are notified
by a growing network of local friends
and guides who help them
reach the craters as fast
as humanly possible.
Maurice and Katia
make their expedition to Nyiragongo,
a volcano that sits
between two diverging plates.
They are guided by fellow
volcanologist Jacques Durieux.
You arrive
at the mouth of the volcano,
then you have to go
in the mouth of the volcano.
So you are going down.
Not so high, 300 meters.
But very bad rock.
All kinds of fumaroles went through,
and so it's not strong.
Here,
Maurice and Katia make their home
for the next two weeks.
Katia would later write...
Suddenly, the lava plunges down
ten meters in seconds.
Katia and Maurice
will eventually emerge
from this crater unscathed and emboldened.
In the immense universe
that is the classification of volcanoes,
the Kraffts will eventually
adopt two general classes.
Red...
and gray.
Red volcanoes,
like Nyiragongo,
form as tectonic plates pull apart,
and at hotspots on the ocean floor.
Magma rises and fills in the gaps
opened up by the movement of the Earth,
creating new land.
Red volcanoes are basaltic.
Effusive.
And up to 1200 degrees Celsius hot.
Katia and Maurice
have their differences.
Katia is like a bird.
Maurice, an elephant seal.
Katia is drawn to details,
the interconnectedness of things.
Maurice, the singular, the grandiose.
They both observe the world,
but in their own distinct ways.
Katia, with her still camera,
captures one moment with one frame.
Maurice chases motion...
recording a stream of seconds,
24 frames each.
He thirsts to get every possible shot,
because the spectacle could vanish.
But this causes him to wander...
and wander...
and wander.
Katia's greatest fear is
that she will lose sight of him...
and never see him again.
A surprise telegram
summons Katia...
and Maurice to Nyiragongo,
their beloved volcano
that they met four years ago.
Katia and Maurice knew
this kind of destruction was possible.
But this is the first time
they experience it firsthand.
The lava flows were going very...
very fast.
They were probably running
at 60 to 70 kilometers per hour.
And this was in the morning
where a lot of people were on the road
going for the market.
We think that around 100 people
were overwhelmed by the lava flow.
Very unusual eruption.
No amount of scientific research
could have prepared them for this shock.
The language of myth instead feels apt.
They're in the cauldron of the devil,
the portal to hell.
Or caught amid the warring spirits
of the volcano,
according to the stories
from their friends in Goma.
For Katia and Maurice,
the unknown is not something to be feared.
It is something to go toward.
At only 52 years old
an infant Indonesian volcano begins
to throw a fit.
Katia and Maurice go chase it.
In 1883, its parent,
a volcano named Krakatau, exploded.
It conjured a tsunami so forceful
that it swept
neighboring coastlines,
killing 36,417 people.
It also ripped up this coral
from the seafloor
and parked a colonial Dutch steamship
two miles inland.
Ash traveled the globe,
intensifying sunsets that transfixed
the gaze of scientists and artists,
especially one Norwegian painter
who described the sunsets as a scream.
Then the volcano
collapsed into the sea...
only to spring up again as a newcomer
called Anak Krakatau.
Katia and Maurice
must be totally in sync.
Any mistake that one makes can be costly
for the both of them.
But Maurice cannot do this work
without Katia.
Neither can Katia, without Maurice.
And together, they're there
for the volcano,
who is indifferent in the face
of their adulation.
Katia and Maurice know
that these rocks will long outlive them.
They are not religious.
"We are scientists," they say.
"We have but this one short life,
then we return to the ground."
With her one short life,
Katia dreams of growing old
with the volcano, of turning over
its every stone.
Maurice burns
to get closer to the fire, no matter what.
He once wrote,
Maurice hatches this plan
from another boating adventure
during their first trip
to Indonesia in 1971.
Here,
they study the largest reserve
of sulfuric acid in the world.
MAURICE: F
Suddenly,
the acid eats through the steel cable
and claims the sample bottle
at the bottom of the lake.
This mission is over.
A headwind sweeps them further from shore.
They will spend the next three hours
struggling to get back.
Katia is furious.
Over time, Maurice perfects
the legend of Maurice Krafft.
And together,
he and Katia
have gotten good at playing themselves.
Despite what Maurice says,
their footage suggests otherwise.
For instance, how do they show
that their work is grueling?
Perhaps like this?
Or this?
How do they show how to gaze
into the abyss?
Perhaps like this.
How do they stage geologic scale?
With images like this?
But what about this?
Why was this moment captured
with their rationed feet of film?
What or who was it for?
Now and again, Katia and Maurice
must go back to Alsace
to turn their photos and footage
into books and films.
Here, they are denizens
of this human world.
In order
to get back home to the volcano,
they must pay the bills.
Katia catalogues their images,
writes the books
and handles the logistics.
Maurice takes the lecture tour,
media appearances,
tries in vain to plan his lava canoe trip.
He also edits their films.
Ball is in.
Danger.
Over in the United States,
volcanologist Harry Glicken
takes this photo of Mount St. Helens
on May 17, 1980.
What follows are some
of the best-known images
of what will happen here tomorrow,
starting at eight hours, 32 minutes,
11.4 seconds Pacific Daylight Time.
Fifty-three kilometers
to the east on Mount Adams,
a hiker takes these photos.
Fifty-six kilometers
to the northwest,
this image is taken.
Somewhere further, an eight-millimeter
film camera records this.
As for Maurice and Katia,
they did not film or photograph
this eruption...
because they could not see or hear it.
As ash descends
on the surrounding area...
Katia and Maurice make their approach.
Katia and Maurice will spend
three months amid the ash...
monitoring, photographing,
studying this force.
And little by little, they
and their fellow researchers
will paint a clearer picture of the event,
with numbers like
two point eight,
the number of cubic kilometers
of land cast off by the mountain.
Twenty-five thousand,
the eruption's force measured
in atomic bombs like the one
that the United States dropped
on Hiroshima.
Fifty-seven,
the official human death toll.
At one point, they will find
the melted tapes of David Johnston.
No matter what
they discover after the blast...
they come no closer to understanding how
to make the most critical measurements
before it.
From this moment on,
they will devote their lives
to this kind of volcano.
The gray volcano.
The killer volcano.
Gray volcanoes may be killers,
but their ash makes the most fertile soil
in the world,
as demonstrated by this killer turnip.
Unlike red volcanoes,
which form when plates pull apart,
grays form when plates collide,
causing pressure and heat
to build and build
until a cataclysmic release.
A Who's-Who of such eruptions
would include Vesuvius in the year 79,
Tambora in 1815,
and Pelée in 1902.
Here is a relatively small one,
Galunggung, in 1982.
And here's Una-Una in 1983.
There may be signs
before an eruption,
but there is no certainty.
No way of knowing the exact timing.
And timing is everything
in the human world.
In 1884,
time was set to machines
instead of the wild rhythms of the Earth.
No longer told by the Sun, Moon or stars,
it relied on manufactured intervals
to coordinate railway cars
transporting minerals ripped
from the Earth.
Embraced by the British Empire,
this new railway time soon
mapped the globe.
But a volcano can't be scheduled.
The length of the fuse
is never known.
This is a map
drawn of Nevado del Ruiz,
a gray volcano in Colombia's Andean range.
It illustrates the threat if it erupts.
And there's every indication that it will,
as Colombia's geoscientists communicated
to officials in reports.
This one, presented on October 7, 1985,
states that there is
a 100 percent probability of mudflows,
with great danger for Armero
and the surrounding towns.
Katia and Maurice
are part of a chorus
who call for warning systems
and evacuation plans.
They know what will happen.
But the decision-makers
deem these plans too costly.
On November 14, 1985,
these images circulate around the world.
The volcano erupted the previous day,
and the mudflows swallowed the villages
late at night,
while residents slept.
Katia arrives while
Maurice is on a lecture tour in France,
promoting their latest film.
The official death toll climbs
to 22,000...
and then 23,000.
Some reports say 25,000.
The exact number is not known.
Survivors would later recount.
Katia longs for Maurice,
who is likely lecturing
at this moment on the creative powers
of volcanoes.
For the first time, she questions
her life's purpose.
Katia and Maurice
had spent their lives
documenting how the Earth's heart beats,
how its blood flows.
Now they feel their own human hearts
beating and breaking.
Long ago, Maurice said...
Volcanoes must destroy to create...
but must this unruly cycle
take human life?
Katia and Maurice set out
to hunt for the rarest,
deadliest forces
for a new film on volcanic hazards.
It took them one full year
to get these shots
on Alaska's Mount Augustine.
The camera shakes as if it's telegraphing,
whether to stay or run.
Perhaps it is because their colleague,
Juergen Kienle,
is about to pull them away
from the burning ash cloud
at the last second.
Several years from now,
their obituary will cite this
as the moment where Katia
and Maurice insisted that the risks
should always be minimized...
but that this type of close-up study
had to be done.
Maurice once said,
“Look at how small we humans
are against this volcanic force.
"The only thing that will remain
of our passage is that we can write,
"tell stories, and film.”
When you could die
at any moment...
what do you leave behind?
A set of forces
collide inside the planet
throughout the enormity of geologic time
to trigger one instant, an eruption,
that forever re-shapes the Earth.
And across humanity's two million years,
two tiny humans are born
in the same place,
at the same time,
and they love the same thing.
And that love moved us closer
to the Earth.
June 3rd, 1991,
Mount Unzen begins to wake up
after its 200-year slumber.
The mountain has been stirring since May,
but today, something will shift
inside the Earth.
We hope always, but we cannot be sure,
and we don't know nothing.
You have big blocks on the top
and they have to...
to come down, but when?
Just after 4:00 p.m.,
it starts to rain.
Ash blows in on a north wind.
Something seems different this time.
The mist obscures their view,
so Katia and Maurice push closer
with their friend, Harry Glicken,
to get a better shot.
A journalist who abandoned
their camera captured this shot.
And there's this moment,
just before the blast.
The last known shot of Katia
and Maurice together.
Japanese officials gave Katia
and Maurice's friend, Yves, this photo.
Their urns resting
in the Shimabara Temple
at the base of Mount Unzen.
Near the site of the surge,
the marks on the earth indicated
that Katia and Maurice were next
to each other.
Two items were recovered.
A camera and a watch,
its hands forever frozen in time
at 4:18 p.m.
Just over the East China Sea,
Mount Pinatubo trembles.
In one week, it will explode
in the most spectacular
volcanic eruption the Philippines
has ever known.
Fifty-eight thousand people will evacuate.
Officials took the warning signs
seriously, thanks to Katia
and Maurice's film
about understanding volcanoes.
Across the world,
near the French-German border,
the Vosges and Rhine fault lines shift
imperceptibly beneath a sleeping Earth.