Good for you, Pete.
Good for you.
(SNEEZES)
BILLY BUSH ON T.V.:
Access Hollywood spotlight
on sexy crime
fighter Sarah Marshall.
Hi, everybody, welcome to Access
Hollywood. I'm Billy Bush.
Each week, millions of
viewers love to watch
Ms. Marshall's brainy sexpot
character, Maddy Stark,
alongside Billy Baldwin's
dark and brooding,
hard-to-love lead detective,
Hunter Rush.
And this isn't
your jurisdiction.
I just made it
my jurisdiction.
Can you say "catfight"?
BILLY:
Off-screen, Sarah cozies up
to her successful composer
boyfriend, Peter Bretter.
He's no household name,
yet Bretter's dark
and ominous score
has set the tone for this
gruesome juggernaut.
Take a look.
What do you think?
(RUSH SCOFFS)
I think it's gonna be hard
for her to re-enter the pageant
without a face.
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
BILLY: Looks like the sky's the limit
for this adorable couple.
Anything could happen.
(SINGING) We got to do something
We got to do something
Before Mother Earth
gets any more hurt
We got to do something
BILLY: We leave you
tonight with the newest
smash single
from Infant Sorrow.
Lead singer and
notorious lothario,
Aldous Snow,
begs us to change
in his environmental anthem,
We've Got to Do Something.
I hope, for once, we all hear the
message. Good night.
Mr. Prime Minister
and Mr. President
You better see
that it's not only me
No, a mob is rising in size
And they've been dying to scream
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey, baby.
Just working.
Salad.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Totally.
I didn't realize that you were
gonna be back so early.
Great. I'll see you in a bit.
Okay, bye.
It's time to do something
Someone should do something
We got to do something
And that someone is you and you
And you and you
I pray it ain't
all lost and gone
I pray we might
learn right from wrong
And I pray this broken day
will not last too long
Hey, you got here fast.
I got a surprise for you.
Peter, as you know,
I love you very much.
Are you breaking up with me?
Pete, are you...
I just need a minute.
Okay.
(WHIMPERS)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
-Please don't go.
-Why don't you just put on some clothes,
and we can sit
down and discuss this.
No. I can't do
anything right now.
I'm so sorry, Pete.
I'm in love with you.
Why don't you just
put some clothes on, okay?
I'm not going to
go put clothes on.
I know what that means, if I put
clothes on, it's over. Okay?
Excuse me.
Let's talk.
Let's talk about him.
I feel...
I've been feeling
for a long time that we've
been growing apart.
We're leading
different lives.
Who's the dude?
-Who's the dude?
-What?
No, that's not
what this is about.
There's no one else.
I know what's happening here.
I really do.
You've been working
so much lately,
that we haven't got to spend
much time together,
and you're forgetting
what it's like to be with me.
But maybe, if we just held
each other or something,
you would remember
what it's like to be with me.
-No.
-Just hold me.
Please. Here we go.
There's someone else.
I'm sorry.
(LOUNGE MUSIC PLAYING)
We don't hang out
in places like this, Liz and I.
Why did you
take me here?
This place smells
like stripper's perfume.
I'm gonna get herpes
just from sitting on this couch.
-Sure you okay, bro? Yeah?
-Yeah.
Yeah. You don't
have to keep asking me.
I'm good.
You're out!
Thank you so much
for this opportunity.
-Auf Wiedersehen!
MAN ON T. V. : Thank you.
Thank you all.
(CRYING) Auf Wiedersehen!
I feel really good.
I feel happy.
Maybe you should work
on the Dracula musical.
Look, you've been
working on it for a while.
It'll help your mind.
Be creative.
-Think about you.
-I think I need to fuck somebody.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You're not my
stepbrother anymore.
You're a step-stranger.
-Why you talking like that?
-Brian!
You don't need to put
your P in a V right now.
No, I don't. I need to B my L
on somebody's T's.
That's disgusting.
I'm leaving, man.
I'm out of here.
She's fucking somebody.
Okay, Bri? It's all I can think about,
is that she's out there,
and until I do
the same thing,
I'm gonna feel
like I wanna die.
So just talk to girls with
me tonight, all right?
All right. All right,
I'll help you out.
I'll talk to girls
with you.
So, Peter, what do you do?
Musician.
He's being modest. He works on
a show called Crime Scene.
(EXCLAIMS) Oh, my God!
It is what it is,
you know?
No, I love that show.
I find you both very
sexually attractive.
Let's pump the brakes.
Okay?
I think that having
sex with either of you
would be
a great treat for me.
You are so funny.
I just got out of a
five-and-a-haIf-year relationship,
so I'm not looking
for anything serious.
Just sexual activity.
Let's wrap it up, buddy.
You wanna come home?
I'm sorry,
you're cracking me up.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
Do you wanna
come home?
Stop it, seriously.
-That was fun.
-Yeah, yeah.
Overall, I think that
went really well. Yeah.
(IN MONSTER VOICE)
I want to have sex with you!
Are you crying?
What? No.
(CRYING)
Last night, like some
sort of idiot,
I had sex with this woman
who I barely even know.
I used a condom, but
I'm really scared
that I have an STD, Doc.
Peter, I'm a pediatrician.
Have you noticed
you're sitting on a fire truck?
-Right.
-Little kids running?
Yeah, this is new.
I like it.
I'm kind of backed up...
Could you take
a look at my penis?
Go ahead. Let me see it.
-Sorry.
-That's all right. Take it out.
Good.
-You barely looked at it.
-It's a good-looking dick, Peter.
Beautiful dick.
Do you think maybe while I'm here,
I could get some blood work?
Peter!
Your girlfriend
dumped you, right?
Are you hurting?
Are you hurt?
Stop it. Stop crying.
Use your dick.
Keep fucking.
Fuck everything that moves.
Just wear a condom.
You're okay.
Want a lolly?
(MOANING)
I just came!
Hi.
-Hi.
Okay, do you mind not saying that
over and over again?
You can gag me.
You brought a gag?
And handcuffs.
Do you wanna gag me?
Kind of, now.
What've we got today?
Just a walk and
talk at the lab.
That's what 20 years
on Vice will do to you.
What've we got here?
The victim's penis was found
behind the AC unit.
Ouch!
Can you say "dicksicle"?
Let's do this.
Okay, I'm ready.
The victim's penis
was found behind the AC unit.
(PLAYING UPBEAT MELODY)
Just go with
the usual stuff, maybe.
Something dark
and ominous.
Like losing your
penis is a bad thing.
Oh, you want dark
and ominous.
Come on, I got Allman Brother tickets,
I gotta get out of here!
That's what 20 years
on Vice will do to you.
What've we got here?
Peter! Peter,
Jesus Christ!
You're fucking Billy Baldwin,
aren't you?
-Aren't you?
-Pete, Pete, Pete.
-Stop staring at me.
-Pete!
You know you're not getting paid
for today's session, right?
-I'm aware of that.
-Fucking asshole.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
BRIAN: Peter!
Hey, don't walk away
from me.
You come close.
Your place
is disgusting, Peter.
Hey, don't walk
away from me.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Hey!
What are you burning, man?
Come on.
It's everything.
It's everything that reminds me
of her and I need it gone!
Okay, I thought I was
fine, Brian, and I'm not.
I'm not fine at all.
Okay, let's just
put the picture down.
Put that down.
Let's discuss this.
-I love her, man.
-I know.
Look, Liz and I,
we think the world of Sarah.
We think she's great.
Okay, but everything...
I'm just being
honest here.
Every time she would
come over to our house,
she always acted,
you know,
like a little bitch!
Okay, okay,
pump the brakes.
Dating Sarah is not
like dating Liz. Okay?
Sarah is better than Liz.
You really wanna
have this conversation?
Do you really wanna have
this conversation?
-Yes.
-She is the mother of my unborn child.
-Sorry.
-You're my stepbrother. We're not even blood.
I have no qualms
with sticking you.
I will equalize you.
-Sorry.
-You dick!
I'm just worked up.
You gotta get your
shit together, man.
I'm trying to.
It's so hard here.
Brian, everywhere I look,
I'm reminded of her, okay?
Like, she got me this,
okay, because I would always leave
my cereal boxes open,
and the cereal
would get stale,
and so one day I came home,
and she had this waiting for me,
because it keeps
my cereal fresh.
And now I have
the freshest cereal.
Why don't you, you know what,
go on a vacation?
Go to the Alps.
-Alps?
-Go to Gstaad. It's the best.
I could go to Hawaii.
Sarah was always
talking about this place
in Hawaii that was
supposed to be nice.
No, don't.
I wouldn't go there.
What, I can't go to
Hawaii now,
because Sarah Marshall
has heard of Hawaii?
Then go to Hawaii.
Go to Hawaii.
Do it.
(MUMBLING)
No, no, no,
don't destroy the computer.
I'm just
deleting these pictures.
Okay, I need them
off my computer.
You know what? You're not even doing
a proper permanent delete.
Well...
If we end up
getting back together,
I wanna have
a few of them left.
You're crazy.
-No, no, please don't delete them.
-They have to go.
(SCREAMING)
Done, done.
Aloha!
Check in this way.
-Just married?
-Yes, how did you guess?
Oh, you've got that
magic newlywed dust all over you.
Oh, my wife.
Oh, my husband.
-Oh, my wife.
-My husband.
My old ball and chain.
You quit squirming
and come here.
What is into you?
Not me, yet.
Here is your room key.
So you're all set. Room 222.
Room key's inside,
and the elevators are to the right.
Mahalo.
Congratulations.
Here you go, sir.
Have some POG juice.
Welcome to Turtle Bay.
What can I do for you?
I'm checking in. My name's Bretter,
Peter Bretter,
but actually,
I don't have a reservation.
I just thought
I'd take my chances.
Bold!
We are all booked up, but we do have
the Kapua suite available.
Okay. How much is that?
$6,000 a night.
-Wow.
-Beautiful views.
I can imagine.
That's a little bit
out of my price range.
Sorry.
That's a shame.
This is a beautiful
hotel.
Oh, yeah, it's Sarah Marshall
from Crime Scene.
People are excited
that she's here.
She's my ex-girlfriend.
We broke up three weeks ago.
I'm sorry, sir.
-Right. This is fine, right?
-Sir?
It's totally fine.
Okay, there she is.
-Did she see me?
-Uh-huh.
-Is she coming over here?
-Yup.
I wish I wasn't
wearing this fucking shirt.
Fair enough. Why don't you
try to unbutton it?
Button it back up.
-Peter!
-Hey.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
Came here to murder you.
Really, what are you
doing here?
l have been having a tough time,
you know, back in LA.
But then I came here,
and here you are.
I just think that's
too crazy to be...
Hello there,
you little sex object.
I've lost a shoe.
Have you
seen it anywhere?
It's like this one, but, you know,
obviously it's the opposite one.
Excuse me,
missus, I've lost a shoe.
Like this one.
It's like this one's fellow.
-Sort of the exact opposite, in fact, of that.
-RACHEL: Uh-huh.
Not an evil version,
but just, you know,
a shoe like this,
but for the other foot.
Otherwise,
I'd have two right...
Aldous, this is Peter.
Hey, all right, Peter.
Nice to meet you, mate.
Aldous.
Good to meet you, man.
My ex-boyfriend.
Right.
Hey, I'm Aldous Snow.
I know who you are.
Yeah, you're very, very famous.
Yeah, I am.
I am for my sins.
So are you
staying here, as well?
-I'm not, as a matter of fact...
-I'm sorry.
Excuse me, Mr. Bretter,
Ms. Marshall,
but we were able to book the
Kapua suite for you, sir, for four nights.
-You were?
-Yes, sir.
-Marvelous.
-Perfect. Perfect amount of time.
Listen, if you wanna have dinner
with us one of those nights...
-Aldous.
-…feel very...
No.
That's very gentlemanly of you,
but you two enjoy your trip.
I'll be just fine
on my own.
ALDOUS: All right, Peter.
The Kapua suite...
-Have a good trip, Pete.
-You too.
RACHEL:
I'll call lost and found.
Thank you.
Thank you for bailing me out.
I still can't
afford that room.
Nobody can. It's for, like, Oprah or,
like, Céline Dion.
Really, it's not a big deal.
So you can stay in the suite,
but since you're not technically a guest,
you have to clean
up after yourself.
Otherwise,
here is your room key
and enjoy your stay.
Why are you
doing this for me?
She's here with
some guy already?
Kind of messed up.
-Right?
-Yeah.
-Thank you.
-Really, it's not a big deal.
Go enjoy yourself.
Rachel Jansen.
A thousand times, thank you,
-you know what I mean...
-Go enjoy yourself.
This is a disaster!
BRIAN ON PHONE:
Calm down, man.
Are there other
hotels on the island?
(WHISPERING) Of course
there are other hotels,
but I'm not leaving here,
it'll look like I'm running away.
Wait. Why are you whispering?
You're not following them, are you?
I had a girlfriend,
right?
And Liam and Noel Gallagher
both had it off with her right in front of me,
so that's similar.
And that was
a bit awkward, actually.
So if you do wanna change hotels,
I quite understand.
No, no, I'm not
changing hotels.
Stop following and just go back
to your room, Peter.
They're gone!
Why are you
looking for them?
-I don't know.
-You're acting like an idiot.
Run! Get out of there!
Go to your room!
What do you
think they're doing?
Peter, go.
Oh, God!
Okay, there they are.
-There they are, I see them.
-Go back to your room, Peter.
Peter, go back to your room.
Go back to your room, Peter.
-I'm going in.
-Go back to your room, Peter.
Are you listening to me?
Peter, go back to your room.
Peter, Peter, Peter…
Hey!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hey, nice room.
BRIAN: Go!
I am in the Kapua suite.
BRIAN: What are you doing?
Sucker!
Have fun.
BRIAN:
Listen, you piece of shit!
You're an idiot. Back to your room, Peter.
Peter, back to your room.
(PETER SOBS ON PHONE)
Did you enjoy that?
Did you like what you saw?
That hurt a lot.
But I know Sarah, and I'm pretty sure
I just ruined her day.
(SCREAMING)
You know how we thought
the killer masturbated
before he committed
each homicide?
That's the theory.
Take a look
at the microscope.
Oh, yeah, looks like
where he's going,
he'll need to know
how to masturbate.
(CRYING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(SNIFFLING)
Oh, God!
-Hello.
RACHEL ON PHONE: Hey, Peter?
-Sarah?
-No.
It's Rachel Jansen,
from the front desk.
Hey!
Hey, what's going
on up there?
I'm getting complaints
about a woman crying hysterically.
Yeah, you know what,
I hear her, too,
and it sounds like
she's having such a hard time.
I think it's coming
from the floor above me.
You're on the top floor.
I'll try to keep it down.
Are you okay?
Yeah, you have a nice night.
Okay.
(CRYING)
I would love to sell
you some weed, Jeremy,
but I'm at my
fucking job right now.
Obviously, because
you called me at work,
you know that
I'm at my place of work.
So I can't just leave here
and sell you some weed.
I can sell you some
weed when I'm done.
Hold on,
I gotta call you back.
Mahalo, all right.
Hey, how's it going?
Hey.
I'd just like to grab
some dinner, please.
Okay, great.
Is your wife gonna meet you?
No.
Your girlfriend?
No, I don't have
a girlfriend.
You're just by yourself?
Yeah.
Sucks.
Okay, so just one. Here's your
wine list and your menu. Come on.
Do you want, like,
a magazine or something?
It's gonna be boring if you're just
sitting by yourself.
I'll be all right.
Thank you.
I just would be
so depressed.
-Yeah.
-Here you go.
Thank you.
The best thing is, you have the
greatest table in the house.
-Oh, yeah?
-That's Aldous Snow right there.
I know. I know, dude.
I know.
I'm gonna ask him.
I'll ask him politely.
Mate!
Why don't you come over and sit with us?
You'll be very welcome.
No, thank you.
I need a drink.
Would you guys like a drink?
Well, no, actually,
because...
Seven years clean.
That's what this
tattoo denotes.
Seven years free
from drugs and alcohol.
If I have just
one sip of wine,
by the end of the evening,
I'll be, like, rimming waiters for their tips
just to get me
hands on a rock.
You know
what I mean? Nasty.
MATTHEW: (CHUCKLING)
I heard that.
Hey, what's up, man?
How are you enjoying
your vegetable medley?
It's mundane.
It is mundane.
It's great, I know.
Will you marry me?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Yes!
-She said yes!
-Beautiful.
(PEOPLE ALL APPLAUDING)
Congratulations!
(SQUEALING)
I'm so excited!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Peter!
What's up?
-Are you doing okay?
-Yeah.
Yeah, I'm good.
Look, did you
follow me here?
Did my assistant
tell you I was coming?
-No.
-Did you talk to her?
No, I didn't talk
to your assistant.
It's not all
about you, you know.
Hawaii is a beautiful place.
People come here,
usually not to follow you.
So you're really staying?
You're gonna stay?
Yeah, I think so.
I really like it here.
I feel at home here.
I just love it.
Yeah, you should stay.
I appreciate
your consideration.
Sounds like Aldous probably
shared a lot of needles,
so thank you for
dating him after me.
I appreciate that.
Hope you have
a really good time here.
Have a great dinner.
Thank you.
PETER: Groupie whore.
SARAH: Psycho stalker.
You know what? It's vacation.
I think I'll just take a piña colada, please.
Look at this guy.
Not us, buddy.
Right? Not us.
I'm on Sex and the City.
What's up, Miranda?
I'm Samantha.
I have sex with everyone.
Maybe it's a good
thing that they're here.
You know what I mean?
Maybe this is a challenge from God
for me to forget her.
You know?
Or maybe it's a sign from God
that you should be with her.
I love her show.
When they mix the sexuality
and the violence, I like it.
What the hell is wrong with you two?
You gotta move on.
I hear you say that,
but it's not that easy.
It's that easy.
Promise you it is.
I lived in South Central.
South Central.
And I hated it.
That's why
I moved to Oahu.
Now I can name you
over 200 different kinds of fish.
-PETER: No, you can't.
-Oh, yes, I can.
-Do it.
-Yeah, you cannot.
G. Ghost pipefish, grill fish, goaler fish
grouper fish, greenback...
What's the state
fish of Hawaii?
Humuhumunukunukuapua'a.
Yeah, bitch.
Hey.
You ready?
Yeah, just gonna
close up.
Hello, Mr. Bretter,
Mr. Brayden.
Where's your wife,
sir?
She is in bed.
How are things
going with the lady?
Not awesome. She's complicated,
like The Da Vinci Code,
you know,
but harder to crack.
But life is full of lessons.
You learn
something new every day.
Wonder what I'm going
to learn tomorrow.
Well.
-Good night, sir.
-Good night.
Good night, sir.
Off to find
the mythical clitoris.
So, Peter,
were you able to get
that crying lady out of your room?
'Cause I could
send someone up, if you want.
-Oh, you could?
-Yeah.
That's very funny. It is.
Well, listen, Sarah Marshall
Show sucks. Who cares?
I do the music
for that program.
Did I mention
that the music rocks?
That's very sweet of you.
That's very
sweet of you to say.
You don't have to say that, though.
It's not music.
There's no melody,
it's just tones.
Just dark, ominous tones.
"The masturbating dog killer
is on the loose again.
"He'll kill the owner, but at least
the dogs are happy."
(SNICKERS)
(IMITATING KEYBOARD)
I'm no Aldous Snow,
I guess, you know.
(SINGING DRUNKENLY)
Time to start the music
All gonna light the light
Yeah, yeah, gonna get things started
on The Muppet Show tonight
(CRYING)
-Whipped cream or berry?
-Whipped cream.
Here we are, sir.
Have a wonderful breakfast.
What a lovely table,
so close to the buffet.
I'm glad you like it.
Mahalo.
Good morning, sir.
Can I start you with anything?
Orange juice, coffee?
What about,
like, some pineapple juice
with a little bit
of rum on the side.
Of course. I like
your style. Cocktail guy.
-Thank you.
-You are welcome.
We've already reserved
the sea kayak for noon.
Honey, I know that, but you know that
I wanted to see...
-Hey. Hello there, friend.
-Hey.
How are you guys?
How was your evening?
-Great.
-Awesome.
I can't feel anything.
All right.
Does that feel good?
I still can't feel anything.
Okay, 'cause
it hurts me.
Would you
do that for me?
Yeah.
-Yeah
-No, no, no. No.
God put our mouths on our head
for a reason. No!
-I'm going to the bathroom.
-Okay.
Is everything okay with...
Waffles.
Here you go, sir.
Breakfast of champions.
Oh, thank you.
And don't tell anybody,
but...
A little extra love
for you.
Thank you.
-Take it easy.
-You, too.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
Hey.
Are you Chuck?
Oh, man, you know,
they won't change that flyer.
That's my mainland name.
My Hawaiian name is Koonu.
Cool, sorry.
No, it's all good.
Does Koonu have some, like,
cool Hawaiian meaning?
It means Chuck.
I plugged it into a database.
There's a thing you can go on,
on the Internet,
you just type in your name,
and it just says it.
What's your name?
-I'm Peter.
-Peter.
-Yeah.
-I'm gonna give you a Hawaiian name.
Oh, great.
Pepiopi.
-Great.
-Pepiopi, looks like you've got a little pain
behind those eyes.
Yeah, maybe a little.
There's really only
one cure for that.
What's that?
Weed. You got any?
-No.
-Well, then let's go surfing.
Okay, when we're out there,
I want you to ignore your instincts.
I'm gonna
be your instincts.
Koonu will be
your instincts.
Don't do anything.
Don't try to surf,
don't do it.
The less you do,
the more you do.
Let's see you pop up.
Pop it up!
That's not it at all.
Do less. Get down.
Try less. Do it again.
Pop up.
No, too slow. Do less.
You're doing too much.
Do less. Pop down.
Pop up now.
Stop!
Get down. Get down there.
Remember,
don't do anything.
Nothing. Pop up.
Well, you... No,
you gotta do more than that,
'cause you're just
laying right out.
It looks like
you're boogie-boarding.
Just do it.
Feel it. Pop up.
Yeah. That wasn't quite it,
but we're gonna figure it out, out there.
Let's go surfing, come on.
Everybody's learning how,
come on and...
(SINGING)
The weather outside is weather
PETER:
How long you lived out here?
Man, I don't know. I quit wearing a
watch when I moved out here.
-Wow, that's so cool.
-Yeah.
No, like my cell phone has a clock
on it, so I don't really need it.
Right, so it's basically
the same thing.
-How old are you?
-I don't really believe in age or numbers,
you know, I don't... I mean, if you had
to put a number on it,
I guess I'd be 44.
Fuck!
Thanks for
taking me out here.
This is the first time I've felt good
in three weeks or so.
You need to get back on that board
is what you need to do.
-Yeah?
-Hey, here's the deal.
When life gives you lemons,
just say,
"Fuck the lemons," and bail.
Yeah.
No. You said it, totally.
You gotta just pull yourself up
by your wetsuit,
get back on that board...
Hey, look, man,
if you're attacked by a shark,
are you gonna
give up surfing?
Probably, yeah.
Let's go in, all right.
Tacos are on me.
Can you try to listen
to what I'm saying to you, Brian?
I'm confused and
I don't know what to do.
What's up with that hat?
What are you in the Buena
Vista Social Club?
This is a nice hat.
What member of
the Brat Pack are you?
You look like one of those guys
suspected of killing JFK.
That's very funny.
That's great.
LIZ:
Tell him to make friends.
You need to get out there
and make some friends, man.
Is Liz there right now?
No, no, she's not
in here, buddy.
I just heard her.
She's gone.
Who are you looking at?
What?
Is she still... Hi, Liz.
No. I swear on my
mother's grave, it…
Okay, it was Liz.
She wasn't here
the entire time.
Go out and meet people.
We meet people
all the time…
-All the time on vacation.
-Constantly.
I've tried, all right, there's
a couple of dudes here,
but they're kind of weird.
Just be friendly.
Iron your shirt.
Iron your shirt, look sharp.
Even your T-shirts.
There is this girl at the front
desk who's pretty cute.
Oh, yeah. You know what? Go have
another dirty one night stand.
That worked out
so well before.
What do you want from me?
You just told me I need to meet people.
Ask her out.
Maybe that's what he needs,
is a rebound.
BRIAN: He's had plenty of chances
for rebounds. This isn't…
LIZ: Can we get on
the same team here?
Okay, I 'm sorry.
We're on the same team.
Sorry.
LIZ: You should go on
a date with this girl.
Well, maybe I'll ask
her out then.
-LIZ: Yes.
-My wife says so.
Hey, I'm in Hawaii, too!
LIZ: Oh, that's neat.
Aloha, bitches!
That's very cool.
(CHANTING)
They're not Native Americans,
Brian.
-Bri...
-What are you doing?
-The luha. Is that right?
-Oh, yeah.
It's called the hula.
-Luau?
-No, hula.
You're doing a luau?
(SINGING)
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
-Hey.
-PETER: Hey.
-Peter.
-Wow.
You look beautiful.
I mean,
that's a beautiful dress.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
This'll be fun.
Lei?
May I help you with
something else, Peter?
No, I'll just grab a drink.
I'm just gonna head inside.
Happy 4th of July!
Thank you.
Aloha!
(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
-You done here?
-No, actually, I just sat down,
I'm just getting started.
It's delicious,
though, thank you.
I'll just go fuck myself.
-Sorry, what?
-Mahalo.
SARAH: Hi, Peter.
Hey. Hey, bro.
-Hi.
-Hey, all right.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Everybody, can I have your attention
for one second, please.
We have a very special guest
with us here, today.
He is the lead singer
of the band, Infant Sorrow,
one of my favorite
musicians of all time.
He's so awesome.
Please, please, let's take...
Let's see if we can get him up here,
Mr. Aldous Snow.
Please, come on.
Share your gift.
Duty calls and all that.
I'm trying to be incognito,
it's weird.
It's like work to me,
this is no fun.
Hey! Thank you!
ALDOUS: Thank you.
What a lovely introduction.
What an eccentric and
confident young man.
I'd like to
dedicate this song
to a very beautiful
woman that's here today.
It's Miss Sarah Marshall,
there she is.
Look at her, blimey!
(SINGING) Old
as ancient skies
I've had these wandering eyes
but you took me by surprise
when you let me inside you
Inside you
This went from
6:00 to midnight.
Teach me how to grow
while I'm moving inside of you
Inside of you
Inside you
I long to be,
is it wrong to be
inside of you
Inside of you
the restless find their dreams
Hey.
You're from
the breakfast buffet, right?
-Yeah.
-Whipped cream or berries?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm Peter.
-Kemo.
Good to meet you, man.
Good to meet, you, man.
Have a beer.
Thanks. Thank you.
Sarah Marshall.
Yes.
How do you know
I was dating Sarah Marshall?
Dwayne told me.
Chuck told me.
Even Rachel told me.
I heard about it
from everybody.
You gotta stop
talking about it.
It's like The Sopranos.
It's over.
Find a new show.
You need a hug.
Come here.
Oh, thank you.
You're awfully nice.
I gotta go.
I'm prepping the pig
for tomorrow's luau.
You should come and help me.
It'll take your
mind off of things.
-Yeah? You don't mind?
-No.
I mean, I must say
I'm a pretty good cook.
All right!
(PIG GRUNTING)
I can't!
Please don't make me do this!
Do it!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
(PETER CRYING)
KEMO:
You can stop crying now.
He's dead already.
PETER: I'm not crying.
You should stop crying.
KEMO: I don't cry.
I'm not a baby.
PETER: Really?
'Cause you look
like a gigantic baby.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that at all.
Hey.
Listen, would you
like to hang out tonight,
like, not in
an official hotel function?
Yeah. Totally.
A bunch of us are
going to go to this,
like, little beach
thing afterwards.
You're totally
welcome to come.
Maybe we could
go together?
Yeah, whatever.
I mean we don't have to,
if you don't want to,
I just thought
that maybe...
No, listen, you don't have to
make this weird.
You either want
to go or you don't.
-I would love to.
-Okay.
Awesome. Why don't you go upstairs,
change that shirt,
and I'll meet you out
front in, like, five?
This is so cool.
You like it?
So what brought
you to Hawaii?
A dude.
Of course.
A surfer dude.
You know, WCT, top 44.
Totally.
We were together
for two years.
Dropped out of school,
moved out here with him.
Three weeks later,
I caught him cheating on me,
so I moved out,
and that's that.
What an asshole.
No, he's just a boy.
You ever think about going back
home, finishing school, or...
No.
No. I work at the hotel,
doesn't really have to
be a future in there.
Okay, my turn.
Okay.
So, how do you like
writing music for a TV show?
It's great, you know.
People are great.
It's great to have
a steady paycheck.
It's... I'm very lucky.
-Oh, my God, you hate it.
-I fucking hate it so much.
So then,
do something about it.
(SARCASTICALLY)
Excuse me.
I'm just saying, if you hate
something, change it.
-Don't dwell.
-Well, I'm trying.
I'm actually
working on a rock opera.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
What's your
rock opera about?
Dracula.
Yeah, and eternal love,
you know.
That's the theme.
But I think the two sort of go
hand in hand, you know?
And I...
I have this vision of
doing it with puppets.
(LAUGHS)
I mean, humans also,
you know.
Why Dracula?
Because he's a man
like anyone else.
He just wants
to be loved.
And every time he gets close
to a human woman,
he ends up
smothering and killing her,
which is a feeling
I am familiar with.
What?
That's just a joke.
-What?
-Oh, shit.
My ex. If I run, you run.
-Do you understand?
-No, I don't understand at all.
Fucking motherfucker!
Dipshit!
Rachel,
what are you doing?
I thought I told you
to stay back on your island.
Take it easy,
just take it easy.
Yeah, you know what?
The deal was over April 9.
Well, the deal's
back on, motherfucker.
You ain't the chief in this
village. I'm the chief.
Of the idiots?
Rachel, let me handle this.
I know his friend.
Let me handle this, okay?
Go ahead.
Hey, man, you remember me
from breakfast?
Oh, yeah, the cocktail guy,
that's right.
Yeah.
This ain't
the breakfast buffet.
What, you with my girl?
Keeping her warm
for me at night, huh?
Hey, what are you doing here?
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
RACHEL:
That's right. Just hit him!
Rachel, we gotta get
out of here. Rachel?
You get what you deserve.
(PLAYING POP MUSIC)
Just a boy?
No, that dude
was a fucking man.
No, no, no.
He's an asshole.
I can't believe
I ever dated him.
You went nuts.
Yeah.
You guys are dysfunctional.
You were like one of those girls
from Flavor of Love.
-From what?
-You were.
"I'll kill you.
I'll kill you."
(RACHEL LAUGHING)
Okay, I'm gonna go
get us another round.
I'II grab it.
It's no big deal.
You don't have to
dote on me.
I'm not that type of girl.
(INAUDIBLE)
You look so hot.
Give me Crime Scene.
Give me dirty Crime Scene girl.
André the Giant,
out of the shot, please.
Mutombo,
out of the shot, come on.
Did you know that
there's a picture of you flashing,
hanging in the men's room?
Yeah. I hate it so much.
My jackass
boyfriend made me do it.
Keoki took it,
right there.
And I asked him
to take it down,
but he said that it would ruin
the balance of the collage.
Do you want me to try
to get it down for you?
No. No, no, no,
he'll kill you.
Like, really kill you.
But I have
a surprise for you.
Really, what?
MAN: We're gonna
take a quick break.
Tonight we have a special guest
from the mainland,
singing a song from
his Dracula musical,
please welcome to the stage,
Mr. Peter Bretter.
(WHOOPS)
Peter!
Yeah! Go get them, tiger!
Please don't.
(EXCLAIMING)
Peter!
Rachel...
Dracula! Peter!
Get them!
What's up?
Thank you.
You know,
I could play something else.
I just think out of
context this might be...
RACHEL: Dracula musical!
Thank you.
(SINGING) It's getting
kind of hard to believe
things are
going to get better
I've been drowning too long to believe
that the tide's going to turn
And I've been living
too hard to believe
things are going
to get easier now
I'm still trying to shake off the pain
from the lessons I've learned
And if I see Van Helsing,
I swear to the lord I will slay him
(LAUGHING MENACINGLY)
Take it from me, but I swear
I won't let it be so
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Blood will run down his face
when he is decapitated
His head on my mantle
is how I will let this one know
How much I love you
Die
I can't
(CHEERS)
RACHEL: Awesome!
PETER: Thank you.
Thank you.
So, I had a really,
really great time tonight.
-Yeah?
-Yeah. I mean, it got a little wild.
-"A little"? You can say that.
-Yeah.
But it was really fun,
and you're so cool, and it was...
Thank you for taking me out.
No, I had a great time.
Thank you.
-You did?
-Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I just...
I don't...
I just don't wanna
complicate things.
-No, of course!
-Yeah?
No, no, no. Totally.
I totally get that.
I had a great time.
A handshake?
-Well, I don't know. Okay.
-All right, all right.
All right. Get home safe.
You, too.
-Thanks again.
-Bye.
(ALDOUS SINGING) I'm on
a hammock with me lady
Watching the sea roll by
Things have been great now
'Cause we're in Hawaii
Hey, guys.
Hey, man. I'm Koonu.
Yeah. No, I remember.
I'm Peter.
We took a surf
lesson together.
Yeah, you're that guy
that works with Kaiser Permanente.
No, I'm Peter.
We had a nice talk
out on the water.
That's cool.
Okay, can I just say
something?
I went on a date
tonight with Rachel, right?
That wasn't a date.
She's in customer service, dude.
She took you out
for charity.
It was a date, okay?
Trust me.
I know a date,
and that was a date.
I bet you think
strippers like you, too.
-That's really not necessary.
-It's true.
Don't waste your time, man.
Believe me, it is a nowhere road. I know.
Did you see
her ex-boyfriend?
He is ridiculous.
Who, Greg?
I love Greg, man.
I saw him beat up
a guy with a starfish.
Okay, that's just
ridiculous.
That guy was me.
Dude, my homie over here,
on his honeymoon?
Getting as much sex
as he possibly can ever have.
Are you giving to her
hard and rough, dude?
Come on.
The wife wants me to do certain things
that I find inappropriate.
Let me just say that if God was
a city planner,
he would not put a playground
next to a sewage system.
We're trying to fuck,
but we're not having fun fucking.
We're just, like...
I'm stabbing her private parts,
and it's not fun,
and it causes anxiety.
Fucking is...
And then when
you're not fucking...
PETER: Hey,
someone's gotta stop him.
You're the butt of a joke.
Fucking this ring is...
Fuck!
It's gonna be
all right.
Hi.
Hi, do you wanna
come back to bed?
Sure.
Have fun.
I like her hair.
I wonder if the carpet
matches her pubes.
(PHONE BUZZING)
Julian, what's up?
Oh.
God.
The show's been canceled.
That's good, 'cause
that's what you wanted.
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
It's just... I guess I thought
we had another year left.
It seems like we did, and...
This'll be good,
'cause it's been a long-awaited
transition into film for me.
Don't get me wrong,
but it's just...
It's a surprise.
Come on tour with me.
I'II serenade you every night in
front of thousands of women.
I didn't know you
were going on tour.
Yeah, I'm going
in two weeks.
It's like an 18-month tour,
43 countries, Infant Sorrow,
and it's gonna
be a massive tour.
Yeah. I can't come
'cause I have a job.
I'm a working actress.
Not anymore.
You're an unemployed
actress, perfect.
You could be the queen of the groupies,
queen of the Sorrow Suckers.
The Sorrow Suckers.
Sorrow Suckers. I don't know
why they call them that.
MATTHEW:
Mr. and Mrs. Snow, sorry.
Sorry to bother you.
The hotel wanted to offer you some
complimentary coconut cake.
It's from the hotel. It's definitely not
from me personally, so...
Yeah, thanks.
Okay, great.
When were you
planning on telling me this?
I just told you, then.
Yeah. No, I know.
But telling me now isn't really
the same as telling me.
Well, look, you know, I've not told you
I've got genital herpes,
because it's not
inflamed at the moment.
Do you guys want some
champagne with your cake,
or do you want it
without your cake?
ALDOUS: I don't drink.
All right, so I came here
to give you my demo. I just...
I worship you, and I just wanted
to give you my demo.
Just take a listen and...
Okay.
'Cause you know what?
You don't wanna be the guy sitting there,
watching BBC, and saying,
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT)
"Oh, I saw that guy! He was my waiter,
"and I totally dismissed him
like everyone else does in his life.
"And I totally was wrong,
"because he's a major, major,
major influence on me now,
"and I feel terrible!"
(CLEARS THROAT)
That stupid English voice,
was that me?
Unfortunately, yes.
Hey, look, just don't
tell anyone at the hotel.
What's up, dude?
What's up?
Peter, I got some
really interesting news this morning.
What's up?
Crime Scene was canceled.
Whoa.
Wow.
-You all right?
-Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, I've been waiting
to take the next step,
you know, into features for a long
time, so it's a really good thing.
This isn't The View.
I mean, we can have an honest talk
about this if we want.
I don't wanna step out of the spotlight
and then be forgotten.
I don't wanna disappear.
I'm freaked out.
I wanna be honest. I'm really freaked
out right now, okay?
Because, seemingly, the only actresses
that actually can survive
are the ones that
show their cooter,
and, excuse me,
but I refuse to do that.
I have a little dignity.
And I don't have the frame to
support plastic surgery. I would tip over.
And I'm not gonna do that.
I'm not gonna exploit myself.
Listen,
you're gonna be fine.
You have along
career ahead of you.
You've got, like,
four years until you're 30.
It's gonna be fine.
How are you?
I'm screwed.
Frankly,
I don't stand a chance.
No, I'll be fine.
I've been quietly stealing money
from you for a long time.
You're always good at cheering
me up, Pete, thank you.
(SINGING) Die
Die
I can't
It's really good, Peter.
I just don't understand it. I don't.
I mean,
just chalk it up to that.
Please don't play it again,
'cause I don't...
Just listen to it one
more time and see...
Where's Aldous?
Mr. Snow,
may I ask you a question?
Okay.
I want to please my wife here,
on our honeymoon,
but I don't know
what I'm doing.
You having
difficulty sex-wise?
Do you not know
how to use this?
I know how.
Have you had sex before?
We can't.
-Why?
-Our religion.
Right, 'cause of God
and everything?
Hey, that's not
gonna be a problem,
because God should be
present in the bedroom.
Just tell me
specifically what I need to do.
You need to penetrate deeply
and stimulate the clitoris simultaneously.
That's what you gotta do.
That's what it's about.
If you can involve
the anus in that,
then that's
absolute perfection.
Got it.
Explore her ears.
Find it in you to be
a little more circly.
You are a man.
God's within you.
I actually feel
okay about it.
You know, I'm a little scared,
but I'll be all right.
I'll get another job.
That's interesting, man.
-You know what else is interesting?
-What?
Me on the moon.
I just wanna talk to
you about something.
Can you stop?
All right, I'm just
gonna talk, and then...
Air!
There was this
interesting moment with Sarah.
Whoa, what?
I don't wanna hear about your interesting
moment with Sarah, Pete.
Then who am I supposed to
talk to about this?
Well, not me, because
have I ever had
an interesting moment
with an ex-girlfriend?
Do you have
an ex-girlfriend? No!
No.
LIZ: No.
I would really love to get the woman's
perspective on the matter.
-Really?
-No
But come on in
and just sit down.
Stay. You have to…
Honey, no,
no, the camera's right there.
No, I know, but I just wanna
tell him, though.
No, the camera…
Think about how
much she's hurt you.
-Hey, Liz?
-Yeah?
I think you need to
move just a tiny bit
further away
from the microphone.
-Just…
-No, closer.
-Now a little further.
-Okay.
-Closer.
-And then…
-And then a little further, and then closer.
-I don't know.
-Keep your head down, though.
-I'm bad at this thing.
-Can you hear me?
-Yeah, closer. Further away.
I know what
you're doing.
That's not funny
at all.
You stop that.
What?
-What's he doing?
-Come on. Yeah, yeah, real funny.
Hey, that's a great
necklace, Liz.
-Thank you!
-Did you have that a second ago?
That's gross!
-LIZ: I don't get it.
-Stop it.
Hey, Dracula!
"And when I see Van Helsing,
I swear to the Lord, I'II slay him."
(GROWLS)
That shit is funny, dude!
Hey, Pete.
So I was gonna go over
to Lazy Joe's later tonight,
and I wanted to see
if you wanted to come and join.
I think I'm confused,
because I thought last night...
Oh, my God.
Dude, get out of your head.
It's really nice out here.
Yeah, I bet it is.
All right, yeah.
You know what?
I could totally use
a friendly hangout, so...
All right.
I don't know if you want,
instead of Lazy Joe's,
I was thinking of going
to Laie Point right now.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I heard that place
was a pain in the ass.
RACHEL: Okay.
-Hey!
-DWAYNE: Yo, what's up, guys?
PETER: We're just
going for a hike.
No, you're not,
you're going snorkeling.
PETER: I think we're
gonna go on a hike.
DWAYNE: It is sea turtle
fucking season, dude. Let's go.
They fuck for
three hours, dude.
I mean, that's magical.
-No, we're going on a hike.
-I think we'll go on a hike, yeah.
What? Your loss.
Why won't anybody
go snorkeling with me?
How you doing back there?
Awesome.
I don't think I've ever been
this covered in sweat before.
It's like I have
some sort of fever.
I told you this was
a pain in the ass.
Could've been
at Lazy Joe's.
Oh, yeah.
PETER: Oh, shit.
-You good?
-No.
(LAUGHING)
PETER: Wow, we're really going
up to the edge of this, huh?
Look!
Wow, this is
really beautiful.
All right,
so now that your show's done,
are you gonna finish
the Dracula musical?
It's not that easy,
you know.
Sarah always thought
it was crazy, and...
Well,
you're definitely crazy.
But so is everyone, right?
So who cares?
I just don't feel
like doing anything.
Why?
'Cause my heart
is broken,
and I can't imagine
doing anything right now.
It's probably the same reason
you don't go back to school, you know?
Maybe it's good we
got hurt like that, you know?
I don't know about you,
but it makes me feel impervious to pain.
Yeah. Kind of like
there's nothing left to be afraid of.
Yeah. No, exactly.
Right.
We could leap off this rock,
and it won't hurt us as bad as they did.
So jump, then.
No, I meant that,
like, as a metaphor, you know?
No. Just do it.
You'll be fine. Jump.
What the hell?
Oh, God! Oh, God.
I made her kill herself!
(EXCLAIMING)
You must be crazy!
So are you
gonna jump or what?
No!
Come on, Peter!
I can see your
vagina from here!
I can see your hoo-ha.
I mean, I'll jump!
Chicken! Come on!
(GROANING)
(SHOUTING)
Please, God,
don't let me die today.
-I'm okay!
-Okay!
I'll just let go, right?
No, no, no!
If you fall straight down, you'd probably
hit a rock and kill yourself!
-Totally.
-Yeah.
So what do I do?
Why don't you press your feet
up against the rock,
and, like,
shoot yourself off!
-What, like a frog?
-I don't know, Peter!
Just get off
the fucking rock!
Here I go!
Okay!
PETER: One!
Two!
Two and a half!
Jump!
Three!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
-You saw that, right?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, I saw it!
I was there.
I witnessed it.
Thanks.
Come on.
You've got Christ
between your thighs,
but with a shorter beard.
Mahalo.
Aloha.
Sex!
I'm cramping, I'm cramping.
-Okay.
-Okay, okay.
Petey? Petey?
Sorry. I knocked a bunch.
You were really out.
Ken sent me.
Dakota Farming and her people,
they need this room.
Oh.
So does that mean I
have to leave the hotel?
Ken found you a room.
I'll take it, yeah.
I wanna hang out with
Rachel a little more.
Are those sad tissues
or happy tissues?
Maybe you should
just give me a minute.
It was the only
room available!
I'm sure it was!
Hey, how's it going?
It's all right.
Really?
I think you got some
pain behind those eyes.
-A kind of pain that only...
-Okay, you know what?
Let's cut the bullshit.
I wanna stand up on
a wave before I leave.
I don't think
you're ready yet, man.
I'm ready to
ride giants, Koonu.
I think you're ready.
Petey!
-Hi.
Miss Marshall,
what can I do for you?
Is there a place to get good
sushi around here?
Yeah. Yeah,
there's a really great place
about five minutes
from here called Asuki.
Perfect.
-Do you want me to get you a map?
-Please.
Okay.
So, this is where we are.
Head down Kamehameha, and then pass
Funaho Loko Marsh.
And it should be
right to the left.
It might take,
like, five minutes.
Great. Thank you.
Any time.
Um...
-I saw you with Peter Bretter...
-Yeah.
...who's my ex-boyfriend.
Oh, my God.
I'm really sorry.
-It's not like that at all.
-No.
-It's not what you're…
-No, it's fine.
I'm just really glad you're keeping
him company, 'cause...
Gosh, no.
...you seem like
a really nice person,
-and you're very pretty.
-Thank you.
Gosh, you're,
like, way prettier.
No, you're, like,
so pretty.
Really?
-Yeah.
-Wow, thank you. Thank you.
And one more
thing about Peter.
He's a really good guy.
Really good.
Like, great, actually.
Yeah.
Um...
Please don't cry,
Miss Marshall.
God. Do you need me
to get you a tissue?
Oh, no, I'm good,
I'm good. I'm okay, I'm okay.
Okay.
Thank you, Rachel.
Any time, Miss Marshall.
Hey, ahoy, there!
You surf, too?
Good Lord, no.
I'm just drifting around,
you know?
Getting in touch with
the ocean and stuff.
It's really pleasant.
It was, yeah.
I'm gonna head in.
Before you go, actually, Peter,
I just wanted to tell you,
l was listening to Sarah's
iPod the other day,
and amidst the interminable dross
that's on that thing,
I found one track
that I quite liked.
So I checked what it was,
and it was actually one of yours.
And it kind of
reminded me of a dark,
gothic Neil Diamond.
It's great.
That's, like,
exactly what I'm going for.
Right, yeah.
Fuck.
Fuck, you're cool.
It's so hard to say, because, like,
I hate you in so many ways,
but whatever. I can see why
Sarah likes you.
No accounting for taste,
I suppose.
In her case, anyway.
She was with me for five years,
so there you go.
Yeah, you got four
on me there, mate.
You slept with
Sarah a year ago?
I thought you knew!
Peter, please,
don't take it seriously.
What the fuck, man! You've...
Don't get
offended by that.
You can't be so
casual about this!
This isn't Europe, okay?
There are rules here.
I'm really sorry.
I apologize for
offending you, Peter.
I just hope this
doesn't ruin our friendship.
Well, what's that about?
What do you think it's about?
This is a big deal!
What about a code of the ocean?
That's not on.
What about codes
among men?
You don't sleep with another
man's girlfriend!
-Think of...
-Get out of here!
-All right, okay! All right!
Oh, God!
PETER: Koonu!
This guy needs help! Koonu!
(SCREAMING)
Should I call
the front desk?
It hurts. It hurts.
Wow, you got coral
right there in your leg!
Can you get it out
of my leg, please, hotel man?
Can you do
something about that?
I'd love to,
you know, but hotel policy...
They don't let me do
that kind of thing.
They get all weirded out.
Insurance...
Koonu, can you call
the front desk for me, please?
-Yeah.
-It really hurts.
Koonu, call
the front desk now!
Okay, monster man.
Pete, he's not gonna
do nothing.
I kind of have this
thing about blood, okay?
Look at it.
It's raping my leg.
Peter, get it out of
my fucking leg, please!
One, two.
-You can't get it out.
-It's really in there.
Get it out of me!
Three!
Fuck my arse!
Okay, I got it.
It's all done. It's all over.
Everything looks fine.
It's all good!
They're coming wiki wiki.
Can you get some
towels for me, please?
I'm really
losing a lot of blood.
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT)
You sound like you're from London.
Yeah, I'm from London.
What's going on?
SARAH: You fainted.
I didn't want you to
wake up by yourself.
How's your friend?
Is he all right?
Yeah.
They gave him stitches,
and he's sleeping it off.
-Hey, you wanna hear something funny?
-What?
Are you ready to laugh?
'Cause this is a gas.
Okay.
Edward Scissorhands
over there told me
that you two were
fucking each other
for a whole God damn year
while we were together.
Shit.
How about that, Sarah?
I'm sorry, Peter.
Pete, you shouldn't be up
and walking around. Can you please...
Please don't touch me.
Just don't touch me,
okay?
I'm not touching you.
Will you just please sit?
Please?
All right, I'II sit down,
but I'm sitting down 'cause I want to,
not because you've
asked me to sit, okay?
Great.
A year?
Listen, I get it, okay?
I just...
I need to understand what I did
to make you cheat. I just...
Pete, it's not
anything you did.
You didn't do anything.
I mean, you were great.
Will you please cut the bullshit
and have a talk with me?
Fine. Cutting the bullshit.
It got really hard to
keep taking care of you
when you stopped
taking care of yourself.
I tried to get you
out of the house.
I tried to get you off your little island
you loved so much, the couch.
You didn't wanna
see the light of day!
God, there was one week
when you wore sweatpants! Every day.
You shall not pass!
You know what? If they were
Sean John sweatpants,
it would have been fine.
But because
they're Costco brand,
it's like the worst thing
I could do.
That has nothing
to do with it.
That's what you don't get.
I'm sorry that
I didn't end up being
who we thought I was
gonna be, you know?
I tried really hard.
I promise you that.
I just didn't have it in me.
I think if you had just,
maybe tried harder.
I tried!
You have no idea how
hard I tried, Peter.
I talked to a therapist.
I talked to my mother.
I read every book possible.
I took love seminars.
I took sex seminars.
None of it worked.
None of it made
a difference to you.
And I couldn't
drown with you anymore.
Don't you dare sit there
and tell me that I didn't try.
I did.
You were just too
stupid to notice.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Whoa. I thought you were gonna
wear the shirt I got you.
What? No.
I mean, I do love
that shirt you got me.
I admire Sir Tommy
Bahama an awful lot.
He's a talented man, but tonight, I feel
that this is appropriate.
Wow, thank you.
Yeah, Sarah got it for me.
This is, like, way more convenient
than my backpack.
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
Awesome hat!
Thank you.
Yeah,
my girlfriend got it for me!
I'm fucking with you!
Cool!
Sarah, can I borrow
this lipstick?
Sure. I don't care.
I think it looks great.
But if you're not, let's go change.
No, I like it.
I didn't like it at first.
Now I really think it's...
Oh, bloody hell.
This is a small resort.
SARAH: Hi, Peter.
Hey. Wow.
Aldous,
Sarah, this is Rachel.
Sarah bought me this shirt.
I could've guessed that.
Yeah.
-Looks great.
-You look great.
Looks awesome.
See.
Thanks.
Mr. Snow, I'm so sorry.
I did not know you
guys were coming.
You're gonna have
to wait five minutes.
I did not know you
guys were coming.
It's okay.
It's not a problem.
I didn't see you guys, so...
ALDOUS: There's
really no need to weep.
I'm not crying.
It's no problem, honestly.
It's not a problem.
-So, your table is ready, guys.
-Oh, great.
Hey, have a lovely evening,
you two.
-Thank you. Have a great dinner, you guys.
-Thank you.
You're welcome to join us,
obviously, if you want.
-Wouldn't dream of it. What?
-Okay.
What?
-Oh, okay.
-Okay.
-RACHEL: That's great. Awesome.
-Sure.
Great. I'll just
set two more places.
-Okay.
-Not a big deal.
Awesome.
So this is
actually happening.
We're gonna
let this happen.
I am so sorry.
I never thought in a million
years she would say yes.
I did.
What? I just
accepted an invitation.
I didn't wanna be rude.
It's got us in
a terrible situation.
Now I'm gonna have to sit with him
wearing this shirt all night.
You're wearing
the shirt regardless.
Australia is amazing.
-I'm telling you. It is a great place to shoot.
-Yeah?
Rachel, you would love it.
You would love it.
I wanna go. I really,
really wanna go there.
Wait, so when's
the movie coming out?
It came out.
-It was already released.
-Oh.
(SNICKERING)
Well, you know,
it's an island.
It's isolated.
-Yeah.
-Movies don't really come out here.
-Obviously.
-Did you like it?
-The movie?
-Yeah.
-It was...
-Awful bloody film.
I say, it's just
a ridiculous premise.
What would happen if your mobile
phone killed you?
Why would a mobile phone kill anyone?
Doesn't make sense.
How can a mobile phone have
an agenda and kill people...
I told her that when
she read the script.
Yeah. You were
the voice of reason, mate.
I tried to be,
but she didn't listen.
Going around
killing people.
A mobile phone,
like, doing murders.
Why couldn't you just take the
battery out of the phone?
ALDOUS: Right. That's it.
The battle's over.
Yeah, we've won.
ALDOUS: I hated it.
Well, it's not for everyone,
but it...
No, it's ridiculous.
Here's my favorite scene.
Ring-ring. Hello?
-ALDOUS: (LAUGHING) Right. It would never happen.
-Yeah.
No, it could never happen.
It's a metaphor for
addiction to technology.
For society, for how we're
reliant on technology.
I get it. I'm with you.
It's a metaphor
for a crap movie.
Well, it was the right choice
for me at the time.
-RACHEL: Sure.
-You know?
Well, this is awkward.
Yeah?
It's a bit more
awkward now.
RACHEL: A little.
PETER: Hey, excuse me.
Can we get another
bottle of wine, please?
-Sure.
-Thank you.
Mr. Snow?
Can I get cranberry juice
with a bit of lime in it, please.
Do you want cranberry juice
or cranberry cocktail?
Because I can probably
rustle up either one.
Throw some OJ...
I don't care.
Okay, great.
Hey, can we get
another bottle of wine?
If I've learned anything from
addiction, it's that,
you know, life is as brief as the
twinkling of a star over all too soon.
So if you're in a situation
where you're with a woman,
why not do
the most interesting thing
that you can do
in that situation?
And by which, I don't mean
have a conversation,
have a chin-wag,
a bit of a chat.
Lose yourself in something
that's both ancient and perennial.
Find something eternal,
perpetual.
Lose yourself in fuck.
I'm going to disagree.
Respectfully,
of course, sir.
Maybe for you, that works.
For me, it's much more enjoyable
to get to know somebody.
If you end up
sleeping with them, that's great.
But I like getting
to know somebody.
But he...
What he's saying is that
he's gonna stick it wherever he wants,
but he's joking.
I ain't.
No, I'm not joking.
It's just what I believe,
really.
So...
Just so we're clear
and so I can hone in
on your central
thesis of the night,
wade through
all the bullshit,
you're telling me
that you think you have the right
to just fuck anyone,
anywhere, anytime?
-Yes. There it is. That's right.
-That's what you're saying?
Not so eloquently
as you just put it, sweetheart.
But ultimately,
yes, that is...
Oh, no! Not the shirt!
Take my eyes,
but not the shirt.
Yeah, that's pretty much
what I believe, Sarah.
When you're done making jokes,
are you gonna get a napkin?
Do you know what? I think I've improved
it, actually, against all odds.
I think I deserve
a design award.
Please get some
seltzer water.
Garçon,
could we get some...
I saw it from farther away.
-Okay.
-Just lean back for a second.
No, it's all right.
It's not there. Let me...
You're very diligent.
I appreciate it.
Let go of the glass now.
You're gonna have to walk away.
Bless you.
There you are.
Oh, me, oh, my.
Call the doctor.
Oh, good.
(PETER MOANING)
I love Hawaii.
RACHEL: Is it good?
Yeah, it's nice,
but I think for like a week tops.
Any more than that,
I know I'd go crazy,
because I think that
Hawaii is a place to escape
for people who can't deal
with the real world.
Yeah, you know,
there's so few
personal shoppers
and pet therapists.
Gosh, it's such a hard life.
I like living here.
Anyone need any more vino?
I think we're good.
I've a question for
you real quick, Mr. S.
I was actually
meaning to ask you,
what did you
exactly think of my demo?
Did you get it?
Oh, no.
I was gonna listen to that,
but then I just
carried on living my life.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Are you sure that you're not,
like, too drunk?
Jesus, would you
stop being so sensitive.
(GIGGLING)
(RACHEL MOANS)
(RACHEL MOANING)
Aldous.
(SNORTS)
Wake up.
Aldous. Wake up.
Make love to me.
All right. You go on top, though,
'cause I'm knackered.
(MOANING)
(MOANING LOUDLY)
Listen.
Yes! Yes!
-SARAH: Yes!
-Yeah.
-Oh, yes!
-Yeah!
-Yeah! Oh, God!
(YELLING)
-Right there!
-Yes!
Yes!
Yes! She's having an orgasm!
This is the best sex ever!
Yeah, all right, that'll do.
What?
I made a mistake
coming here with you.
(MOANING CONTINUES)
And I'm not done either!
-Please shut up! Okay.
-Okay!
You're still involved with
him next door, ain't you?
Excuse me?
You should've seen yourself
at dinner, Sarah.
Then we come back here, and you
put on that ghastly performance.
I mean, I've heard that
women do fake orgasms,
but I've never seen one.
It really deeply upset me.
You should have seen
yourself at dinner.
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT)
"Oh, I'm Aldous Snow.
"Bullshit,
bullshit, bullshit, bullshit.
"No, no drinks
for me, thanks.
"Bullshit,
bullshit, bullshit."
And you know what?
Let me tell you something
about these tattoos, okay?
That is Buddhist.
That is Nordic.
That is Hindu.
That's just gibberish.
They are completely
conflicting ideologies.
And that does not make you
a citizen of the world.
It makes you full of shit.
Was that genuine
or did you fake that?
Right. I'm gonna
probably clear off now.
I'll have a little
sleep for a few hours,
then I'm gonna probably go
in the morning, okay?
I hate your music.
Yeah, well, I fucked the
housekeeper the other day.
(WHISPERING)
Are you sleeping?
Not anymore.
I know that I'm leaving in a couple
of days, so I don't even know
what the hell this means,
but I really like
spending time with you a lot.
I know. Me too.
Hey.
Good morning.
Where are you going?
The Korean Textile
Manufacturer's Luau.
Just kill me.
Fun.
Joy.
I want you to know that I meant
what I said last night.
I know you did.
I did, too.
Can I see you again tonight?
Yeah.
I get off at 7:00.
Yay.
Bye.
Sir, morning mai tai.
You know what?
I actually will not be having
an alcoholic beverage this morning.
(CHEERING)
-KIDS: Jump! Jump! Jump!
-Don't make me do it.
(WHISTLING)
Hey. Morning, mate.
-How are you today?
-Yeah, I'm good. I'm good. You okay?
Am I okay? I'm better
than okay, my friend.
You seem sprightly.
I…
I had a great
time last night.
-Congratulations. Well done. Well done.
-Thank you.
What about you?
What's with the bag?
Right, yeah. I'm off
back to England, mate.
Oh, you and Sarah
are going to England.
No, no, no.
I'm just going alone.
-Yeah.
-Did you guys have a fight or something?
Yeah, it was really...
How you served
five years under her, I don't know.
You deserve
a medal or a holiday
or at least
a cuddle from somebody.
You were only
here for a week.
Well, I don't know.
For me, that one week of it
was like going
on holiday with,
I don't know,
I wouldn't say Hitler,
but certainly Goebbels.
It was like a little
holiday with Hitler.
Jesus.
Hey, listen, at least it's clear now
for you two to reconnect.
Oh...
No, no. No.
You know what? I have a good thing
going on with Rachel,
and I want to
see that through.
Well, maybe you
could have both of them.
Rachel and Sarah.
They got on all right,
didn't they, at dinner?
So maybe...
You know what? First of all,
I'm not that kind of guy.
And even if I was,
I don't think that I have
the sexual competency
to really pull that off.
Yeah. It's a gift.
Okay. Well, I think
my ride's here.
So I'm gonna skedaddle then
before anything else happens to me.
Before life
gets any more daft.
Is someone gonna take that?
Listen, don't let
them grind you down.
Take it easy.
Hey, look at my driver.
I'm gonna have sex with her.
He said it was
clear I wasn't over you.
And then he left.
Fucking prick.
And then I started thinking,
what if he's right?
What if I'm not over you?
-Sarah...
-Please just let me finish, Pete.
What if I made a really,
really horrible mistake?
-Sarah.
-Yeah?
Stop pulling my
face towards your face.
Why?
You don't like it?
Listen, pulling my shirt
towards you
is the same concept
as pulling my face.
Let's spend one more
night here together,
and then let's go
home and then...
And we'll just pretend
like it never happened.
-That's the big plan?
-…face reality. No.
No. I love you.
That's not fair.
That's not fair of
you to say that to me.
Please, Peter.
Tell me you're sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I missed you.
I'm sorry.
God, I missed you, Peter.
All right.
Get hard for me, Pete.
Get hard for me.
I know what
I'm supposed to do.
Okay.
Just do it.
Come on. Get hard.
-I'm trying.
-Okay.
-Here. Just let me do it for a second.
I really want you, Peter.
I missed you.
You don't want help?
-You don't want help?
-Can you be quiet just for a minute?
Do you want my hands?
Maybe just don't talk for
a second is what I mean.
Do you want my mouth?
-Yeah, maybe your mouth.
-Yeah. Okay.
What's the problem, Peter?
I don't know...
More?
You can keep
trying if you want.
(SIGHS)
What's wrong with you?
-Nothing is wrong with me, okay?
-Okay.
-No, I didn't...
-Just, something doesn't feel right anymore.
Okay. Well,
did you... You know what?
Did you drink today?
Because sometimes
when you drink...
Excuse me.
No, I haven't had
anything to drink today.
Maybe the problem is that
you broke my heart into a million pieces,
and so my cock doesn't want
to be around you anymore, okay?
Ever!
Because you know
what I just realized?
Huh?
You're the God damn
devil. Okay?
Wedding in Hawaii!
Real original!
Hey.
Hey, Rachel.
Sarah and Aldous
broke up this morning.
What a surprise.
So I went to
check on Sarah, and...
Listen, I'm here because I don't want
to lie to you, okay?
Some stuff happened.
I'm really,
really sorry that it did,
but I'm also really
glad that it did, because
I'm able to see
so clearly now
that Sarah and I are
not right for each other.
What stuff?
I went up to make sure that she
was okay, and it got weird.
But now everything
is fine.
And I need you
to understand
that I meant everything that I said
to you this morning.
What exactly happened,
Peter?
We fooled
around a little bit.
Shut the fuck up,
and tell me exactly what you did.
All right.
I went to her room,
and she was crying
and crying and crying.
And I felt like
I should comfort her.
And then she started kissing me
because I was comforting her.
And then the next thing I
knew, I was kissing her
because she had been kissing me
because of the comforting.
Then she started
taking my clothes off,
and then her
clothes were off.
Then she performed 10 to 15
seconds of oral sex on me.
Okay. Peter,
you can leave now.
At the most. Maximum.
Thank you for
staying at Turtle Bay.
Rachel,
please don't do this.
The only reason I'm telling you this is
because I really care about...
Listen to me, Peter.
I was a mess, too.
I understand. Okay?
But it does not excuse
you acting like a complete asshole.
Listen, I know that
I fucked things up for a minute,
but I'm not like
every other asshole.
You should not be
with anybody right now.
Anybody.
I know...
I know that there
is something here.
I know that I was
not wrong about that.
And, yes, it's only been four days,
but I know you feel it, too.
I need you to leave.
Do not write me. Do not call me.
Do not e-mail me.
Peter, I need you to go.
I won't bother you
anymore.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what to do.
Hey, brother, what you doing, huh?
You stealing my art?
I want you to put
it back right now.
Put it back, bro!
Listen, give me the picture.
Doo-doo paper.
You're throwing
doo-doo paper?
Give me the picture.
Don't be stupid, brother.
Just give me the picture.
You can hit me as
many times as you want.
I'm not giving
you the photo back.
Oh, yeah.
No, no, no. Peter, I told you I
did not want to see you.
Aloha, I'm Sarah Marshall
from Crime Scene:
Scene of the Crime.
And when I'm not
scrubbing for evidence,
I'm flying Hawaiian Airlines
to my favorite destinations.
Now sit back and enjoy your
in-flight entertainment.
I know I will. Mahalo.
(PETER SINGING)
Everybody hates you
Everybody wishes
that you were dead
Because, Peter, you suck
Peter, you suck
Peter, your music
is fucking terrible
Peter, you suck
Peter, you don't
do anything of value
Peter, you suck
Write some music but instead
you sit and write these bullshit songs
It's so self-loathing
Go see a psychiatrist
I hate the psychiatrist
Well, go see one anyway
I don't like the psychiatrist
You need to go and see one
See a psychiatrist
I'm not going
It's getting kind
of hard to believe
things are
going to get better
I don't understand
what there is to think about.
Because, D, he...
She licked the tip.
That doesn't count.
Of course it counts. He...
He what?
He refused a blowjob from his
ex-girlfriend mid-blowjob.
Do you know what
that's like for a man?
It's called
blue balls, Rachel.
This guy is like Gandhi,
but better.
He likes puppets.
I love puppets.
I love Fraggle Rock.
I love Lamb Chop.
I love Elmo.
Sesame Street,
Bert and Ernie,
Snuffelupagus.
Fucks my shit up.
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) This is a song that
I never thought I would write
On the night I'm dying
Sorry for all
the wrong I've done
I'm finished trying
It was a wonderful dream
Now let him come and slay me
There he is
The demon who haunted
the streets of London
I've come to slay you
Here I am!
I'll leave you
bleeding in my dungeon
I'll never obey you
I'll rip out your esophagus
Please, Mr. Van Helsing
Listen to me
He is just a man
who wishes to be free
Lay him in a hearse
You must end this curse
He is the worst!
(EXCLAIMS)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Don't go my love
I can't say goodbye
My reign is done
It's time to die
I'm pregnant
Dracula
VAN HELSING: What have I done?
Has flown above
Who killed Dracula?
But he found a taste
A taste for love
My life is a lie
Sweet Dracula
I miss my young dead prince
I'll never see him again
Until my death
What a wonderful dream
To find a taste for love
A taste for love
(ALL APPLAUDING)
Wow. You came.
I can't believe
that you came.
Peter, this is great.
-It was really funny. Yeah.
-Thank you.
You know what?
I didn't realize that it was a comedy,
and then
someone told me that,
and it just, like,
opened the whole thing up.
How long
are you in town for?
Open-ended.
-Bold.
-Yeah.
Yeah, you know, I'm kind of
checking out some schools.
Congratulations.
Yeah, maybe.
You never called.
You told me not to.
And I listened.
Right.
Wasn't easy.
I might have
called once and hung up.
-No. No.
-From a private number.
No.
Maybe.
MAN 1: Peter!
MAN 2: Nice job, Bretter.
Well, you should
probably go back.
Would you like to hang out
while you're here?
Maybe we could
go to dinner or...
Yeah.
-Still have my number?
-Yeah. Yeah, I'll call you.
Go.
Yeah, I should do that.
Yeah, yeah. Go mingle.
-MAN 1: Hey, Peter!
-MAN 2: Hey, Bretter!
Come over here
and meet my mom!
Go, go.
Off I go.
-MAN 1: Hey, Peter.
-MAN 2: Nice job, Bretter.
The play was sick, man.
Good work.
Nice job.
Good job, man.
That was awesome.
So cool!
Peter, congratulations.
I just wanted
to say thank you.
I had such
a great time tonight.
Oh, good. You know what?
I'm gonna change out of this unitard,
-'cause I'm getting a chafe. Okay.
-Enough said.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Hey, Peter?
I was just calling you.
Wow.
Oh, Peter.
I'm sorry.
Stop laughing.
Can you please
stop laughing?
I missed you.
I just... You know,
I actually wanted to tell you
that I've been
thinking so much about...
NARRA TOR: This fall, Sarah Marshall is
back in a brand-new role.
Your wife had no enemies
that you're aware of.
NARRATOR: Get ready for the most
daring show on television.
Just came home,
and she was lying there.
Right.
NARRATOR: In a world where you
don't know who to trust.
(YELPS)
Charlie,
who's Franco Marconi?
No. No.
Gun, gun, gun, gun.
Drop it, drop it.
NARRATOR: Go with
your animal instincts.
(DOG HOWLING)
-How did you know?
-She's an animal psychic.
NARRATOR: Sarah Marshall
returns on Animal Instincts.
Life's a bitch.
And where you're going,
that's exactly what you'll be.