Inside a snowflake,
like the one on your sleeve,
there happened a story
you must see to believe.
Way up in the mountains,
in the high range of Pontoos,
lay the small town of Whoville,
the home of the Whos!
Ask any Who, and they'll have this to say,
"There is no place
like Whoville around Christmas Day."
Every window was flocked,
every lamppost was dressed,
and the Whoville Band marched
in their Christmas-y best.
Merry Christmas!
Arbor Day was fine,
and Easter was pleasant,
and every Saint Fizzin's Day
they ate a Fizz pheasant,
but every Who knew,
from their 12 toes to their snout,
they loved Christmas the most,
without a single Who doubt.
- Farfingle's welcomes you!
- Thank you.
Merry Christmas! Thank you
for shopping Farfingle's!
We got a snoozlephone
for your brother Drew,
and a snoozlephone for your brother Stu,
a muncle for your uncle, a fant for your aunt,
and a fandpa for your Cousin Leon.
So, we just need... Cindy?
Sale on aisle three!
- Cindy Lou! Cin... Oh.
- Merry Christmas!
Oh, hello, Myrna. Merry Christmas, Fred.
Excuse me one minute. Cindy Lou? Honey?
- Dad?
- Yeah?
Doesn't this seem like a bit much?
This is what Christmas is all about!
Can't you feel it?
Merry Christmas!
Thank you for shopping... Wait a second!
- Don't forget your change!
- Another minute closer to Christmas!
For the next five minutes only, 99 % off!
Yes, every Who
down in Whoville liked Christmas a lot,
but the Grinch, who lived
just north of Whoville,
did not.
Hi, girls.
All the good mistletoe's at the top.
Hey, Drew!
I'll race you!
Not if I race you first.
Last one to the top's a stinky old Grinch!
You guys, where are we?
- I think we should go back.
- What? You're scared of the Grinch!
- No!
- They say he lives up here in a big cave.
And he only comes down
when he's hungry for the taste of
- Who flesh!
- Oh, Drew!
- Guys!
- STU: You're scared of the Grinch!
You're scared of the Grinch!
Are too!
- Am not!
- Are too!
Wait for me!
Can we touch it? Touch the door?
Do it for me, Stu.
Drew?
Well done, Max!
Serves them right, those yuletide-loving
sickly-sweet, nog-sucking cheer mongers!
I really don't like 'em.
Mmm-mmm. No, I don't.
Max!
Get my cloak!
I've been much too tolerant
of these "Who-venile" delinquents
and their innocent, victimless pranks.
So, they wanna get to know me, do they?
They want to spend a little
quality time with the Grinch.
I guess I could use a little social interaction.
Merry Christmas!
Oh, yeah, you bet. Ho, ho, ho, and stuff.
Oh, my. Someone has
vandalized that vehicle.
You see, Max? The city is a dangerous place.
The Grinch hated Christmas,
the whole Christmas season.
Top of the day, flatfoot.
Now, please, don't ask why.
No one quite knows the reason.
Hey, kids. Here's a present for ya.
Be sure to run real fast with it, now.
Come on. Double time. Let's go. Move.
It could be that his head
wasn't screwed on just right,
or it could be, perhaps,
that his shoes were too tight.
But I think that the most likely reason of all...
- Merry Christmas!
- Idiot.
...may have been
that his heart was two sizes too small.
Hey, stranger,
won't let you go till you buy a chapeau!
The streets are filled
with Christmas cheer
Boy, nothing beats Christmas, right?
I guess.
- You guess?
- Well, it's just
I look around at you and Mom
and everyone getting all kerbobbled.
Doesn't this seem superfluous?
Dad! Dad!
- What happened to you?
- It was the Grinch!
- Grinch?
- What do you want? I mean...
Grinch? Oh, no!
Did someone just say, "Grinch"?
Hello, Mayor May Who, sir.
Lou?
I don't need to remind you
that this Christmas marks
the one thousandth Whobilation.
- Whoville's most important celebration!
- And The Book of Who says,
very clearly,
"Every size of Who we can measure
"knows that Whobilation is
a time we must treasure!"
Now, Lou, please tell me that your boys
were not up on Mount Crumpit
provoking the one creature
within a billion bilometers of here
- who hates Christmas!
- But it was the Grinch!
No, no, no, no, sir,
the boys didn't see any Grinch.
They just... I think they were
up on the mountain
playing with matches,
or defacing public property, or...
Oh, well.
That's a relief.
All right, you heard the man,
there's no Grinch problem here.
Lou,
I need it there by tomorrow.
Heckuvarush.
Merry Christmas, Mo. Next in line.
But, Dad. I just don't understand something.
Why won't anyone talk about the Grinch?
You kids and the Grinch!
You see, Cindy,
the Grinch is a Who who always...
Actually, not a Who, he's more of a...
- A what?
- Exactly, honey.
And he's a What who doesn't like Christmas.
Take a look at his mailbox, sweetie.
Not a single Christmas card, in or out, ever!
- But why?
- MAN 2: Lou, where's my mail? Lou!
- Got the wrong mail here.
- Lou! I got the wrong mail!
- I'll be right there.
- MAN 1: Lou, we got a problem!
All right, we'll straighten this out.
It'll take them years
to sort this out.
This is his and now
it's yours, and this hers and now it's his!
And for the rest of you...
Jury duty! Jury duty! Jury duty!
Blackmail. Pink slip.
Chain letter. Eviction notice.
Jury duty...
Would you mind helping me
take this to the back room, honey?
But be careful of the sorting machine, right?
Yeah.
Hmm.
Whew.
Gesundheit. Oh.
You're the...
The... The Grinch!
- Well, that worked out nicely.
- Help!
Help!
- Help me! Somebody!
- GRINCH: Max, let's go.
Our work here is finished. Sheesh!
Help me! Please help!
That is not a chew toy!
Stop it, Max! Get that out of your mouth!
You have no idea where it's been!
Help!
Bleeding hearts of the world, unite!
There!
There! Give me that!
Don't you know you're not supposed to take
things that don't belong to you?
What's the matter with you?
You some kind of wild animal?
- Let's go.
- Thanks for saving me!
Saving you?
Is that what you think I was doing?
Uh-huh.
Wrong-o.
I merely noticed that
you were improperly packaged, my dear.
Drat! Hold still!
Max, pick out a bow.
Can I use your finger for a second?
Hello! Hello!
- Cindy?
- Dad!
Daddy!
What the hey... Honey.
Cindy!
Dad! It was amazing!
You've been practicing
your Christmas wrapping!
- Honey, I am so proud of you.
- Oh, well...
Now, that's holiday.
Sweet little Cindy
didn't know what to do.
In her head bum-tumbled a conflict or two.
"If the Grinch was so bad,
then why did he save me?"
Maybe he wasn't so bad.
Come on, let's go home.
Maybe. Just maybe.
I've got the Christmas tree
I've got the melody
No lights on in the house.
Your mom must be shoppin'.
Oh, good, I'm so glad
you're home.
Oh, I can feel it, Lou. This is the year.
When everybody asks who has the most
spectacular lights in all of Greater Whoville,
they're gonna cry out, "Mrs. Betty Lou Who!"
Isn't this the chandelier
from the dining room?
It's all for the cause, dear.
- Oh, and Cindy?
- Oh. Yeah.
Could you be Mommy's Little Helper,
and unscrew the bulb there
from the refrigerator?
- 'Cause somehow I missed that one.
- Go on.
Every year Martha May Whovier
has the best lights.
Well, not this year. This year,
I'm gonna beat that prim,
perfect little prissy...
Betty!
- Hi!
- Martha!
My, I've never seen so many
beautiful Christmas lights, Betty Lou!
Well, I'd blow every fuse
if I tried to keep up with you, Martha May!
Isn't this antique darling? It's handcrafted.
And almost 100 years old.
Jeez. I'm really impressed!
This, however, is new.
Whoa up! Hey! Betty, Betty! Sweetie!
Well, good night, Betty.
Oh! I got it!
- Honey, honey.
- I've got it. I got it. I...
Hello?
Is my sub-zero chillibrator running?
- I suppose.
- Well, you better go catch it!
That's a good one!
That is rich.
Let's go home.
Fleas before beauty. Thank you.
Come on, hurry up. Slowpoke.
There's got to be a better way!
A car would have paid for itself by now!
Oh, goody. Another load coming down.
Ugh, what's that stench?
It's fantastic!
Max! Grab a bag.
We'll come back for the rest.
Of course, when I say "we," I mean "you."
It's amazing what these
Whos just throw away.
Oh, well. One man's toxic sludge
is another man's potpourri.
I don't know. It's some kind of soap.
Where are you, Christmas
Why can't I find you
Why have you gone away
My world is changing
I'm rearranging
Does that mean Christmas
Changes too
Where are you, Christmas
Do you remember
The girl you used to know
You and I
Were so carefree
Now, nothing's easy
Did Christmas change
Or just
Me
Sweet!
Be it ever so heinous
There's no place like home
First floor, factory rejects.
Those Whos are hard to frazzle, Max!
But, we did our worst.
And that's all that matters.
At least I scared the bejeebles out of that
little girl at the post office.
She'll be scarred for life, if we're lucky.
Funny she didn't rat on us, though.
Must be afraid of reprisals.
Yes! Down a size and a half!
And this time, I'll keep it off.
Get the stick, Max. Get the stick!
There's no stick!
I'm smarter.
Any calls?
You have no messages.
Odd. Better check the outgoing.
If you
utter so much as one syllable
I'll hunt you down and gut you like a fish!
If you'd like to fax me, press the star key.
Oh, well.
That's more like it.
Excellent year.
I'll tell you, Max,
I don't know why I ever leave this place.
I've got all the company I need right here.
Hello!
- How are you?
- I asked you first!
Oh, that's really mature,
saying exactly what I say!
...mature... Mature... Exactly what I say.
- I'm an idiot!
- You're an idiot!
All right, fine.
I'm not talking to you anymore.
In fact, I'm going to whisper,
so that by the time my voice
reverberates off the walls
and gets back to me,
I won't be able to hear it!
You're an idiot!
Am I just eating because I'm bored?
Oh, who could that be?
Hello, little girl.
Are you here to read to us?
No. I hear
you know some things about the Grinch.
Cindy Lou
had some questions in her curious heart.
Why did the Grinch hate Christmas?
Where did it all start?
With her dad's blabbacorder,
she wouldn't give an inch.
In your own words, please tell me
everything you know about the Grinch.
- Where did he come from?
- Oh, well.
He came the way all Who babies come.
On calm nights, baby Who girls
and tiny Who fellas
drift from the sky in their own pumbersellas.
Hey, honey!
Our baby's here!
He looks just like your boss.
Oh! So that's how it works.
It was Christmas Eve,
and a strange wind blew that night.
We were having
our annual holiday get-together.
It was morning before
anybody realized that he was out there!
The poor dear! But, you know what?
We knew right away that he was special.
Christmas time is here again
Oh. Do you want a Christmas cookie?
Yes, which Christmas cookie would you like?
Santa.
Oh! His first words!
Yes, that is a Santa plate.
Do you want to hold this Santa plate?
Santa, bye-bye!
Oh, he was a wonderful...
Whatever he was.
And we raised him like any other Who child
with a deep love of Christmas.
Don't forget,
tomorrow's our big Christmas gift exchange.
Everyone bring a special gift
for a special someone.
The... Grinch...
He had no sense of color coordination.
Although I hardly remember him.
I didn't have time to socialize.
I was far too busy with my studies.
Now, class,
is everyone almost finished?
And if the truth be told, he liked Martha.
Martha was my girlfriend.
I don't like discussing this Grinch
so very close to Christmas, but
maybe if you hear the truth,
you'll understand why...
Put your back into it!
I tried to take him under my wing.
You don't have a chance with her.
You're eight years old and you have a beard!
He had hair. Not pleasant.
He shed. Not right.
You know, Christmas is
my favorite time of year.
I just love the colors.
Red. And green.
Did I have a crush
on the Grinch?
Well, of course not.
- I didn't ask you that.
- Oh. Right.
For some reason,
when he came home that day,
he really got
into the Christmas spirit for the first time.
Baby, picture you and me
Perfect!
Hangin' 'round a Christmas tree
Whoopsy.
Colored lights
and an angel up above
Christmas of love
What a lovely family heirloom!
Gather everyone
And they're gonna come
Have a lot of fun
at Christmas time
Now it's on the way
Everybody say
We're gonna have
a Christmas of love
The fires of love!
Baby, make a little wish
This will be
perfect on the top of her tree.
Oh, Martha! Oh, Christmas!
Everything you been
dreaming of
- Christmas of love
- CHORUS: Love, love, love
I want you all to look your best tomorrow.
You don't have a chance with her.
You're eight years old and you have a beard!
Has everyone given their gifts?
- I haven't.
- ALL: What?
Merry Christmas, Martha May.
Why do you have a bag on your head?
Probably because
he's embarrassed by that hideoderous gift.
Mr. Grinch,
please take the bag off.
Yes, you take it off.
Put the book down.
And your foot.
Look at that hack job!
Stupid present!
Stupid tree!
I hate Christmas!
- The anger.
- The fury!
The muscles!
It was a horrible day,
when they were so cruel to him.
And...
I could hardly bear it.
I hate Christmas! I hate it!
And that was
the last time we ever saw him.
The very last time.
So, whatever the reason,
his heart or his shoes,
he stood outside his cave, hating the Whos.
Alphabetically.
Aadvarkian Abakenezer Who,
I hate you!
Aaron B. Benson Who, I hate you.
Hate, hate, hate. Hate, hate, hate.
Double hate.
Loathe entirely!
Nutcrackers?
It's their Whobilation.
He snarled with a sneer.
Tomorrow is Christmas! It's practically here.
Max!
Fetch me my sedative.
Now to take care of those pesky memories.
Whobilation, plentiful
With candy canes and pies
I can't wait to get there
To eat some google fries
Whobilation, Whobilation
- Dad?
- Yeah.
- I've been thinking about the Whobilation.
- Uh-huh.
And I may do something drastic.
That's fine, dear. Ask your mother.
- Where'd she go?
- BETTY: Honey!
Honey. Hi! Oh!
Look, I just found
the cutest light for my Christmas display.
Hurry up, we're gonna be late. Come on.
And now, the nominations
for that Who among us who best typifies
the qualities of Who-dom and Who-dery
the Whoville Holiday Cheermeister!
Do I hear a nomination?
I nominate the Grinch!
- The Grinch?
- MAN: The Grinch?
The Grinch?
My, my, my.
What an altruistic daughter
you have there, Lou!
Thank you.
Cindy?
Let me quote a verse
from The Book of Who.
Thank you.
Ah, "The term 'Grinchy' shall apply
"when Christmas spirit is in short supply."
Now, I ask you, does that sound
like our Holiday Cheermeister?
True, Mr. May Who.
But The Book of Who says this too,
"No matter how different a Who may appear,
"he will always be welcomed
with holiday cheer."
Whoa. Yes, well, the Book also says, the...
"The award cannot go to the Grinch, because
"sometimes things get the lead pipe cinch."
You made that up! It doesn't say that.
No, no, no, no, it does.
What page?
Uh...
Lost my...
My place, but it's...
- It's in here!
- But the Book does say
"The Cheermeister is the one
who deserves a back slap or a toast.
"And it goes to the soul
at Christmas who needs it most."
And I believe that soul is the Grinch.
And if you're the Whos I hope you are,
you will too.
She's right!
Fine. Fine.
You people want to waste
a perfectly good nomination,
why, it's up to you.
But I am telling you,
the Grinch will never come down.
And when he doesn't,
the Mayor will wear the crown.
Well, more or less.
Deck your heart with jollity
Style your smile
all Christmas-y
Flick some flocking
on the tree
Let there be Whobilation
Bake the fruitcake
Egg the nog
Feed the flaming Who-ltide log
Baste the beast
and gulp the grog
Let there be Whobilation
- Tick, tock, tick tock
- GRINCH: Tick, tock, tick, tock
Counting down
the Christmas clock
Old, young, big, small
Blast this Christmas music.
It's joyful and triumphant.
Must drown them out!
Not working!
The whipperwinds
whipped high above the Who town,
a trip or a slip, you'd slide all the way down.
But this girl had a mission.
She knew what to do.
She'd invite the Grinch herself,
that brave Cindy Lou.
Play, monkey! Play!
Ow-y!
Mr. Grinch?
Mr. Grinch!
Hello?
Excuse me.
Hello, little girl.
How dare you enter
the Grinch's lair?
The impudence! The audacity!
The unmitigated gall!
You called down the thunder, now, get ready
for the boom!
Gaze into the face of fear!
Mr. Grinch,
my name is Cindy Lou Who.
You see, even now the terror
is welling up inside you.
I'm not scared.
Denial is to be expected
in the face of pure evil.
I don't think so.
Doubt?
Another unmistakable sign
of the heebie-jeebies!
Now, you're doomed!
Run for your life,
before I kill again!
I'm a psycho!
Danger! Danger!
Um, maybe you need a timeout.
Kids today.
So desensitized by movies and television.
- What do you want?
- Mr. Grinch,
I came to invite you
to be Holiday Cheermeister.
"Holiday Whoobie-what-y?"
- Cheermeister.
- Huh?
"Cheermeister... Celebrate with friends."
That's a good one.
I know you hate Christmas,
- but what if it's all just a misunderstanding?
- Don't care.
I mean, I myself am having
some Yuletide doubts.
But maybe if you can reunite with the Whos
and be a part of Christmas...
- Grow up!
- Then maybe it'll be all right for me, too!
I'm sorry, your session is over.
Please make another appointment with
the receptionist on the way out.
Please, please. You have to accept the award.
Award?
You never mentioned an award.
Yeah, with a trophy and everything!
- And I won?
- You won!
- That means there were losers.
- I guess.
- So, if you come...
- A town full of losers!
I like it.
Was anyone emotionally shattered?
Come on, a minute ago
I couldn't shut you up!
Details, details!
Well, the Mayor wasn't happy.
Oh! No.
Martha May will be there.
- Oh, she will?
- Mmm-hmm.
And she'll see me. A winner.
She'll be on me like fleegle flies
on a flat-faced floogle horse.
Well, I'm sorry
to disappoint you, Martha baby.
But the "G" train has left the station.
So, will you come?
Oh, all right.
I don't know if it's that
adorable twinkle in your eye,
or that nonconformist streak
the reminds me of a younger, less hairy me.
But you've convinced me.
Who knows?
This Whobilation could change
my entire outlook on life!
- Really?
- No.
There you are. Honey.
You can make snow angels later.
We can't be late for the Whobilation!
The nerve of those Whos.
Inviting me down there.
On such short notice.
Even if I wanted to go,
my schedule wouldn't allow it!
"4:00, wallow in self-pity.
"4:30, stare into the abyss.
"5:00, solve world hunger,
"tell no one.
"5:30, Jazzercise.
"6:30, dinner with me."
I can't cancel that again.
"7:00, wrestle with my self-loathing"
I'm booked!
Of course, if I bumped the loathing to 9:00,
I could still be done in time
to lay in bed, stare at the ceiling,
and slip slowly into madness.
But what would I wear?
It's not a dress, it's a kilt!
Sicko!
Stupid. Ugly. Out of date!
This is ridiculous.
If I can't find something
nice to wear, I'm not going.
Oh.
Ah.
Mmm.
That's it, I'm not going.
Well, it's time for our
Holiday Cheermeister of the Year Award!
Congratulations, Mr. Grinch!
He isn't here.
What?
He didn't show? Oh.
Who could have predicted this?
All right. I'll swing by for a minute,
allow them to envy me, grab a handful
of popcorn shrimp, and blow out of there.
But what if it's a cruel prank?
What if it's a cash bar?
How dare they? All right, I'll go.
But I'll be fashionably late.
No. Yes. No. Yes. No!
Yes!
Definitely not!
All right. I've made my decision.
I'm going, and that's that.
Had my fingers crossed.
Maybe I should flip a coin!
Well, I guess the award goes
to the runner-up.
That's right.
A man for whom Christmas comes,
not once a year,
but every minute of every day!
A handsome, noble man,
a man who's had his tonsils removed twice!
That's an interesting story.
You see, what happened was...
Hello, Martha.
He made it!
- Cindy...
- Honey!
Boo.
Hot crowd. Hot crowd.
I believe I'm here to
accept an award of some kind?
And the child
mentioned a check?
- No, I didn't.
- All right, then, give me the award.
Come on, while I'm young!
Don't you worry, Mr. Holiday Cheermeister,
you'll get your award.
But first, a little family reunion.
They nursed you.
They clothed you. Here they are,
your Old Biddies!
Are you two still living?
- Oh.
- We missed you!
Rose. The sweater. The sweater, Rose.
Sweater? What are you talkin' about?
No, I can't!
I can't do this!
Don't touch me there!
Put him in the Chair of Cheer!
Chair of Cheer? What's the Chair of Cheer?
- You didn't tell me about the Chair of Cheer!
- Please, Mr. Grinch. Please?
No, no, no. I can't do it. Honestly.
I'm not ready. It's too much, too soon!
It's that time of year.
The Cheermeister's ride
in the Chair of Cheer!
Put me down! I mean it! I've got a lawyer.
There'll be hell to pay!
First, you'll put your taste buds to the test
- as you judge the Who-Pudding Cook-off!
- Who-Pudding Cook-off!
- Mine first.
- I really don't know.
No, mine's the best!
You'll enjoy this!
This is not pudding.
What is it?
This is mine.
Yummy, yummy, yummy.
Christmas Conga!
Gee, look at the time.
I really should be getting back.
All right!
Fruitcake... Fa la-la!
No.
Fudge Judge.
- Made it myself.
- Yeah?
- Mine are homemade too.
- Okay.
Put it in. Bring it on!
Is that all you got?
Is that all you got? Come on.
Outta the way, slow-mo!
He's number one in the sack race run!
Number one! I'm number one!
I'm number one!
No child can beat the Grinch!
Yeah!
I beat you!
And now it's time
for the moment we've all been waiting for.
Yes! My award.
- Write the check.
- There's no check.
Are you sure?
Because I really thought
I heard someone mention a check.
I said, there's no check.
And now it's time for Present Pass It On!
As always, we start with our Cheermeister.
A gift of a Christmas shave.
Look at that hack job!
Ah, yes, yes, yes. Good times!
Good times.
And now, I have a little something
for the love of my life.
Martha May,
please become Mrs. Augustus May Who.
Augustus.
If you agree to be my wife,
along with a lifetime supply of happiness,
you'll also receive this...
It's a new car!
Generously provided
by the taxpayers of Whoville!
What do you say, Martha?
Ya got 20 seconds on the clock.
Well, I...
These gifts are quite dazzling.
Of course they are.
That's what it's all about, isn't it?
That's what it's always been about!
Gifts! Gifts.
Gifts, gifts, gifts, gifts, gifts.
You wanna know what happens to your gifts?
They all come to me. In your garbage.
You see what I'm saying? In your garbage!
I could hang myself with all the bad Christmas
neckties I found at the dump!
And the avarice.
The avarice never ends!
"I want golf clubs."
"I want diamonds." "I want a pony
"so I can ride it twice,
get bored, and sell it to make glue!"
Look, I don't wanna make waves.
But this whole Christmas season
is stupid, stupid, stupid!
There is, however,
one teeny-tiny
Christmas tradition
I find
quite meaningful.
Mistletoe.
Now, pucker up and kiss it, Whoville!
Uh-oh! Somebody's fabulous!
All right, your turn! Go on! That way!
- Let's go!
- No!
Excuse me, old-timer.
Mind if I wet my whistle?
Well...
That's my good stuff!
Burn, baby! Burn!
Oh, wow.
Oh, the Whomanity!
- Let's go! Come on!
- No! Wait!
- Do something.
- Right!
Calling all units. Calling all units.
Taxi!
It's because I'm green, isn't it?
Halt!
Evening, folks. Mind if I ride along?
You might wanna scooch over.
You did the right thing.
Outta the way!
Hey!
That's gonna hurt in the morning.
It's gonna blow!
You fellas all right?
Hey, how about a nice hat?
Lou?
I'm hurt, Lou.
I'm hurt, and I don't hurt easily.
But you and your family...
I'm so...
So disappointed.
Can we just get back
to Christmas the way it should be?
Grinch-less?
Merry Christmas!
I just wanted everybody
to be together for Christmas.
I quite enjoyed that.
I hope I get another invite soon.
Come on, come on!
Good thing we have a spare.
Suffering snorkelblatz!
They're relentless!
Only four hours till Christmas!
Yes, the Grinch knew tomorrow
all the Who girls and boys
would wake bright and early
and rush for their toys.
And then, oh, the noise!
Oh, the noise, noise, noise, noise!
They'll bang on tong-tinglers.
They'll blow their floo-flounders.
They'll crash on jang-jinglers
and bounce on boing-bounders!
Then Whos young
and old would sit down to a feast,
and they'll feast and they'll feast.
And they'll feast, feast, feast, feast!
They'll eat their Who-pudding,
and rare Who roast beast!
But there's something I just
cannot stand in the least.
Oh, no.
I'm speaking in rhyme!
Blast you Whos!
And the more the Grinch thought
of what Christmas would bring,
the more the Grinch thought...
I must stop this whole thing.
Why, for year after year
I've put up with it now!
I must stop this Christmas from coming!
But how?
I mean, in what way?
Well, Christmas is
goin' to the dogs
We're scarfing down
the turkey and the grog
Are you having a holly, jolly
Christmas?
Wrong-o!
If you're not going to help me,
then you might as well...
Then he got an idea.
An awful idea.
The Grinch got a wonderful,
awful idea.
I know just what to do.
The Grinch laughed
in his throat.
And he made a quick
Santy Claus hat and a coat.
And he chuckled and clucked
at this great Grinchy trick.
With this coat and this hat,
I'll look just like St. Nick.
Ho-ho-ho!
You're a mean one, Mr. Grinch
You really are a heel
You're as cuddly as a cactus
and as charming as an eel
Mr. Grinch
You're a bad banana with a
Greasy black peel
Just face the music
You're a monster
Mr. Grinch
Yes, you are
Your heart's an empty hole
Your brain is full of spiders
You got garlic in your soul
Mr. Grinch
I wouldn't touch you with a
Thirty-nine
and a half-foot pole
I asked for three-quarters, not five-eighths.
Stay focused!
You know, if you asked
the Who's Who of Whoville...
No one would deny it
Air bag's a little slow.
But that's what these tests are for!
You're a vile one
Mr. Grinch
You have termites in your smile
You have
all the tender sweetness
Of a seasick crocodile
Mr. Grinch
Given the choice between you
I'd take the
Seasick crocodile
Fat boy should be finishing up anytime now.
Talk about a recluse.
He only comes out once a year,
and he never catches any flak for it!
Probably lives up there to avoid the taxes.
Merry Christmas!
Oopsie.
Forgot about the reindeer.
Did that stop the old Grinch?
No.
The Grinch simply said...
If I can't find a reindeer,
I'll make one instead.
Oh, Max!
So he called his dog Max,
then he took some red thread,
and tied a big horn on top of his head.
All right.
You're a reindeer. Here's your motivation.
Your name is Rudolph. You're a freak
with a red nose, and nobody likes you.
Then one day, Santa picks you
and you save Christmas.
No, forget that part. We'll improvise.
Just keep it kinda loosey-goosey.
You hate Christmas! You're gonna steal it!
Saving Christmas was a lousy ending.
Way too commercial.
Action!
Brilliant!
You reject your own nose
because it represents
the glitter of commercialism!
Why didn't I think of that?
Cut, print, check the gate. Moving on.
That feels good.
Here goes nothing, hot dog!
Wow.
This is nuts!
On Crasher! On Thrasher!
On Vomit and Blitzkrieg!
We're gonna die!
I'm going to throw up,
and then I'm gonna die!
Mommy, tell it to stop!
Ha!
Almost lost my cool there.
All their windows were dark.
Quiet snow filled the air.
All the Whos were all dreaming
sweet dreams without care,
when he came
to the first little house on the square.
Welcome to Whoville, Max.
Betty?
- Betty?
- What?
Did you hear something?
It's Santa!
Go right back to sleep.
Come on, Max. It's our first stop.
The old Grinchy Claus hissed,
and he climbed to the roof,
empty bags in his fist.
He'd slide down the chimney,
a rather tight pinch,
but if Santa could do it,
then so could the Grinch.
He's planning a double-twisting
interrupted forward-flying two-and-a-half,
with a combo tuck and pike.
High degree of difficulty.
He got stuck only once,
for a moment or two.
Blasted water weight! Goes right to my hips.
Then he stuck
his head out of the fireplace flue.
A little more stealth, please.
Where the little
Who stockings all hung in a row.
- These stockings...
- NARRATOR: He grinned.
...are the first thing to go.
Okay, fellas. Chow time.
Then he slunk to the icebox.
Slunk?
He eyed the Whos' feast.
He took the Who-pudding.
He took the roast beast.
Hike!
He cleaned out that icebox
as quick as a flash.
Why, that Grinch,
he even took their last can of Who-hash.
Then he stuffed all the food
up the chimney with glee.
- And now...
- NARRATOR: Grinned the Grinch.
...I'll stuff up the tree.
And the Grinch
grabbed the tree, and he started to shove,
when he heard a small sound
like the coo of a dove.
Excuse me.
The Grinch had been caught
by this tiny Who daughter,
who'd got out of bed for a cup of cold water.
Santa Claus?
What are you doing with our tree?
But, you know, that old Grinch
was so smart and so slick,
he thought up a lie,
and he thought it up quick.
Why, my sweet little tot.
The fake Santa Claus lied.
There's a light on this tree that won't light
on one side.
So I'm taking it home
to my workshop, my dear.
I'll fix it up there,
and I'll bring it back here.
Santa, what's Christmas really about?
Vengeance!
I mean,
presents,
I suppose.
I was afraid of that.
And his fib fooled the child.
Then he patted her head,
and he got her a drink,
and he sent her to bed.
- Santa?
- What?
Don't forget the Grinch.
I know he's mean and hairy and smelly.
His hands might be cold and clammy.
But I think he's actually kind of sweet.
Sweet?
You think he's sweet?
Merry Christmas, Santa.
And when Cindy Lou
went up with her cup...
Nice kid.
Bad judge of character.
...he went to the chimney
and stuffed the tree up.
And the last thing he took
was the log for their fire.
On their walls he left nothing
but some hooks and some wire.
And the one speck of food
that he'd left in the house,
was a crumb that was
even too small for a mouse.
Then he slithered and slunk,
with a smile most unpleasant,
around each Who home,
and he took every present.
Clearance sale. Everything must go.
What now?
Martha,
have you ever kissed a man
who lost his tonsils twice?
No, silly.
But it's an experience
that I've always longed for.
Kiss me, you fool.
What are you laughing at,
Rudolph?
It's all you, Maxie!
Three thousand feet
up, up the side of Mt. Crumpit,
he rode with his load to the tiptop to dump it.
Whoa!
We did it!
We did it! We did it!
That wasn't so bad, was it, Max?
They'll be waking up now.
And I know just what they'll do.
All those Whos,
down in Whoville,
will all cry...
Boo-hoo
What an embarrassment! I've been robbed!
Mayor May Who? Oh, dear.
Well, I wonder
who could've done this.
Tell you people one thing.
Invite the Grinch,
destroy Christmas.
Invite the Grinch, destroy Christmas!
But did anyone listen to me?
- I did.
- No!
You choose to listen to a little
not-to-be-taken-seriously girl,
who hasn't even grown into her nose yet.
Cindy, I hope
you're very proud of what you've done.
If she isn't, I am.
I'm glad he took our presents.
- What?
- I...
Well, I'm glad.
He's glad. You're glad.
You're glad everything is gone.
You're glad that the Grinch
virtually wrecked...
No, no, no, no, not wrecked,
pulverized Christmas.
Is that what I'm hearing from you, Lou?
You can't hurt Christmas, Mr. Mayor,
because it isn't about the gifts
or the contests or the fancy lights.
That's what Cindy's
been trying to tell everyone.
And me. She's been trying to tell me.
What is wrong with you? This is a child.
She's my child.
And she happens to be right, by the way.
I don't need anything more
for Christmas than this right here, my family.
- Merry Christmas, everybody!
- Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas,
you hunk of burnin' Who!
Oh, give me a break.
Merry Christmas!
Mr. Grinch?
Now for the final note in my symphony
of downright nasty not-niceness!
The crescendo of my odious opus!
Yes!
Oh, the wailing and the gnashing of teeth.
The bellowing of the bitterly bummed out!
It'll be like music to my ears!
Welcome, Christmas
come this way
Then the Grinch
heard a sound rising over the snow.
It started in low, then it started to grow.
But the sound wasn't sad.
Why, this sounded merry.
But it was merry. Very.
Every Who down in Whoville,
the tall and the small,
were singing without any presents at all.
He hadn't stopped Christmas
from coming. It came.
Somehow or other, it came just the same!
Mr. Grinch?
And the Grinch,
with his Grinch feet ice-cold in the snow,
stood puzzling and puzzling.
How could it be so?
It came without ribbons!
It came without tags!
It came without packages, boxes or bags!
And he puzzled and puzzled,
till his puzzler was sore.
Then the Grinch thought of something
he hadn't before.
Maybe Christmas...
He thought.
...doesn't come from a store.
Maybe Christmas,
perhaps,
means a little bit more.
Max!
Help me!
I'm
feeling!
And what happened then...
Well, in Whoville they say
that the Grinch's small heart,
grew three sizes that day.
What's happening to me?
I'm all
toasty inside.
And I'm leaking.
Oh, Max.
I love ya!
All right, that's enough. Knock it off. Beat it!
Get out of here! One step at a time.
Oh, no. The sleigh. The presents.
They'll be destroyed! And I care!
What is the deal?
Wait!
This can't happen.
It shouldn't! It couldn't!
It mustn't! It wouldn't!
Not now, not then, not ever again!
No!
Boo-hoo!
Oh, well.
It's just toys, right?
Hi, Mr. Grinch.
Cindy Lou!
What are you doing up there?
I came to see you.
No one should be alone on Christmas.
No!
I got ya, Cindy Lou!
You did it!
Spread eagle! Nailed it!
- Are you all right?
- Are you kidding?
The sun is bright and the powder's bitching!
Now scoot over! It's my turn to drive!
I'd better slow this puppy down!
We're gonna crash!
Now you listen to me, young lady!
Even if we're horribly mangled,
there'll be no sad faces on Christmas.
- What is it?
- CINDY: Help!
- Cindy!
- Grinch?
My baby!
Oh, Martha, grab an end.
By the way, these lights match
your outfit perfectly.
This could be a little more
difficult to negotiate.
Heads up, Whoville!
Hurry! Here he comes!
Outta the way! I have no insurance!
Yeah!
Run for your lives! Watch out, I can't stop!
- Daddy, move!
- Dad, move it!
Thanks for the help, Lou.
- Hi, Daddy!
- Hi, Cindy, honey.
Merry Christmas,
one and all!
Cindy!
Mommy!
Merry Christmas.
Cindy!
All right.
What do we have here?
You got me, Officer!
I did it!
I'm the Grinch that stole Christmas.
And I'm sorry.
Aren't you gonna cuff me?
Put me in a choke hold?
Blind me with pepper spray?
You heard him, Officer. He admitted it.
I'd go with the pepper spray.
Yes, I heard him, all right.
He said he was sorry.
Besides, it looks like
everything is all here and accounted for.
Help me out here, people. Martha?
Merry Christmas, Augustus May Who!
I'm afraid I do have something for you.
Your ring back.
Sorry, but my heart belongs to
someone else.
No hard feelings?
Cheer up, dude. It's Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Mr. Grinch.
Your cheek's so...
I know. Hairy?
- No.
- Greasy?
Stinky? Do I have a zit?
No.
Warm.
Fah who Foraze
Dah who Doraze
Welcome, Christmas Come this way
Fah who Foraze
Dah who Doraze
Welcome, Christmas,
Christmas Day
Welcome, welcome
Fah who Ramus
Dah who Damus
Christmas Day is in our grasp
So long as we have hands
to clasp
Fah who Ray Moo
Yah who Hee Haw
Welcome, Christmas
- Bring your Cheer
- Cheer
Fah who Foraze
Yah who Doraze
Welcome, all Whos Far
And
Near
So he brought back
the toys and the food for the feast.
And he, he himself,
the Grinch, carved the roast beast.
Yeah!
There's nothing
like the holidays.
- Who wants the gizzard?
- LOU: I do!
Too late! That'll be mine.
Where are you, Christmas
I think I've found you
This time I'll make you stay
All will be singing
Bells will be ringing
Now and forever
Christmas Day
Where are you, Christmas
Why can't I find you
Why have you gone away
Where is the laughter
You used to bring me
Why can't I hear music play
My world is changing
I'm rearranging
Does that mean Christmas
Changes too
Where are you, Christmas
Do you remember
The one you used to know
I'm not the same one
See what the time's done
Is that why you have
Let me go
Christmas is here
Everywhere
If you care
If there is love
In your heart and your mind
You will feel like Christmas
all the time
I feel you, Christmas
I know I've found you
You never fade away
The joy of Christmas
Stays here in silence
Fills each and every heart
With love
They're makin' noise
Noise, noise, noise
How I hate their happy noise
There's only one thing
I hate more
Come to think of it
And that's the people who keep
Makin' it
Feast, feast, feast, feast
They'll have more
than anyone could ever eat
Me, I'm stuck here with my
Cream of wheat
There's no one here
to feast with me
On this lonely Christmas Eve
Don't they know
I'm up here all alone
In my cave up in the hills
How I wish that
this would go away
This dreadful holiday
That they call Christmas Day
It's a lonely Christmas Eve
The streets are filled
with Christmas cheer
At least it's only once a year
Perfect parcels tied
with perfect bows
And carols ringing in my ear
Bundled up against the cold
Lines wherever gifts are sold
Each shop window
displays a Christmas scene
For everybody young and old
Icicles on eaves troughs
and tinsel on the tree
But it's a green Christmas
for me
Couples skating on the pond
Makin' angels on the lawn
Five red mittens
drying on the rack
And needle-shedding Tannenbaum
Red bows on the railings
and snowflakes on the ground
But it's a green Christmas
in this town
Green
'Cause of everything I miss
All this mistletoe
No kiss
And with every Christmas wish
There would be no greater gift
Than to have this envy lift
Carolers are at my door
Don't wanna hear them anymore
Stockings on the mantel
The snow's here every day
But it's a green Christmas anyway
Red nose on the reindeer
Tinsel on the tree
But it's a green Christmas
for me