Wish: To want something
that cannot or probably will not happen.
But what if it does?
I got a smile taking over my face
Feeling the sunshine
All over the place
If it's for real
You're gonna feel it in your soul
You're gonna feel it in your bones
Clapping my hands
When I walk down the street
Oh yeah.
If it's for real
You're gonna feel it in your soul
You're gonna feel it in your bones
Can you feel it, feel it?
Can you feel it now?
Ooh
It's all just something you feel
That's when you know it's for real
This is for real
This is it
This is for real, this is it
Paul! Paul!
A few words, Paul, Paul...
This is for real, this is it
Boom, boom, boom
Bang, bang, bang...
Oh! Ah!
Wait! Hey, wait, that's my scarf! Stop!
This is for real, this is it
This is for real
Hi, beautiful.
Mwah.
Hi, you. You look great.
Oh, thanks, thanks.
- Paul!
- Paul! Right over here.
- Two seconds.
- Okay.
Hi, how you doing? Good to see you again.
How are you? Thank you so much for coming.
- A few questions.
- Hang on a second. Hang on.
I'd be nowhere without this amazing woman
and brilliant writer in her own right,
my book editor, Madeline Kelly.
- Maddie, come here. Come here.
- Oh.
This is our night, Maddie.
You and me, we did this together.
You wrote a great story, Paul.
I just helped you polish it up.
Save me a moment inside, will you?
I have something I want to talk about.
- What is it?
- You'll see.
- Okay.
- Quick question.
- Hi, Jay.
So, was there a particular lady
in your life that inspired the love story?
Well, come on, you know,
I can't give away all of my secrets.
- Always good to be back.
- Yeah? Another bestseller?
Hello?
- Oh, Maddie.
- Hi, Mom.
Glad I caught you.
What's that clicking noise?
I'm trying to order toilet paper online.
The students keep stealing it,
and the button on my keyboard
keeps getting stuck.
Too much detail, Mom.
Well, you asked.
It's a little hectic here.
I got stuck in traffic, and I just
literally got to the venue.
You're gonna be late for your big night.
It's bad time management.
I wish I could've been there to help you.
- Okay, Mom, can you hang on a second?
- Of course.
Yeah, just one second.
Okay, go ahead.
I was calling
to see if you've had that talk with Paul.
Not yet. I hope you haven't told anyone
about my feelings for him.
Trust me.
No one in Des Moines cares.
Well, Heather and Emma don't even know.
You didn't tell them?
I'm just... I'm not ready.
If your friends don't know,
it's entirely possible
that Paul doesn't either.
No, I've given him plenty of signs.
You should see the way he looks at me
when we work together.
- Mom, he gets me.
- Well, you're in love with him.
- Why don't you just tell him?
- I may not have to.
Oh. What's happened?
He says he has to talk to me
about something.
- Really?
- So tonight may be the night.
Ah! It works.
Okay, Mom, I have to go.
All right. If he doesn't tell you
how he feels about you tonight,
you gotta speak up. That's all I'll say.
- Okay, love you. Bye.
- Love you too.
- Hey, girls!
- Hi!
This is so exciting.
We are so proud of you.
- Thank you for coming.
- Oh, where's the scarf I gave you to wear?
- Somewhere in Brooklyn by now.
- How'd that happen?
Freak accident. I totally get if you
never wanna loan me anything again.
Don't worry about it, Mads.
That scarf was a sample from work.
Heather, great job on the cover art.
You like it?
It's stunning. What do you think, Emma?
- I think you've been holding out on us.
- On what? Paul?
Yeah, you've been working
with him for over a year.
Don't tell me you haven't noticed.
I think he's an amazing writer.
That's all.
You should have
your name on the cover with him.
- You practically wrote the book.
- No, I didn't.
I mean, not exactly.
Besides, it's good for my career.
Paul's talking me up to the publisher.
- He's Irish.
- Yes.
- Does he have a sexy accent?
- Haven't noticed.
- Is he single?
- Give me that.
- Okay.
- Where are you going?
To find Paul.
And in your eyes
True love resides
Forever is a word that tries...
Come on, Maddie. Don't wimp out now.
Here you are.
Thought I'd use a little liquid courage
before going in to face the masses.
They're gonna love it.
It's a beautiful story.
Well, I have you to thank for that.
If I had my way,
the lovers would have tossed themselves
into the lake by chapter ten.
You're amazing. You know that?
You balance me out, Madeline.
We do make a great team.
We do, which is why
I wanted to talk to you
about something really important to me.
- You know you can tell me anything.
- Well...
I feel like it's time
we take our relationship
to the next level.
Oh, Paul, I don't know what to say.
I feel exactly the same way.
Really?
That's wonderful.
So,
will you work with me on my next book?
I want to bring you in
from the conception of the story.
I know you wanted to write your own novel.
I can help you with that.
But do you think it could wait
just... a little longer?
Oh, I, uh...
- Sure.
- Great!
- Sounds great.
- Wonderful!
- Yeah.
- Well...
Right, time to feed me to the wolves.
See you in there.
Well, if you stop moving, I can grab it.
Just get me to the bathroom.
Oh, I'm so sorry. Are you all right?
We're just having
a minor eyelash malfunction.
May I offer my assistance?
Oh, uh, yeah. Maybe.
They're the new NanoGrip lashes.
I'm a stylist at Bergdorf's.
I get the latest samples
of all their luxury cosmetics.
This one gets a thumbs-down.
- Do you mind if I give it a go?
- Sure.
I'll be very, very careful.
There.
How's that?
Much better.
Um, hey.
Hate to break this up, but you have
a lot of people waiting for you.
- Okay, well, after you.
- Oh no, after you.
Ugh.
"She peers up from the watery depths."
"If only he would reach out for her,
it could break the spell."
"But instead, he turns his back."
"She calls out with drowned words
as he disappears
into the shadows of the mossy glen."
"Chapter eight."
"The first night
she spent alone was the worst."
TWO IRISH HEARTS
PAUL KENNEDY
There you go, Gertrude.
That's a beautiful name, by the way.
Thank you, Paul.
- So, how did you three meet?
- Oh, we're friends from school.
I was always a big reader.
What?
That was me.
- Would you like me to sign your book?
- Oh, uh, yes, I would.
Of course.
- Here we go.
- Is that a real lake?
Yes. It's in Ireland.
It's not far from my family's home.
Hmm, well, I'd love to see it sometime.
And I would love
for you to see it sometime.
You write such amazing stories.
I could listen to them all night.
Wow.
Wouldn't that be great?
Unfortunately,
Paul has press in the morning, so...
Check, please.
- It's an open bar.
- No, it's not.
It was amazing.
Yes.
This might have been
the most incredible night of my life.
You and Paul seemed to hit it off.
I know, it's like we had
this immediate connection.
Well, you can't take it too seriously.
Paul's a famous person.
- He's used to making people feel special.
- Well, he signed my book.
He signs a lot of books.
With his phone number?
It's just a phone number.
It's not like it's a proposal.
I can't believe Paul and Emma
are getting married.
It all happened so fast.
Like whiplash.
Welcome to Ireland.
- Thank you.
Nearly there. You've got one more bag.
Oh Paul, that one's mine too.
- There you go.
- Did you bring enough luggage, Em?
I'm getting married.
You won't believe the number
of wardrobe changes I'm gonna need.
Oh.
Excuse me. Ma'am.
- Mads.
- Excuse me.
- Are you okay?
- Sure.
Maddie, have you got your bag?
Almost.
- We'll meet you out front, okay?
- Okay.
If you need me on that job,
I'm available at a moment's notice. Okay?
Good. All right. Yeah, of course. Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
- Oh.
- Oh, sorry. This is mine.
Uh, no, I'm afraid it's mine.
- No, actually it's mine.
- Hang on a minute.
There's an American woman
trying to steal my bag.
I'm not. I'm trying to take my bag.
If you just look at the tag, you'll see.
I don't need to. I know my own bag.
So let go.
I'm not letting go of my bag.
Oh!
See? Look, my favorite plaid skirt.
Are you sure those are your size?
I'm so sorry.
It's quite all right.
It could have happened to anyone.
Although I suspect
it happens to you more often than most.
- Enjoy your visit.
- Hmm.
LOST LUGGAGE
Ah, Maddie. There you are.
We finally managed to get
all of Emma's bags into the car.
I may have to ride on the roof.
- Can't believe this is actually happening.
- I know. How are you feeling?
No cold feet, right?
Me? Never.
I can't thank you enough
for introducing me to Emma.
You've changed my life,
and I'll never forget it.
Can you please fill this out?
Looks like this is gonna take a while.
- Why don't you guys head to the house?
- No. I can't leave you here.
- Don't worry about me. I'll take a taxi.
- Okay.
Call me, let me know everything's okay.
Good.
"No Ubers in the area." Great.
Can you go to this address?
Oh, yeah. I can take you there, love.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Whoa, whoa! Wait, wait, wait!
Billy. Oh, good to see you again.
Ah.
Couldn't convince anyone else
to give you their bag?
As a matter of fact, my bag is missing,
but they'll call me when they find it.
Well, if you're in need of boxer shorts,
you know who to ask.
So, you're a photographer?
I am.
A nature photographer.
Well, at least I'm trying to be.
It's a little trickier now the whole world
carries a camera in their pocket.
Never thought about that.
- What brings you to Ireland?
- A wedding.
- Oh, congratulations.
- Oh, no. It's... it's not mine.
It's my friend's.
Maybe you'll be lucky
to catch the bouquet.
What makes you think
I wanna get married?
Nothing. It was a joke.
Apparently, a bad one.
Oh!
TWO IRISH HEARTS
Oh.
Huh.
- Thanks.
- All right.
You enjoying that?
Yes. Have you read it?
Nope. Don't need to.
I barely made it through his last one.
Paul Kennedy's one
of the best-selling authors in the UK.
They sell a lot of fish and chips too.
Doesn't mean they're any good.
Well, he seems to be doing
very well without your approval.
Not a friend of yours, is he?
Your stop coming up, Miss.
Kennedy House.
Ah.
As in Paul?
Well, that answers that question.
- Thank you.
- No bother, love.
Oh, and, FYI, I edited this book.
So, what do you have to say to that?
My deepest sympathies.
You know what? You can just go...
Hey, you.
- You're trespassing, you know.
- Uh, I'm sorry.
I'm-I'm looking for Paul Kennedy.
I know who you are.
Just having a bit of fun.
I'm Kory, the brother.
- Hi.
- Come on, everyone's inside.
Oh, Maddie! You made it!
Yeah, I took the bus, which was fine,
except for the cheeky English guy
I had to ride with.
Olivia, this china is divine.
You have an excellent eye. It's Belleek.
- Oh.
- It's been in the family for generations.
Just this way.
Oh wow.
This place looks like a fairy tale.
Except around here,
if you lose your shoe at midnight,
you're just drunk.
He's so cute.
- Wow, really?
- I've got Maddie here. Fresh off the bus.
- Hey, Maddie.
- Good.
- Sean. Paul's dad.
- Hi.
Oh, no!
Um, I'm so sorry.
Quite all right.
- No damage done.
- Yes, sir.
Have they found your luggage?
- No, not yet.
- Come join us.
Oh, Mads, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
It was insured.
It's not the bag we're worried about.
It's the bridesmaid's dress.
Without it, you'll imbalance
the look of the wedding party.
Maybe she could stand-off to one side.
You know, like a cheering section.
Right! The car is loaded up.
Ah.
Madeline. Everybody about ready to go?
- Oh yeah.
- Where are we going?
Paul's planned a surprise trip for us all.
Isn't he sweet?
Mwah.
- Just give me a sec to get changed.
- Mm-hmm.
Such a lovely young woman.
She's adorable.
Madeline, you must be
so thrilled for them both.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
SCRUFFY MURPHY'S PUB & INN
You all right? Good.
Afternoon. How are we, chaps?
That looks good.
Ah.
There's the world traveler.
Good to see you, Murphy.
Doing well? How's it going?
Oh, fine, fine. So, are you around
for a week this time?
I am. Yeah, I'm covering
the sheep-shearing festival.
Oh, there's great excitement
around here for that one.
I'm sure.
Now Fionnuala is getting your room ready,
and you can use
my old Triumph while you're here.
No, no, no, no. I can't take your car.
Look, you can trade me
with one of your fancy photographs.
And I'll hang it up in the pub.
All right, deal.
You're still liking it?
All this gallivanting around the world?
Snapping pictures
of lizards and birds, huh?
I am.
If you don't stay put,
how are you going to find
a nice woman to settle down with you?
I'm not sure I'm cut out
for settling down with anyone.
What am I telling you for?
You've never listened to me anyway.
- Good to see you, man.
- All right.
Beautiful.
Hey! You need anything?
I can lend you some clothes.
- No, I'm good. I had a sweater in my bag.
- Okay.
- Gorgeous view.
- Yep.
Is everything okay with you?
You seem a little off.
Yeah. No, uh, I'm good. I'm great.
Why don't we have a girls' night?
We can go out, get a couple drinks,
meet some guys.
You haven't dated in almost a year
since you started writing that book.
- Just say yes. Come on, come on!
- Yes.
Thank you. I'll see you downstairs in 15.
- Happy couple taking us on a picnic.
- Ugh.
Thank you.
- I'll take the basket.
- Lovely. I'll take the heavy thing.
Right, follow me. Let's have a picnic.
It's so pretty here.
This bridge was used by the Vikings.
This must be where
you get all your creative inspiration.
Look, it's Lough Tay.
- It's the lake from Paul's book.
- Ah.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Is this where your mystical fairy lives,
in a sunken city
at the bottom of the lake?
- Yeah, exactly. You're so perceptive.
- Except she's not mystical.
She's wicked and selfish,
and she lures men to their watery deaths.
- Maddie!
- No, that's right.
Evil fairy.
Anyone fancy a boat trip?
- Oh!
- I do.
Nevin put some boats aside for us.
- Maddie, come on, we can squeeze you in.
- Oh, it's okay.
There's plenty of room. It'll be fun.
- I'm just gonna go for a walk.
- Really? Okay.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
- Could we get a picture?
- Oh, okay.
- Cheese!
- Woo-hoo!
How about one of Paul and I?
Here, use my phone.
That way, I can post on my stories later.
Okay. Uh, one, two, three.
- Think the water's warm?
- Here you go.
Thank you, Mads.
- I am so excited by this.
- All right, have fun.
- See you later.
- Enjoy your walk.
- And we're off.
- Oh, it's lovely.
I'm counting on you.
Bye, guys.
- See you, Maddie!
- Bye!
We're off.
- Hi, Mom.
- You promised you'd call when you landed.
Sorry. I am safe and sound.
Actually, Paul took us to Lough Tay.
It's really magical in person.
Is there something in your voice?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm okay, but...
I can't help but think
that things would be different
if I'd just taken your advice
and told Paul how I felt.
Sweetheart,
think of this as a lesson learned.
You're gonna have
to start speaking up for yourself.
Stop that.
Yeah, well,
it's too late now.
It's not like I can tell Paul
I wish he was marrying me instead of Emma.
Maddie?
- Mom?
- Maddie? Maddie?
Mom, it's... it's reconnecting.
Mom?
Oh! Whoa!
Was that a wish you were making?
Oh, no, I was just, um...
I mean, I guess,
but I didn't think anyone was listening.
Well, I was.
Look down.
Okay.
They call that a wishing chair,
but you have to do it right.
So, sit down,
close your eyes and make your wish.
Oh, no, I'm good.
What are you afraid of?
I'm not afraid. I just...
I don't believe in that kind of thing.
Well, then you have nothing to lose.
Oh, come on. Why not give it a go?
Okay, I wish...
No, you have to do it right. Sit down.
Close your eyes and mean it.
Okay, I wish...
I wish I was marrying Paul Kennedy.
Oh.
Well, that didn't work.
Didn't it? And how can you tell?
Isn't there supposed to be an earthquake
or a lightning bolt or something?
So you want something more theatrical?
Let me see if I can muster up
a stiff breeze. Would that help?
That would be nice.
Whoa!
Oh!
That was a weird dream.
Hello?
Heather?
Emma?
Are you in there?
Paul!
Ah, Maddie, you're up.
Can you hand me a towel?
Uh, sure.
Yeah. Okay. Um...
Um, Paul, what are you doing in here?
Taking a shower. What does it look like?
Have you seen my beard balm?
No!
Ow! Oh!
What's wrong with you?
Nothing, I just, um...
I didn't know you were in here.
- Where else would I be?
- Right. Okay.
Oh! Uh, I'm-I'm gonna go. Right. So sorry.
Whoa! Oh!
Maddie! Are you all right?
- They found my suitcase.
- Come here.
Huh!
You know what? I'm gonna go outside.
I'll just... Yeah, I'm gonna get some air.
- Oh, morning, Mads.
- Hi, Emma.
Emma! You're up early.
I'll get a run in before breakfast.
Have you seen Paul?
- Paul?
- I've been looking for him everywhere.
You know, you can get lost in this house.
Yeah, well, uh,
he is definitely not in there. At all.
- Right.
- You know what?
As a matter of fact, I haven't seen
an inch of him anywhere.
What? How did he get in there?
- Morning, Emma.
- Morning.
- Your mother's looking for you downstairs.
- Oh. Great, thanks.
- I'll see you at breakfast?
- Whoa. Paul.
What? It's not like
she's never seen us kiss before.
Nevin, my jacket.
So, uh, getting ready
for the big day, huh?
You must be getting excited.
I'm looking forward to the reception.
There are some seriously hot men
in this town.
See?
Oh.
- Oh. Hey, are you...
- I need to talk to you.
What in the world, Mads? What is wrong?
I'm gonna tell you something,
but you cannot breathe
a word of this to Emma.
Oh. All right.
Last night, I had the craziest dream.
We were by the lake,
and this odd lady told me to make a wish.
And I wished
that I was marrying Paul Kennedy.
- I know that probably shocks you.
- Should it?
Well, anyway,
when I woke up from the dream,
my suitcase magically appeared,
and Paul was taking a shower. In there!
Okay.
Isn't that a bit weird to you?
Uh...
And there's a wedding dress
in my suitcase!
Uh, yeah.
- Why is it in there?
- Because it's yours, silly.
You and your mom
picked it out in New York.
What?
Yeah, and in a couple of days,
you're gonna put it on,
walk down the aisle, and get married!
No, I'm not!
Yes, you are.
I think you're having
a little pre-wedding anxiety.
- Perfectly normal.
- I mean, what are these?
These aren't mine.
Girl, sexy heels for your honeymoon.
No. I am not the one
who's getting married.
She is!
Exactly.
You, my friend, are marrying Paul Kennedy.
Now, just breathe. Relax.
This is gonna be
the best weekend of your life.
Get dressed.
I'm marrying Paul Kennedy.
Yes!
I'm marrying Paul Kennedy!
Ah!
Whoo! Yes!
- Okay, so...
- Well, I just don't understand it.
Why can I not find
a photographer for this wedding?
Because you're horrible, Mum.
The last two photographers
you hired for our parties left in tears.
- Did they really?
- Yes.
They did. They were crying and everything.
Oh, there she is.
- Good morning, everyone.
- Good morning.
I'm digging this groove.
Uh, darling?
Oh.
Allow me.
Thank you.
- Are you feeling all right, Madeline?
- Yes. Just a little jet-lagged.
Have some champagne. It's working for me.
Thank you.
Try these local woodland strawberries.
They're delicious.
Let me give you one. Very good.
- None for me, thank you.
- Madeline might want one.
Madeline, would you like a boxty?
A what?
Oh, she's so adorable.
Um, it's an Irish pancake.
Oh, okay, thank you.
Sean, I meant to tell you.
The bakery called.
The wedding cake we ordered
is too tall for the delivery truck.
- Oh, no.
- Could you get a smaller cake?
Very good.
- I like your thinking.
- Well done, dear.
Finally, someone with some sense.
Well, the weather seems to be holding up.
You fancy a bike ride this morning?
- Oh, with me?
- Mm-hmm.
Of course with me.
Emma and I are going down
to the orchard to pick some apples.
- Kory, do you want to come with us?
- I can't. I've got rugby practice.
Paul, can we go pick apples?
I'm not really
that coordinated on a bicycle.
Don't be silly.
Everyone knows how to ride a bike.
Sweetheart, can you
pick up the pace a little?
Paul, I'm trying.
These are so luscious.
- Maddie, you still back there?
- I'm coming.
- Oh, hey.
- Hi, ladies.
Hey, Maddie.
Whoa! Whoa!
Ah!
Oh!
- Maddie, are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm-I'm fine.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm okay. I'll just hop back on.
I don't know, you kind of look like
a liability on that thing.
Oh, no, I'll just push it
and trot along next to you.
Well, I was kind of hoping
to get some cardio in, babe.
- It's okay. I'll take it from you, Maddie.
- No.
Could use a bike ride.
I'm low on my steps.
- All right then!
- Alright.
- Quick little trip around the village?
- Only if you can keep up with me.
- Whoo!
- Them fighting words.
Yeah, left you in my dust!
I'm gonna get you.
So, want to pick some apples?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay.
I literally cannot believe
we got so many apples.
How about we make an apple pie for Kory?
Maybe he likes a girl that can bake.
There you are.
I've been looking for you everywhere.
Madeline, do you realize what time it is?
We have an appointment at the tailor's
for the fitting of your wedding dress.
Oh, but don't I already have a dress?
My mom and I picked it out together.
Oh, speaking of your mother.
Nevin will collect her from the airport
and bring her to the rehearsal.
- My mother's coming?
- Better late than never.
Yeah, I agree with you.
I don't see a problem
with guys using Botox.
Right? I mean, I don't need it now,
but maybe in the future.
Oh hey, Em.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Paul, darling, I thought you told Madeline
about the wedding dress.
I did.
- Right, honey?
- No.
Well, anyway, come on.
- Well, she's no fun.
- My mom can handle her.
It fits her like a dream.
Spectacular.
Magnificent.
- Wow.
My grandmother
wore that gown on her wedding day.
So did my mother. So did I.
It's a tradition in our family, Madeline.
It's really... fun.
"Fun"?
It's vintage Lanvin.
It is a fashion artifact.
It is the sphinx of wedding gowns.
Maybe you could add a slit?
Hmm.
Brilliant. They have it.
REWILDING
- Fantastic.
- It is lovely.
THE NEW BESTSELLER
FROM PAUL KENNEDY
- Hello.
- Let me get you this.
- Thank you.
Oh! Congratulations.
You are our 100th customer of the week.
Oh. Wow.
Which means you win
a promotional copy
of Paul Kennedy's new novel.
Uh...
- That's okay. It's fine, thanks.
- But it's free.
Even so.
There you go.
Oh.
- Little gift.
- Of course.
- One of this.
- Lovely.
Oh, and the payment. There you go.
Perfect.
- Have a good day.
- You too. Bye.
SHEEP SHEARING
FESTIVAL
CANCELLED
Oh!
- After you.
- Thank you.
WEST COAST RARE BOOKS
Oh, come on. You've got to be joking.
I was looking forward to that gig.
- It's really not that bad.
- Yes, it is. What are you talking about?
- What are you gonna do about this, Maddie?
- Well, I'm just gonna wear the dress.
Because it's only a dress
and because Paul wants me to.
And because you wished it.
Did you just hear that?
There she is.
That's her!
She's right there. There she is!
Oh...
Who? Maddie!
Hey, wait, come back!
What does that mean?
I'm happy with my wish.
Are you really happy with your wish?
Where are you going?
I love my wish.
Come back! Please don't take it away!
Whoa!
Hello.
- It's you.
- You all right?
- You didn't see me crossing the street?
- Well, yes, but you ran into me, so...
- Well...
- There you go.
It's okay. I got it.
- Here.
- Oh. Well done.
Hey.
You told me you didn't like Paul's books.
- Sorry, what?
- When we were on the bus.
I don't mean to be rude,
but do I know you?
You don't remember?
- Oh, that's because it didn't happen.
- What didn't happen?
- Nothing.
- Maddie!
- What was that about? You just ran off.
- I, um, I saw...
You found one. A photographer.
Wonderful. Well done, Madeline.
No, I...
Olivia Kennedy. And you are?
James. James Thomas. Lovely to meet you.
I don't suppose you're any relation
to Paul Kennedy, the author?
That's my son.
- Ah.
- This is his bride-to-be.
- Of course you already knew that.
- I didn't, actually.
The thing is,
James is not that kind of photographer.
How do you know that?
- You're a photographer?
- I am.
What would you charge?
I appreciate the offer,
but I don't think I'm the man for the job.
What do you mean?
I don't really photograph people.
Whatever your fee is, I will triple it.
When did you say the wedding was?
You see how there's this beautiful glow
around the bride and groom.
- It's lovely.
- That's what I'm looking for.
Something ethereal.
And then any photographs of me
should be taken from the right.
That is my better side.
All right.
Whose car is in the middle of the drive?
Hey.
Oh, good, darling. You're just in time.
Madeline found
a wedding photographer for us.
Oh!
James Thomas, this is Paul, my fiancé.
- I've read some of your work.
- Oh.
- It's always nice to meet a fan.
- Yes, I'm sure it is.
You know, my publicist said
that we should get
some PR pictures after the wedding
of Madeline and I
in some idyllic Irish backdrops.
He thinks it'll help
boost my sales figures.
So not just a wedding
but a good PR event too.
Yeah, exactly.
Especially since
Maddie is Paul's book editor.
Why don't the three of you spend tomorrow
driving around the area?
- You might find some great spots.
- That sounds wonderful.
- What do you think, Paul?
- It's a great idea.
- 10:00 a.m., James?
- Sure.
Madeline, would you mind
showing James out?
Sure.
So you're not just his fiancée
but his editor too.
How convenient.
If you're gonna spend the day with us,
can you leave your snark at home?
Since I don't technically have a home,
I don't know where that would be.
I'll do my best.
I suppose I should
be thanking you for the job.
I don't mind saying
it's gonna come in very handy.
Now that the world
has a camera in their pocket?
It's what I always say.
Really?
Yeah.
- See you in the morning.
- Yep.
Hmm.
Guess what?
You are marrying Paul Kennedy.
Oh! Yes!
What the...
Ow!
Oh!
- Paul?
- Maddie! What the hell?
I'm sorry! I was asleep!
God, that hurts.
I didn't... It was a knee-jerk reaction.
Did I get you in the eye?
You got a bit more than the eye.
Oh, I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
Don't... Don't touch me.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- Oh.
I'm so sorry.
Are you sure you're okay?
- Oh, I'm tickety-boo.
- . Okay.
- You're doing a grand job, mate.
- Thank you.
Ah. Morning.
Where's Paul?
Uh, he's not coming.
Well, why not?
He had a little late-night injury.
He said we should scout locations.
- Nothing serious, I hope?
- Oh, no, he just needs the ice.
- What about your friends?
- Uh, they're getting mani-pedis.
Ready?
So how did you become an editor?
Oh, well, I was a freelance writer,
but that wasn't really paying the bills.
- Then I got a job at the publishing house.
- Ah, so that's how you met Paul.
Yeah. He wasn't really clicking
with any of the other editors,
and we were a good fit right off the bat.
That's interesting.
What does that mean?
I guess opposites attract.
Excuse me, Paul and I are not opposites.
We have many things in common.
I stand corrected.
I'm sure it's a long list of mutualities.
Why don't we stay silent for a second?
That way I can enjoy the view.
As you wish.
DES MOINES,
IOWA
- How about you?
- We don't need to talk about me.
- Nice view though.
- Where are we going?
- This is so pretty.
- Oh, it gets better. Come on.
So... I've got to ask.
Do you have to?
- Go ahead.
- Okay.
Why don't you write your own book?
I've been trying,
but it's been a bit difficult lately.
Because you're too busy
working on Paul's book.
No, I just...
- I'm not sure I have anything to say now.
- Everyone has something to say.
They just have to be
brave enough to say it.
- Are you calling me a coward?
- Absolutely not.
- You came up with that all by yourself.
- Okay.
Right. Well, Paul said
he wanted some authentic Ireland.
So, this is about as authentic as it gets.
Wow.
It's the Cliffs of Moher.
- You know it?
- I've heard about it.
What do you think?
I think I just stepped
into a James Joyce novel.
That's not the reference I was expecting.
Joyce is my favorite author.
Is he?
Hmm.
Hey, you're pretty good.
Thank you.
Unfortunately, I don't think
a rugged cliff is Paul's style.
No. No, probably not.
But is it yours?
- Yeah, I think it's beautiful here.
- Yeah, me too.
I'd love to get married up here.
Why don't you?
Because the wedding is this weekend,
and I don't want to be difficult.
I'd hardly call having a voice
at your own wedding being difficult.
Sorry, I just like to know
a little bit about my subjects
before I photograph them, that's all.
I thought you didn't photograph people.
I'm willing to make an exception.
I just don't understand it.
Oh.
- Wow.
- That was awful.
This looks like fun.
Heather, Emma. Come meet my mate, Finn.
Hi, I'm also Paul's groomsman.
Nice to meet you.
Paul, what happened to you?
Well, it's a long story.
I'm trying to minimize the damage.
Look.
Do you think it'll show in the photos?
I have an amazing concealer
you can borrow.
That'd be great. Thanks.
Heather, I was talking to Kory
about the big wedding aisle walk.
Should we all practice,
so we can make a splashy entrance?
I've got my eye on you, Finn.
- He's trying to steal my spotlight.
- I got moves, Paul. I ain't gonna lie.
Oh, no one could steal your spotlight.
Can I get you some more ice?
No, no, no. Stay here and entertain me.
Stop me feeling sorry for myself.
Are you always so thoughtful?
Not with everybody.
Lucky me.
There's a storm's coming.
We should probably get you back.
I'm sure you got lots to do.
Not really. Paul's mom
has already done everything.
Where's your mum in this whole equation?
In Des Moines, but she's flying in
for the rehearsal dinner tomorrow.
- I'm sure you'll be happy to see her.
- It'll be great to get her here.
She knows how to handle these situations.
It'll make everything easier.
- Should...
- Give me a hand with that. Yeah.
Just pull.
Holy mother of God!
- This is intense.
- You know what they say about Ireland?
If you don't like the weather,
just wait five minutes.
Mark Twain said that.
That is a really big tree.
Yeah, it is.
And this is the only road out.
- There has to be another way around it.
- If we had a Hummer.
I'll have to turn around. It's okay.
I know a lovely little pub we can go to.
Wait, really?
- Come on. Come on.
- Ah!
- Get under.
- Thank you.
Let's go.
It's a good pub, this. It'll be worth it.
Wow. This is a fun place.
They do the best
fish and chips in Ireland here.
- I thought you didn't like fish and chips.
- What makes you think that?
Well, you said...
Never mind.
James Thomas, you bastard.
O'Callaghan, you swine.
How are you, buddy?
Yeah. What brings you here?
Well, there's a tree down on the road,
so we're stuck.
Oh, right, I heard, yeah.
Seamus is gonna see to it
first thing in the morning.
But he's a little cabbaged now.
In that case,
we'll need two rooms for the night.
Whoa, wait, we can't spend the night here.
Well, do you fancy sleeping in the car?
Just give me a second.
This is Paul Kennedy.
I can't get to the phone right now.
- Who's that lovely creature?
- Calm down.
Don't tell me you finally convinced
some young lady you're worth a shake.
Hey, Paul, it's Maddie.
Uh, a tree fell down in the middle
of the road, and so we are stuck here.
Her name is Madeline Kelly,
and I'm photographing her wedding.
Ah.
- Her wedding, huh?
- Now, now.
Looks like I'll have to spend the night.
Call me when you get this.
Okay, I left a message.
Good. Let's eat.
- Ah, take a seat.
- Okay.
How about a couple of stouts?
Oh, can I have a white wine, please?
I don't really drink beer.
Ooh, I wouldn't say that too loud
around these parts.
You'd get locked up for treason.
- He seems great.
- Yeah, he's great.
Tom and I go a long way back.
I've been coming to Ireland
since I was a kid, so it holds a very...
special place in my heart.
Here's our latest. Hope you like it.
Is it true that you don't have a home?
This week it's a rented room
above Scruffy Murphy's.
After, I'll be on the road
traveling the world
with nothing but a camera and a passport.
Different situations
Running through my mind
Doesn't that get lonely after a while?
I mean, it's...
There's a freedom, having no ties.
And I don't know if I'm crazy
Well, maybe you haven't found that person
to spend the rest of your life with.
Like you did?
I see a house upon a hill
With our names written on the deck
Do you play darts?
Not recently.
Let's play now.
Here we go.
It's all about grip,
stance, and confidence.
- You don't like to talk about yourself.
- What makes you say that?
You keep changing the subject.
You're supposed
to keep your feet on the floor.
You see what I mean?
This time, just try your stance like this.
Only your arm moves.
You're a man of mystery.
If you keep talking,
you won't visualize hitting the target.
- That was sneaky.
- I'm not sneaky.
Maybe it's the luck of the Irish then.
Or maybe it's just you.
- I mean, you're a good coach.
- Well, you're a good student.
I'm getting married in two days.
Right.
- Your drinks.
- Oh.
And your rooms.
- Lovely. Thanks, Tom.
- Enjoy.
Thank you.
- You want to try it?
- Uh, sure.
Not bad.
- One dance before we call it a night.
- Okay.
I'm sorry. I need to get by here.
It's a family emergency.
I got to go. Please. Please.
Yeah, you're done. You're done.
Thank you. Bye.
Hi, I've been standing in line
all this time at the wrong counter,
and I've missed my flight.
So I need you to get me
another one immediately.
Principal Kelly. It's me, Allegra.
- Oh. Yes, hello, Allegra.
- Hi.
Well, I need to get to Ireland.
My daughter's getting married.
- Maddie's getting married?
- Yes. I'm pressed for time.
I missed my flight to Dublin.
So see if you can you find me another one.
Then I need a connection to Knock airport.
That's in West Ireland.
Sure. How did you miss your plane?
A clock malfunction.
You overslept. That's crazy.
There was a power outage,
and my backup phone alarm just...
- What are you doing?
- I'm texting Kimmy.
Remember her from detention?
She's gonna freak out.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
Somebody help me.
Please, help me!
Let's go.
Hey!
WILD HEN INN
Come on, please start. Please.
Mm-hmm.
Nope, nothing.
I can't believe this. I'm gonna be late
for my own wedding rehearsal.
Could be water in the carburetor.
- We could try a rolling jump.
- What's that?
You two push. I spring the clutch.
- Sure. Okay.
- Yeah, great.
All right, ready?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay!
Push!
Whoa!
Success!
Ah, crap.
I'll get a rag.
That'll do. A rag.
Well, no sign of Madeline.
First, her mother misses the flight,
and now here we are
waiting for the daughter.
- I hope this isn't a family trait.
- You couldn't make it up.
I'm sure Maddie will be here any minute.
I mean, those trees
can be a huge challenge,
and we don't even know
if they had a chain saw, right, Em?
Yeah, right.
I can't believe
you didn't bring a phone charger.
Neither did you.
Does this car go any faster?
- No.
- Great.
- It's not funny.
- It's pretty funny. It'll be fine. Look.
Look at that.
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here today
to celebrate the love
of these two fine, young people who...
Hold on, I'm here, I'm here, I'm here.
I'm sorry. I'm-I'm so sorry.
Close call, Maddie.
You almost lost your place.
Come here. Come here.
Oh. Sorry.
- What happened to you?
- Well...
Uh, I'm afraid I'm to blame.
We were coming back
from the Cliffs of Moher.
What were you doing in that tourist trap?
How did you get all muddy?
Well, we're all together now,
and that's what matters.
Mind if we cut to the chase?
We have guests are arriving
at the rehearsal dinner in an hour.
All right then,
let's skip to the good part.
You may now kiss the bride.
- Aw!
James?
What?
Who's James?
That'd be me.
What happened?
Well, you fainted.
It's her.
It's who?
Saint Brigid?
She's the one who made all this happen.
- Do you think she's been at the whiskey?
- Sean, please.
- Must be the stress of the wedding.
- Need water?
No, I'm just, uh...
I just feel a little dizzy, that's all.
- Are you sure you're okay?
- Yeah, of course I'm okay.
I'm marrying Paul Kennedy.
That's right.
Shall we continue?
Of course, Father. Sorry.
Where were we?
Quieten down, everyone.
My darling husband, Sean, has the floor.
Thank you, darling.
May your hearts be light and happy.
May your smiles be big and wide.
And may your pockets
always have a coin or two inside.
No worries there, Maddie.
You're marrying a Kennedy.
- Sláinte!
- You're drinking Guinness now, Maddie?
- I'm acquiring a taste for it.
All right, now in honor
of the happy couple,
we're gonna play a game
of "How Well Do You Know Your Fiancé?"
Oh!
Three questions. If you get them right,
you both take a shot.
Mm-hmm.
If you get them wrong,
we all have to drink a shot.
We have to drink no matter what?
Can we play a different game?
Oh, no, you're not getting out of this.
Kory's making the rules.
All right, first question.
Who is Maddie's favorite author?
Oh, that's an easy one.
Paul Kennedy.
No. Very good. Very good, no.
No, my fiancée likes the classics.
Her favorite author is...
James Joyce.
...Charles Dickens.
That's right.
Hey!
One point for the happy couple.
Question two. What is the song
you first danced to together?
Ooh.
- Well, there wasn't one.
- Mm!
Maddie doesn't know how to dance, do you?
Nope.
We've heard enough from you, brother.
Last question is for you, Maddie.
Where did Paul propose to you?
- She knows that answer.
- Tell us anyway.
- Propose?
- Yeah.
You know, how'd you get
the ring on your finger?
Well, go on, Maddie. Tell them.
Well, it was in this really special place.
Really special.
It was so, so special and...
Right, wasn't it?
It was really beautiful and special.
It was at O'Toole's in Brooklyn
on my birthday.
Exactly.
Ah.
- It was. It was at O'Toole's in Brooklyn.
- Mm-hmm.
- On your birthday.
- On my birthday.
And then...
Well, and then Maddie looked at me,
and she said, "What would it take
for you to bring me to Ireland?"
And I said,
"We'd have to be getting married."
And then...
Then...
Oh, she's only messing.
Then you got down on your knee,
and you proposed to me.
I proposed?
I mean, yes, of course.
Yes, I proposed. Me.
- I. Yes, I proposed.
- You.
And the rest, as they say, is history.
Hey, hey, hey
Ba-dee-ya, say, do you remember
Ba-dee-ya, dancing in September?
- You all right? What's the matter?
- Foot's hurting.
Come on.
Excuse me.
James, I thought
I might take a look at those.
I think it might be better
if you stay tonight.
I've asked Nevin
to make up the tower suite for you.
Nevin. Lovely.
- I'll see you in the morning.
- Fantastic.
- Thank you for today.
- Of course. Thank you for having me.
It's been lovely.
Remember
How we knew love was here to stay
Now December
Found the love we shared in September
Only blue talk and love, remember
Are you leaving already?
No, no, no. Just packing up
my stuff for the night.
Olivia has me staying
in their guest tower.
Sounds very posh.
I don't think she trusts me to make it
on time tomorrow after the tree incident.
- Mm.
- Yeah.
Thank you for taking me
to see the Cliffs, and for the dance.
I'd like to think of myself
as a full-service photographer.
Is it everything you imagined?
- What?
- This.
All of this.
You seemed confused in there,
like you and Paul didn't know each other.
That's ridiculous.
Of course we know each other.
- Charles Dickens?
- Anybody can make a mistake.
Yeah.
I hope you're not making one too.
You don't get to say that to me.
We barely know each other.
We spent a day together.
I admit it was a beautiful day
filled with dramatic vistas
and romantic rain,
but that doesn't give you the right
to question my life choices.
Tomorrow, I'm marrying Paul Kennedy.
Because you asked him.
Wait, so... so what? You don't think
a woman can ask a man to marry her?
Of course not.
But if you were my girlfriend,
I wouldn't have waited.
I'd have asked you first.
You know what?
Maybe you shouldn't come to the wedding.
I'll tell Olivia then.
- Fine. Take the photos.
- Fine. It'll be the last you see of me.
After this job, I'm off to Bolivia
to photograph an endangered tree lizard.
- What? When do you leave?
- Sunday.
Great. Right on time
to keep running from your own life.
I shouldn't have said that.
A bit late.
Mom?
- I got a flight. We're about to board.
- You did?
- That is great news.
- I'll be there in time for the wedding.
But don't pick me up. I'll take a taxi.
Okay. Mom, I'm so happy you're coming.
- I really need to see you.
- I'll be there soon.
I'll make sure your wedding to Paul
is absolutely perfect.
Thank you, Mom.
Gate change announcement.
Flight 47 to Dublin will now...
What did they just say?
Hold on one sec, honey.
Where's everyone going? What's happening?
- I gotta go. Bye.
- Mom? Mom?
Coming through. Coming through.
Oh.
Ah!
Goody two, goody two
Goody goody two shoes
Don't drink, don't smoke
What do you do?
There must be something inside
Phew! Hi.
Hi. Uh, looks like you're having fun.
Emma's a good dancer, huh?
Yeah. Hey, maybe she can give you
a few pointers for tomorrow.
Oh, I almost forgot. I wrote our vows.
I emailed them to you.
Wait, uh, you wrote my wedding vows?
Maddie, I am a writer.
But maybe you can
spruce them up a bit, huh?
Paul, can you come here for a sec?
Oh. I'm being summoned. You coming?
You know, I think
I'm gonna head to bed if that's okay.
I'm pretty beat.
Okay, well, I'm staying
in the guest room tonight.
Wouldn't want any bad luck
before the wedding.
No. Wouldn't want that.
- Good night.
ACKNOWLEDGMENTS
EDITED BY MADELINE KELLY.
UNTITLED NOVEL BY MADELINE KELLY
CHAPTER ONE
HERE YOU GO BABE!
WEDDING VOWS BY PAUL KENNEDY
- This was an amazing night.
- It was.
Yes. I wish it could have gone on forever.
Yeah, me too.
- Good night.
Those flowers go in the chapel.
A perfect morning for a wedding.
Did you get a good shot?
I think so. Yeah.
Um, haven't you got
a wedding to get ready for?
Yeah, I'm just taking a moment.
I'll leave you to it.
James. I'm really sorry about last night.
No apologies necessary.
You've had a lot going on.
- I read your book.
- You mean Paul's book.
I know what I said.
It's better than his other books.
A lot better.
Wonder how that happened.
I didn't change all that much.
- Why do you do that?
- Do what?
It's one thing to edit a book,
but you shouldn't
go on editing your own life.
I'm not editing my own life, I just...
I know this might sound strange,
but I'm not sure
this is supposed to be my life.
If that's the case,
then now is the time to speak up.
Is this what you really want, Maddie?
Is Paul really the person you want
to share the rest of your life with?
Marrying Paul is my wish come true.
Okay.
Then why are you so sad?
Right this way.
Your veil is spectacular.
You look amazing.
Well, this is it.
I can't believe it's all happening.
Me neither. Can you do me a favor
and see if my mom's arrived?
- She's not answering her phone.
- Yeah, absolutely. I'm on it.
Okay, thank you.
Hi, Father.
Are you ready, Madeline?
Uh, I guess so.
- You guess?
- I'm just...
Father, I think I've done something wrong.
What is it, my dear?
I made a wish to Saint Brigid.
Oh!
Is that all?
You have to be careful with that one.
She's known to have
a bit of a sense of humor.
Oh. What does that mean?
Well, when you ask her for something,
she may not give you what you want,
but she'll always give you what you need.
Oh, that's my cue.
It's all going to work out just fine.
I'll see you out there.
Oh!
Oh! It's starting.
Ah! Are my eyebrows even?
That makeup artist Olivia hired
has serious 'tude.
- And I think I pissed her off.
- You look great.
Mm...
- I'm sorry, Em.
- Hmm?
About what?
You and Paul.
What are you talking about?
I know you two
have feelings for each other.
I saw you on the patio last night.
Nothing happened.
I've known you since we were kids, Em.
It's all right. You can tell me.
Maddie.
Do you believe in fate?
Sometimes.
See, I don't know why,
but from the moment I met Paul,
it just... it just felt like
we were supposed to be together.
In another life, maybe we would have been.
Just not this one.
I can't believe
you're taking this so well.
This is your big day, and I'm ruining it.
It's not your fault. Really.
I'm gonna try to make things right.
Ah.
Excuse me.
- Hi.
- Stop, stop, stop.
- Hello.
- Is that the dress?
- What's going on?
- Oh, dear.
What's she wearing?
Where's the family wedding dress?
Hi, there.
Um, for those of you who don't know me,
I'm Maddie.
The bride.
Or at least I was supposed to be.
Of course, uh, you know Paul.
He's a really great guy,
and a good writer too.
Um...
People often tell me
that I need to speak up for myself.
So, here it goes.
I really care about Paul...
...but I'm not in love with him.
And I'm pretty sure
he feels the same way about me.
Maddie.
I just think
that if you're gonna go through
with something like this,
like a wedding,
and a marriage, and a life,
that it should be with someone you love,
not just someone you wish for.
It should be with someone you find,
or even someone who finds you.
I'm sorry. This is unacceptable!
Paul, how did you let this happen?
Me?
It's all his fault.
- The photographer?
- I saw you with Maddie this morning.
At the lily pond.
Wait, what about you and Emma
last night on the patio?
Oh, that's irrelevant.
This joker is trying to steal my bride.
At least I'm not stealing Maddie's ideas
and calling them my own.
- What are you talking about?
- Your latest book.
Well.
Wha...?
I wrote that book.
Hmm.
No, you didn't. I wrote that book.
And there you have it.
Paul, stop.
No. You're right. You're right.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, everyone.
Come here!
No! Stop. Let go of him.
Maddie, this is not helping.
Paul, stop it!
- My leg.
- Oh!
Oh!
Sean, don't just stand there!
Do something!
Come on, son. You got this.
- Steady does you.
- Who's that?
- Leave my brother alone!
- Mom? Where are you?
Don't panic,
but I am in the hospital in Des Moines.
- What? Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
I've just got a fracture of the metatarsal
and a little bump on the head,
but I remember everything now.
Honey, tell me. The wedding.
Was it everything you ever dreamt of?
Kory!
Not in a million years.
Why are you not getting him? Help me!
Help me get him.
Get off my foot! Get off!
What's wrong with you? What?
Mom, I'm gonna have to call you back.
James!
Who are you helping?
Paul. Are you hurt?
No, I don't think so.
I can't believe you called me irrelevant.
What?
I didn't mean it like that.
I'm sorry! Come back!
Oh my God.
Let's keep him out of this.
James.
Wait, James.
I made a mistake.
I shouldn't have stayed on this job.
I've become too emotionally involved.
- You have?
- You heard Paul in there.
He thinks I'm responsible for all this,
and if I'm being honest, I probably am.
You're not.
If I ever made you doubt yourself,
then I am truly sorry.
- But...
- The best thing I can do is just...
walk away from you.
But none of this is your fault.
I really wish you
all the happiness in the world.
I can't be happy without you.
I know this doesn't make sense right now,
but I believe in my heart
that we're meant to be together.
Not like this.
James, stop!
Goodbye, Maddie.
Okay, I'm here!
Oh.
I know you're here, Saint Brigid.
You can come out now!
Please! This was all a mistake.
Paul, the wedding, James.
Just take it back!
Saint Brigid!
There's no need to shout, dear.
I'm right here.
I need to unwish my wish.
Oh.
I'm afraid that's impossible.
That wish has already been granted.
But everything has gone horribly wrong.
Has it? Or has it gone exactly
as it was supposed to?
No, you're right,
and I've learned my lesson.
I have to live my own destiny.
Well, then, that's different.
Wait, come back. Where are you going?
Please, Saint Brigid,
let me unwish my wish!
Oh!
Okay.
Okay. I can do this.
I just need a little wind.
Where's the wind? Okay.
Okay, just a little breeze.
Give me something.
I'll take anything you got. Okay.
Just take back my wish!
Is anybody in here?
- Oh!
- Ah!
What are you doing?
- Why aren't you dressed?
- That's a bridesmaid's dress.
Uh, yes, and it's supposed to be
on the bridesmaid.
- The ring is gone.
- What ring?
That's Paul and Emma.
Oh.
Is everything okay?
This is amazing! Ah!
I'm glad you think so.
Let's get moving.
Oh.
- Hi, Mom.
- Sweetheart.
Oh, how's your foot?
My foot? Oh, you mean my arthritis.
Oh, that hasn't acted up
since I've been using that glucosamine.
- That is such good news!
- Aw.
Thank you, honey.
Yay!
James?
Oh, sorry.
Right.
Right. Here we go.
Hey!
Put on your red shoes
Thank you.
Whiskey, please.
- Great reception.
- Yeah.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Cheers.
...playing on the radio
Okay, fine. He's not into me.
I'm moving on.
- Good for you.
- Thank you.
Champagne, please.
- Well, hello, handsome.
- Hi.
- Fancy a dance?
- Oh, yeah. Sure.
All right. Say less.
Yeah.
If you say run
- Hey.
- Hey, having fun?
Yeah, it was a beautiful ceremony.
And you got to wear your own dress.
Wouldn't have happened without you.
Look, Maddie, I spent my whole life
looking for someone like Paul.
I couldn't be happier for you.
Oh, there's the photographer.
Is my lipstick still on?
It's perfect.
...break my heart in two
Ah
If you should fall into my arms
And tremble like a flower
There's my girl.
Congratulations, Paul.
Emma is an incredible person.
- You're lucky to have her.
- We're all lucky.
I just got off the phone
with the publisher.
The US numbers are huge.
They want a sequel right away.
Now obviously, I'm going
on my honeymoon for a month,
so do you mind
starting the story without me?
That depends.
On what?
Am I gonna get co-writing credit?
Madeline, that's not how it works.
I get the sole credit.
You edit the story,
and my name sells the books.
That's why we're a perfect team.
Yeah.
You know what, Paul?
That's not how a team works.
I'm afraid you're gonna have
to fly solo on this one.
Where are you going?
To write my own story.
Enjoy that.
- Thank you, Murphy.
- Sláinte.
So let me give you every...
What can I get for you?
Hi, I'm looking for James Thomas.
He's renting a room upstairs.
James? He's left. You just missed him.
Oh. I did?
- Maybe you'll catch him.
- Okay, uh, thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you so much.
You don't know why I'd waste my time
But I'm falling and I mean it
I want you like I need it
There's nothing you could try
To change my mind
Is this seat taken?
'Cause I'm in love with you
Um, depends if you'll try
to steal my bag again.
- Thanks.
- It's okay.
- Well, this is a coincidence.
- It's a small village.
- So you're a nature photographer, right?
- Mm-hmm.
I was wondering
if I could get your advice on something.
All right.
I'm doing some research
on the Bolivian tree lizard.
They're endangered, you know.
I've just been offered a job
in Bolivia to photograph that lizard.
- When are you leaving?
- Well, I'm not. I turned the job down.
You did?
Well, just after you got off that bus,
I, uh, met this very interesting woman
who encouraged me
to stick around for a while.
See what might happen.
How long are you gonna be in Ireland for?
As long as it takes.
I'm planning on writing
a book on the Cliffs of Moher.
Do you know them?
One of my favorite spots.
Mine too.
Huh.
Maybe we could go there together sometime.
I'd like that.
What's the book about?
I have this crazy idea.
- Fancy something to eat later?
- I'd love that.
I know a lovely little pub we can go to.
Can we play darts?
Absolutely.
There's even live music.
- Do you dance?
- Yes. Yes, I do.
I had a feeling.
Dreams in motion
And I wish tonight
If we stumble, if we fall
High up on the cliffs we go
Waves are crashing down below
Never say goodbye, hello
Hey, hey, hey
Raise our hands up to the sky
We will live and never die
Take you closer to my light
Comin' home
And we'll love until we break
And we'll take all we can take
Building castles
We will stay forever young
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
If we fall, we fall together
And if we rise
We will rise forever
Easy can be hard, you know
Higher can be down so low
We'll never say goodbye, hello
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey
Hey, hey, hey, hey
Raise your hands up to the sky
We will live and never die
Take you closer to my life
Comin' home
And we'll love until we break
And we'll take all we can take
Building castles
We will stay forever young
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Comin' home
Oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Comin' home
Yeah
IN LOVING MEMORY OF ANDREA SUE TOWNSEND