So stay with us,
because later this afternoon,
we're lucky enough to be talking to
Anna Scott, Hollywood's biggest star by far.
Miss Scott's latest ﬁlm
is once again topping the charts…
Of course, I've seen her films
and always thought she was, well, fabulous.
But, you know, a million, million miles
from the world I live in.
Which is here, Notting Hill.
My favourite bit of London.
There's the market on weekdays
selling every fruit and vegetable
known to man.
Rock hard bananas, five for a pound!
The tattoo parlour with a guy outside
who got drunk and now can't remember
why he chose "I love Ken."
The radical hairdressers,
where everyone comes out looking like
the Cookie Monster,
whether they want to or not.
And then, suddenly, it's the weekend
and from break of day hundreds of stalls
appear out of nowhere
filling Portobello Road,
right up to Notting Hill Gate.
And wherever you look thousands of people
are buying millions of antiques,
some genuine,
and some not quite so genuine.
And what's great is that lots of friends
have ended up in this part of London.
That's Tony, for example,
architect turned chef
who recently invested all the money
he ever earned in a new restaurant.
And so,
this is where I spend my days and years,
in this small village in the middle of the city,
in a house with a blue door
that my wife and I bought together
before she left me for a man
who looked exactly like Harrison Ford.
And where I now lead a strange
half-life with a Iodger called…
Spike?
Hi.
You couldn't help me with an
incredibly important decision, could you?
Is this important in comparison to, let's say,
whether they should cancel
Third World debt?
That's right. I'm at last going out
on a date with the great Janine
and I just wanna be sure
I've picked the right T-shirt.
- What are the choices?
- Well, wait for it.
First there's this one. Cool, huh?
Yeah, it might make it hard
to strike a really romantic note.
Point taken. Don't despair.
If it's romance we're looking for
I believe I have just the thing.
Yeah, well, there again, she might not think
you had true love on your mind.
Right. Just one more.
True love here I come.
Well, yeah. Yeah, that's, that's perfect.
Great. Thanks. Wish me luck.
Good luck.
And so it was just
another hopeless Wednesday
as I walked the thousand yards
through the market to work,
never suspecting that this was the day
that was gonna change my life forever.
This is work, by the way,
my little travel bookshop.
-Morning, Martin.
- Morning, Monseigneur.
Which, well, sells travel books
and to be frank with you,
doesn't always sell many of those.
Classic.
Profit from major sales push, minus £347.
Shall I go and get you a cappuccino?
- You know, ease the pain a bit.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Better make it a half. All I can afford.
Get your logic. Demi-cappu coming right up.
Can I help you at all?
No, thanks, I'll just look around.
Fine.
That book's really not great.
Just in case browsing turned to buying,
you'd be wasting your money.
But if it's Turkey you're interested in,
this one, on the other hand, is very good.
I think the man who wrote it
has actually been to Turkey, which helps.
There's also a very amusing incident
with a kebab
which is one of many amusing incidents.
Thanks, I'll think about it.
Or, in the bigger hard-back variety, there's...
I'm sorry, can you just give me a second?
Excuse me.
- Yes?
- Bad news.
What?
We've got a security camera
in this bit of the shop.
So?
So I saw you
put that book down your trousers.
- What book?
- The one down your trousers.
I don't have a book down my trousers.
Right, I tell you what, I'll call the police
and what can I say, if I'm wrong about
the whole book-down-the-trousers scenario,
I really apologise.
Okay. What if
I did have a book down my trousers?
Well, ideally, when I went back to the desk
you'd remove the Cadogan Guide to Bali
from your trousers
and either wipe it and put it back or buy it.
I'll see you in a sec.
I'm sorry about that.
No, it's fine.
I was gonna steal one
but now I've changed my mind.
Signed by the author, I see.
Yeah, couldn't stop him.
If you can find an unsigned one,
it's worth an absolute fortune.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Can I have your autograph?
- Sure.
- Here.
- What's your name?
- Rufus.
What does it say?
That's my signature, and above it,
it says "Dear Rufus, you belong in jail."
Good one.
Do you want my phone number?
Tempting, but no.
Thank you.
I will take this one.
Oh, right, right.
So, well, on second thoughts
maybe it's not that bad after all.
Actually it's a sort of classic, really.
None of those childish kebab stories
you find in so many books these days.
I tell you what,
I'll throw in one of those for free.
Useful for lighting fires, wrapping fish,
that sort of thing.
- Thanks.
- Pleasure.
Here we are. Cappuccino, as ordered.
Thanks.
I don't think
you'll believe who was just in here.
Who? Was it someone famous?
No, no, no.
Would be exciting though, wouldn't it,
if someone famous came into the shop?
Do you know, this is pretty amazing
actually, but I once saw Ringo Starr.
- Where was that?
- Kensington High Street.
At least I think it was Ringo.
It might have been that man
from Fiddler On The Roof.
- You know, Toppy.
- Topol.
Yes, that's right. Topol.
Actually, Ringo Starr
doesn't look at all like Topol.
Yeah, but he was
quite a long way away from me.
So actually
it could've been neither of them?
Yes, I suppose so, yes.
- It's not a classic anecdote, is it?
- Not a classic, no. No.
Another one?
Yes. No! Let's go crazy.
I'll have an orange juice.
- Okay, thanks. Bye-bye.
- See you later.
- Shit! Bugger!
- Oh, my God!
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
- Here let me...
- Get your hands off!
I'm really sorry. I live just over the street.
I have water and soap.
You can get cleaned up.
No, thank you.
I just need to get my car back.
I also have a phone.
I'm confident that in five minutes
we can have you spick and span
and back on the street again.
In the non-prostitute sense, obviously.
All right.
Well, what do you mean
"just over the street"? Give it to me in yards.
Eighteen yards. That's my house there
with the blue front door.
Come on in. I'll just, I'll just...
Right. Right.
Come in.
It's not quite as tidy as it normally is, I fear.
But the bathroom's on the top floor.
And the telephone's just up here.
Here, let me...
Round the corner,
straight on, straight on up.
Bugger!
- Would you like a cup of tea before you go?
- No.
- Coffee?
Orange juice?
Probably not.
Something else cold?
Coke? Water?
Some disgusting sugary drink
pretending to have
something to do with fruits of the forest?
No.
Would you like something to eat?
Something to nibble?
Apricots soaked in honey?
Quite why, no one knows,
because it stops them tasting of apricots
and makes them taste like honey,
and if you wanted honey
you'd just buy honey instead of apricots.
But nevertheless, there we go,
they're yours if you want them.
No.
Do you always say "no" to everything?
I'd better be going. Thanks for your... help.
You're welcome.
And may I also say... heavenly.
I'll just take my one chance to say it.
After you've read that terrible book
you're certainly
not gonna be coming back to the shop.
Thank you.
Yeah, well, my pleasure.
So... it was nice to meet you.
Surreal but nice.
Sorry.
"Surreal but nice." What was I thinking?
- Hi.
- I forgot my other bag.
- Oh, right. Right.
Thanks.
I'm very sorry
about the "surreal but nice" comment.
- Disaster.
- That's okay.
I thought the apricot and honey thing
was the real low point.
Oh, my God. My flatmate.
I'm sorry. There's no excuse for him.
- Hi.
I'm just going into the kitchen
to get some food.
Then I'm gonna tell you a story that will
make your balls shrink to the size of raisins.
Probably best not to tell anyone about this.
Right. Right, no one.
I'll tell myself sometimes but, don't worry,
I won't believe it.
- Bye.
There's something wrong with this yoghurt.
- It's not yoghurt. It's mayonnaise.
- Oh, right. There we are then.
On for a videofest tonight?
I got some absolute classics.
-Smile.
- No.
- I've got nothing to smile about.
Okay, in about seven seconds
I'm going to ask you to marry me.
Imagine... somewhere in the world
there's a man who's allowed to kiss her.
She is... fairly fabulous.
- Do you have any books by Dickens?
- No.
No, I'm afraid we're a travel bookshop.
We only sell travel books.
Oh, right.
How about the new John Grisham thriller?
Well, no, because that's a novel too, isn't it?
Oh, right.
Have you got Winnie-the-Pooh?
- Martin, your customer.
- Can I help you?
- Hey.
- Hi.
Just, incidentally,
why are you wearing that?
Combination of factors really.
No clean clothes...
There never will be, you know,
unless you actually clean your clothes.
- Vicious circle.
- Yeah.
And I was, like, rooting round in your things
and I found this and I thought, "Cool."
Kinda spacey.
There's something wrong
with the goggles, though.
No, they were prescription.
- Groovy.
- So I could see all the fishes properly.
You should do more of this stuff.
- So, look, any messages today?
- Yeah, I wrote a couple down.
So there were two,
there were two messages? Right?
You want me
to write down all your messages?
Okay. Who are the ones
that you didn't write down from?
No, gone completely.
Oh, no, there was one from your mum.
She said don't forget lunch,
and her leg's hurting again.
- No one else?
- Absolutely no one else.
Though if we're going for this obsessive
writing-down-all-the-message thing,
some American girl called Anna
called a few days ago.
What did she say?
Well, it was genuinely bizarre.
She said, "Hi, it's Anna."
Then she said, "Call me at The Ritz."
And then gave herself
a completely different name.
- Which was?
- Absolutely no idea.
Remembering one name's hard enough.
No, I know that. She said that.
I know she's using another name.
The problem is
she left the message with my flatmate
which was a very serious mistake.
Imagine, if you will,
the stupidest person you've ever met.
Are you doing that?
Yes, sir, I have him in my mind.
And now double it.
And that is the, what can I say,
the git that I am living with.
- And he can't remember this other...
- Try Flintstone.
- Sorry. What?
- I think she said her name was Flintstone.
I don't suppose Flintstone rings any bells,
does it?
- I'll put you right through, sir.
- Oh, my God.
Hello. Hi.
Hi.
Hi. Sorry. It's William Thacker.
- Yes?
- We... I work in a bookshop.
You played it pretty cool there,
waiting for three days to call.
Oh, no, I promise you I've never played
anything cool in my entire life.
My flatmate, who I'll stab to death later,
never gave me the message.
I don't know. Perhaps
I could drop round for tea later
or something?
Things are pretty busy here.
I might be free around 4:00.
Right. Right. Great.
-Bye.
- Bye.
Classic.
- Which floor?
- Three, please.
- Are you sure?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, sure.
Hi. Hi. I'm Karen. I'm sorry,
things are running a little bit late.
Here's the thing.
Do you wanna come this way?
Through here.
- So what did you think of the film?
- Yeah, I thought it was fantastic.
I thought it was Close Encounters
meets Jean de Florette.
I agree.
I'm sorry, I didn't get down
what magazines you're from.
-Time Out.
- Great.
And you're from?
Horse & Hound.
The name's William Thacker.
Actually, she might be expecting me.
Oh, okay. Take a seat and I'll go check.
I see you've...
I see you've brought her some flowers.
No. These are for my grandmother.
She's in a hospital down the road.
Thought I'd kill two birds with one stone,
you know.
Sure, right. Absolutely, yeah.
Which hospital's that?
Do you mind me not saying?
It's a rather distressing thing, isn't it?
Name of the hospital kind of gives it away.
- Absolutely. Sure.
- Cheers.
- Right. Mr. Thacker, if you come this way.
- Right.
You've got five minutes.
- Hi.
- Hello.
I brought these, but clearly...
No, they're great. They're great.
I'm sorry about not ringing back.
The whole "two names" concept
was totally too much for my flatmate's
pea-sized intellect.
No, it's a stupid privacy thing.
I always pick a cartoon character.
Last time I was Mrs. Bambi.
- Everything all right?
- Yes, thank you.
And you're from Horse & Hound?
Good.
Is that so? Well.
So,
I'll just fire away, then, shall I?
Right.
The film's great,
and I just was wondering whether
you ever thought of having
more... horses in it?
Well, we would have liked to,
but it was difficult, obviously,
being set in space.
Space, right, yeah.
Yeah, obviously very difficult.
I'm so sorry.
I arrived outside,
they thrust this thing into my hand.
No, it's my fault.
I thought this would all be over by now.
I just wanted to sort of apologise
for the kissing thing.
I seriously don't know what came over me.
I just wanted to make sure
that you were fine about it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, absolutely fine.
Do remember that Miss Scott is also
keen to talk about her next project
which she is shooting later in the summer.
Yes, excellent. Excellent.
Any horses in that one?
Or hounds for that matter? Our readers
are equally intrigued by both species.
It takes place on a submarine.
Well, bad luck.
But if there were horses in it
would you be riding them or would you be
getting a stunt-horse-double-man-thing?
I'm a complete moron. I apologise.
This is very weird.
It's the sort of thing that happens in dreams,
not in real life.
I mean, good dreams.
It's a dream, in fact, to see you again.
What happens next in the dream?
I suppose that in the dream,
"dream scenario,"
I just change my personality
because you can do that in dreams
and walk over and kiss the girl. But...
Time's up, I'm afraid.
Did you get what you wanted?
- Nearly, nearly.
- Well, maybe just one last question.
- Sure.
- Right, right.
Are you busy tonight?
- Yes.
- Right. Right.
Come in.
- Well, it was nice to meet you.
- Yes, and you.
Surreal but nice.
Thank you.
You are Horse & Hound's favourite actress.
You and Black Beauty tied.
Hang on, don't go. How was she?
- Fabulous.
- Excellent.
Wait a minute,
she took your grandmother's flowers.
Yeah, yeah. That's right. Bitch.
Mr. Thacker. If you'd like to come with me
we can just rush you through the others.
-The others?
- Mr. Thacker is from Horse & Hound.
- How's it going?
- Very well. Thank you.
Have a seat.
Well, did you enjoy the film?
Yes. Enormously.
- Well, fire away.
- Right.
- Did you enjoy making the film?
- Yes, I did.
Good.
Any bit in particular?
You tell me what "bit" you enjoyed the most
and I'll tell you
if I enjoyed making that "bit."
I…liked the bit in space.
Very much.
Did you identify
with the character you're playing?
No.
Oh.
Why not?
Because he's playing
a psychopathic flesh-eating robot.
Classic.
So, is this your first film?
No, it's my 22nd.
Of course it is.
Any favourites among the 22?
- Working with Leonardo.
- Da Vinci?
- DiCaprio.
- Of course.
And is he your favourite Italian director?
- Mr. Thacker?
- Oh, no.
- Have you got a minute?
- No.
Hi.
Yeah, so the...
The thing I was doing tonight
I'm not doing any more.
I told them I had to spend the evening
with Britain's premier equestrian journalist.
Well, great. Fantastic. That's...
Shittity brickity.
It's my sister's birthday. Shit.
- We're meant to be having dinner.
- Okay, that's fine.
No, I'm sure I can get out of it.
No, I mean, if it's fine with you,
I'll be your date.
You'll be my date
to my little sister's birthday party?
- If it's all right.
- Well, yeah, I'm sure it's all right.
My friend Max is cooking
and he is generally acknowledged to be
the worst cook in the world,
but you could hide the food
in your handbag or something.
- Okay.
- He's bringing a girl?
- Miracles do happen.
- Does the girl have a name?
- Don't know, wouldn't say.
Oh Christ, what is going on in there?
Oh, God!
Hi, come on in. Vague food crisis.
Hiya.
Sorry, the guinea-fowl is proving
more complicated than expected.
- He's cooking guinea-fowl?
- Don't even ask.
- Hi.
- Good Lord, you're the spitting image of...
- Bella, this is Anna.
- Right.
- Okay, crisis over.
Max, this is Anna.
- Hi.
- Hello, Anna... Scott.
- Have some wine.
- Thank you.
I'll get it.
Red or white?
- Hi.
- Oh yes, happy birthday.
- Thank you.
Look, your brother's brought this girl...
Hi, guys.
Holy fuck!
Honey, this is Anna. Anna, this is Honey.
She's my baby sister.
- Hi.
- Oh, God.
This is one of those key moments in life
when it's possible
you can be really genuinely cool
and I'm going to fail just 100%.
I absolutely, totally and utterly adore you.
And I just think you are
the most beautiful woman in the world.
And more importantly, I genuinely believe,
and I've believed for some time now,
that we could be best friends.
So what do you think?
Lucky me.
- Happy birthday.
- Oh, you gave me a present.
We're best friends already then.
Marry Will, he's a really nice guy,
then we can be sisters.
I'll think about it.
That'll be Bernie.
- Hi.
- Hi. Sorry I'm late.
Bollocksed up at work again, I fear.
- Millions down the drain.
- Well done.
Bernie, this is Anna.
- Hello, Anna. Delighted to meet you.
- And you.
Honey bunny, happy birthday to you.
- Hi, Bella.
- Hi.
It's a hat.
You don't have to wear it or anything.
- Hi, Will.
- Hi.
Hi.
- What?
Wine, Bernie?
You haven't slept with her, have you?
That is a cheap question and the answer is,
of course, no comment.
- No comment means "yes."
- No, it doesn't.
- Do you ever masturbate?
- Definitely no comment.
You see, it means "yes."
Oh, my God!
So, tell me, Anna, what do you do?
- I'm an actress.
- Oh, splendid.
- What do you do?
- I'm actually in the stock market myself.
So... not really similar fields.
Though I have done
the odd bit of amateur stuff.
P. G. Wodehouse. Farce, all that, you know.
"Careful there, vicar."
Always imagined it's a pretty tough job,
though, acting.
I mean, the wages are a scandal,
aren't they?
They can be.
I see friends from university, clever chaps,
been in the business longer than you.
They're scraping by on seven,
eight thousand a year.
It's no life.
- What sort of acting do you do?
- Films mainly.
Splendid. Oh, well done.
How's the pay in movies?
I mean, last film you did,
what did you get paid?
$15 million.
Right.
So that's... well, fairly good.
Right, I think we're ready.
Bella, can you tell me where I can find...
Oh, sorry, yeah, yeah.
It's down the corridor on the right.
I'll show you. I'll show you.
Quickly, quickly, quickly. Talk very quickly.
What are you doing here with Anna Scott?
- Anna Scott? What, the film star?
- Yes. Shut up.
Shh.
- Oh, God!
- What?
- Oh, God. Oh, goddy God.
- What did you say to her?
I don't believe it. I don't believe it.
I actually walked into the loo with her.
I was still chatting
when she started unbuttoning her jeans.
- She had to ask me to leave.
- Oh, God.
So you knew who she was?
Of course I did, but he didn't!
Well, not instantly,
but I got away with it though.
What do you think of the guinea-fowl?
- I'm a vegetarian.
- Oh, God.
So, how's the guinea-fowl?
Best guinea-fowl I've ever tasted.
Having you here, Anna,
firmly establishes what I've long suspected,
that we really are the most desperate lot
of under-achievers.
- Shame.
- I'm not saying it's a bad thing.
In fact, I think it's something
we should take pride in.
I'm gonna give the last brownie as a prize
to the saddest act here.
Bern.
Well, obviously it's me, isn't it?
I mean, I work in the city
in a job I don't understand
and everyone keeps
getting promoted above me.
I haven't had a girlfriend since,
well, since puberty.
And nobody fancies me.
And if these cheeks get any chubbier,
they never will.
Nonsense. I fancy you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You see.
And unless I'm much mistaken
your job still pays you rather a lot of money
whilst Honey here earns 20 pence a week
flogging her guts out
in London's worst record store.
Yes!
And I haven't got hair, I've got feathers.
And I've got funny goggly eyes
and I'm attracted to cruel men.
Actually, no one will marry me because
my boosies have actually started shrinking.
You see, it's incredibly sad.
Yeah, but on the other hand
her best friend is Anna Scott.
That's true, I can't deny it.
She needs me. What can I say?
And most of her limbs work whereas
I'm stuck in this thing day and night,
in a house full of ramps.
And to add insult to serious injury
I've totally given up smoking,
my favourite thing.
Well, the truth is, we can't have a baby.
Oh, Belle...
C'est la vie.
Still, we're lucky in lots of ways.
But, surely that's worth a brownie.
Well, I don't know.
Look at William.
- Very unsuccessful professionally.
- That's true.
Divorced.
Used to be handsome,
now kind of squidgy round the edges.
And absolutely certain
never to hear from Anna again
once she's heard that
his nickname at school was Floppy.
You did. I can't believe it, you did.
Thanks very much. Thank you.
- Well at least I get the last brownie, right?
- I think so, yes.
Well, wait, what about me?
I'm sorry?
You think you deserve the brownie?
- Well, a shot at it at least, huh?
- Right, well, you'll have to prove it.
I mean, this is a very, very good brownie
and I'm gonna fight for it.
I've been on a diet every day since I was 19
which basically means
I've been hungry for a decade.
I've had a series of not nice boyfriends,
one of whom hit me.
And every time I get my heart broken,
the newspapers splash it about
as though it's entertainment.
And it's taken two rather painful operations
to get me looking like this.
- Really?
- Really.
And one day, not long from now
my looks will go,
they will discover I can't act
and I will become some sad,
middle-aged woman who
looks a bit like someone
who was famous for a while.
No, nice try, gorgeous,
but you don't fool anyone.
Pathetic effort to hog the brownie.
- Thank you for such a terrific time.
- I'm delighted.
- That's a great tie.
- Now you're lying.
Okay, it's true.
I told you I was bad at acting.
- It was lovely to meet you.
- Yeah. And you.
I'll wait until you've gone
before I tell him you're a vegetarian.
No!
- Goodnight.
- I'm sorry about the loo thing.
I meant to leave but I just...
Look, ring me
if you want someone to go shopping with.
I know lots of nice, cheap places.
I mean, not that money is necessarily...
It was just so nice to meet you.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
You're my style guru.
Sorry, can I just...
Goodnight, everyone.
Max, Belle,
we'll see you in a couple of days.
- Bye, guys.
- Bye, Anna.
Love your work.
- Goodnight.
Sorry.
They always do that when I leave the house.
It's a stupid thing. I hate it.
- Floppy, huh?
- It's the hair. It's to do with the hair.
Why is she in a wheelchair?
Because she had an accident
about 18 months ago.
And the pregnancy thing,
is that to do with the accident?
You know, I'm not sure.
I don't think they tried for kids before,
as fate would have it.
Do you want to...
My place is just...
Too complicated.
That's fine.
Busy tomorrow?
- I thought you were leaving tomorrow.
- I was.
All these streets round here
have these mysterious communal gardens
in the middle of them.
- They're like little villages.
- Let's go in.
No, that's the point. They're private villages.
Only the people who live round the edges
are allowed in.
- You abide by rules like that?
- I don't, no, no, but others do.
And I just do what I want.
Right.
Whoopsidaisies.
What did you say?
- Nothing.
- Yes, you did.
- No, I didn't.
- You said "whoopsidaisies."
No one says "whoopsidaisies," do they?
I mean, unless they're...
There is no "unless."
Because no one has said "whoopsidaisies"
for 50 years.
And even then it was
just little girls with blonde ringlets.
Exactly. Right.
So here we go again.
Whoopsidaisies.
Yeah, well, it's a disease.
It's a clinical thing.
I'm taking pills and having injections.
And I'm told it won't last long so...
- Okay, stand aside.
- I don't think that's a good idea.
Really, it's quite tricky. Anna.
Anna, don't, it's harder than it...
No, it's not. It's easy.
Come on, Flopsy.
Right. Right!
Oh, bugger.
Oh, God. This could be very unpleasant.
Bugger, bugger.
Now what in the world in this garden
could make that ordeal worthwhile?
Nice garden.
"For June who loved this garden,
from Joseph who always sat beside her."
Some people
do spend their whole lives together.
Come and sit with me.
Bollocks. Bollocks. Bollocks!
- Have you seen my glasses?
- No, afraid not.
Big, big bollocks!
Average day, my glasses are everywhere.
Everywhere I look there's a pair of glasses.
But when I want to go to the cinema
they've vanished.
It's one of life's real cruelties.
That's compared to, like, earthquakes
in the Far East or testicular cancer, is it?
Oh, shit, is that the time?
Thanks for all your help
on the glasses thing.
Oh, you're welcome. Did you find them?
- Sort of.
- Great.
- So who left who?
- She left me.
Why?
- She saw through me.
- That's not good.
You can give me Anna Scott any day.
I didn't like her last film.
Fell asleep as soon as the lights went down.
I don't really care what the film's like.
Any film with her in, it's fine by me.
She's not my type at all.
I prefer that other one.
You know, blonde, sweet looking.
You know, what's her name?
Has an orgasm every time
you take her out for a cup of coffee.
Meg Ryan.
No, she's too wholesome.
You see, the point about Miss Scott
is she's got that twinkle in her eye.
Probably drug-induced.
Spends most of her life in bloody rehab.
Well, whatever. She's so clearly up for it.
I mean, you see, most girls,
they're all like, "Stay away, chum."
She is absolutely gagging for it.
Do you know that in over 50% of languages
the word for "actress"
is the same as the word for "prostitute"?
Where did you get that from?
And Anna is your definitive actress,
someone really filthy
you can just flip over and start again.
- Right, that's it. Sorry.
- No, no. There's really no point.
Sorry, sorry to disturb you guys but...
- Can I help?
- Well, yeah.
I wish I hadn't overheard your conversation,
but I did.
And, I just think, you know the person
you're talking about is a real person
and I think she probably
deserves a little bit more consideration
rather than having jerks like you
drooling over her.
Oh, sod off, mate. What are you, her dad?
- I'm sorry.
- No, I love that you tried.
Time was I'd have done the same thing.
In fact...
Hi.
Oh, my God!
I just wanted to apologise for my friend.
He's very sensitive.
No, no, no, leave it.
I'm sure you didn't mean any harm.
I'm sure it was just friendly banter.
I'm sure you guys
have dicks the size of peanuts.
Enjoy your dinner. The tuna's really good.
I shouldn't have done that.
- No, you were brilliant.
- I'm rash and I am stupid.
What am I doing with you?
I don't know, I'm afraid.
I don't either.
Here we are.
Yes.
- Well look...
- Do you wanna come up?
Well, there seems to be lots of
reasons why I shouldn't, so...
There are lots of reasons.
Do you wanna come up?
Give me five minutes?
- Hi.
To be able to do that
is such a wonderful thing.
- You've got to go.
- Why?
Because my boyfriend, who was in America,
is, in fact, now in the next room.
- Boyfriend?
- Yes.
- Hey, baby, who is it?
- It's...
Room service.
How are you doing?
I thought you guys
always wore those penguin coats?
Usually we do.
But I was just changed to go home.
And then I thought I'd take this final call.
Oh, great. If you don't mind,
I would like something, too.
Could you bring me up some really,
really cold water?
- I'll see what I can do.
- Still, not sparkling.
Absolutely. Ice-cold still water.
Unless, of course, it's illegal in the UK
to serve beverages below room temperature.
I wouldn't want you going to jail
just to satisfy my whim, now.
- I'm sure it's fine.
- Thank you.
Hey, one more thing, if you don't mind,
could you adiós these dirty dishes
and take out that trash, too?
- Right.
- No. No. Don't do that.
I don't think it's his job to clear.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
What's your name, man?
Bernie.
Oh, listen, Bernie, thank you,
I really appreciate it.
Hey, you...
So, tell me, tell me, tell me.
Good surprise or nasty surprise?
- Good surprise.
- Oh, you're such a liar. She hates surprises.
Hey, what are you gonna order?
From him. What are you gonna order?
- I haven't decided yet.
- Well, don't overdo it.
I don't want people saying,
"There goes that famous actor
with the big fat girlfriend."
I should leave.
This is a fairly strange reality
to be faced with.
I'm so sorry.
I don't know what to say.
I think "goodbye" is traditional.
Come on. Open up.
This is me.
Spikey.
I'm in contact with some
quite important spiritual vibrations.
Come on. Hit me with it.
There's this girl.
See, I'd been getting a female vibe. Good.
Speak on, dear friend.
She's someone who can't be mine,
and it's as if I've taken "love heroin"
and now I can't ever have it again.
I've opened Pandora's Box
and there's this trouble inside.
Yeah.
Tricky.
I knew a girl at school called Pandora.
Never got to see her box though.
Right.
Right, thanks, that's very helpful.
You didn't know she had a boyfriend?
No. No. Why, did you?
Oh, bloody hell, I don't believe it.
My whole life ruined
because I don't read Hello! magazine.
Let's face facts.
This was always a no-win situation.
Anna's a goddess.
You know what happens to mortals
who get involved with the gods.
Buggered, is it?
Every time.
But don't despair,
I think I have the solution to your problems.
Really?
Her name is Tessa,
and she works in the contracts department.
The hair, I admit, is unfashionably frizzy.
But she's bright as a button, and kisses
like a nymphomaniac on death row.
Apparently.
Now, try.
I got completely lost.
It's real difficult, isn't it?
Everything's got the word Kensington in it.
Kensington Park Road.
Kensington Gardens.
Kensington bloody Park Gardens.
- Look, Tessa, this is Bella, my wife.
- Hello. You're in a wheelchair.
- Yeah, that's right.
- And this is William.
- Hello, William.
- Hi.
Max has told me everything about you.
- Has he?
- Oh, yes. You are a naughty boy.
- Wine?
- Oh, yes, please.
Come on, Willie, let's get sloshed.
- Red or white?
- Red.
Keziah...
Some woodcock?
No, thank you, I'm a fruitarian.
What is a fruitarian exactly?
Well, we believe that fruits and vegetables
have feelings, so we think cooking is cruel.
We only eat things that have actually fallen
from the tree or bush.
That are, in fact, dead already.
Oh, right.
Right.
So, these carrots...
Have been murdered, yes.
Murdered?
Gosh, poor old carrots. That's beastly.
Delicious coffee.
I'm sorry about the lamb.
No, I thought it was really, you know,
interesting.
"Interesting" means "inedible."
Really inedible, yes, you're right.
Well, maybe we'll meet again.
Yeah. Yeah. That'll be great.
Bye.
Well?
Perfect. Absolutely perfect.
And?
You see, I think you've forgotten
what an unusual situation you two have.
To find someone you actually love,
who'll love you, I mean,
the chances are always minuscule.
Look at me. Apart from the American,
I've only loved two girls,
both total disasters.
- That's not fair.
- No, really.
One of them marries me then leaves me
faster than you can say "Indiana Jones."
And the other,
who seriously ought to have known better,
casually marries my best friend.
She still loves you though.
Yeah, in a depressingly asexual way.
I never fancied you much, actually.
Oh, God.
I loved you, you were terribly funny,
but all that kissing my ears...
I don't believe it. This is just getting worse.
I shall find myself 30 years from now
still sitting on this sofa.
Do you wanna stay?
Yeah, why not.
All that awaits me at home
is a masturbating Welshman.
Here we go.
- Goodnight.
- Night.
- See you, Will.
- Right. Right.
- Guilty. Very, very guilty.
- So it seems.
Hi.
Can I come in?
Come in.
They were taken years ago.
I know it was...
But I was poor and it happens a lot.
That's not an excuse. I just...
But to make matters worse,
it now appears as though
someone was filming me as well.
So what was a stupid photo shoot
now looks like a porn film.
And the pictures have been sold,
and they're just everywhere.
I didn't know where to go.
The hotel's surrounded.
I know it's been months but...
This is the place.
Thank you.
I'm just in London for two days,
but what with your papers,
it's the worst place to be.
I mean, these pictures are just so horrible
and they're so grainy.
- And it makes me look like...
- Listen, don't think about it.
We'll sort it out.
Now what would you like?
Tea? Bath?
Yeah.
A bath would be great.
Oh, Christ alive!
Brilliant. Fantastic.
Magnificent.
You must be Spike.
Hi.
Just checking.
Thank you, God.
I'm really sorry about last time.
I mean, he just flew in. I had no idea.
In fact, I had no idea
if he was ever gonna fly in again.
Listen, it's not often
one has the opportunity to
adiós the plates
of a major Hollywood film star.
It was thrilling for me.
So how is he?
I don't know.
It just got to the point
where I couldn't remember
any of the reasons why we were together.
And you and love?
Oh, well, there's a question
without an interesting answer.
I have thought about you.
It's just that any time I've tried to keep
anything normal
with a person that was normal,
it's just been a disaster.
Yeah, no, listen,
I appreciate that, absolutely.
So what is that, a film you're doing?
I start in LA on Tuesday.
Would you like me
to take you through your lines?
Would you? Because it's all talk, talk, talk.
Come on, hand it over. Right.
Basic plot?
I'm a difficult but brilliant junior officer,
who in about 20 minutes
is gonna save the world
from nuclear disaster.
Okay, well done, you.
"Message from Command,
would you like them to send in the HK's?"
No. Turn over four TRS's
and tell them we need radar feedback
before the KFT's return at 19:00.
Then inform the Pentagon we need
Black Star cover
from 10:00 through 12:15.
And if you say one word about
how many mistakes I made in that speech,
I'll pelt you with olives.
"Very well, Captain,
I'll pass that on, straight away."
Thank you. How many mistakes did I make?
Eleven.
- Dammit. And, Wainwright...
- Cartwright.
Cartwright, Wainwright,
whatever your name is...
I promised little Jimmy
I'd be home for his birthday,
so could you get a message to him
that I may be a little late?
"Certainly." And little Johnny?
- My son's name is Johnny?
- Yeah.
Well, then get a message to him, too.
"I'll do what I can, Captain,
but I can't promise anything."
And, Cartwright goes.
What do you think?
Gripping. You know, it's not Jane Austen.
It's not Henry James. But it's gripping.
Think I should do Henry James instead?
Well, I think you would be brilliant
in Henry James
but, you know, this writer... Writers...
They're pretty damn good, too.
Well, you never get anyone
in Wings of the Dove saying,
"Inform the Pentagon,
we need Black Star cover."
Well, and for me,
the book is the poorer for it.
I can't believe you have that picture.
You like Chagall?
I do.
It feels like how love should be.
Floating through a dark blue sky.
With a goat, playing a violin.
Well, yes.
Happiness isn't happiness
without a violin-playing goat.
You have big feet.
Yes. Yes, always have had.
You know what they say
about men with big feet?
No, I don't know. What's that?
Big feet, large shoes.
The thing that's so irritating is that now
I'm so totally fierce
when it comes to nudity clauses.
You actually have clauses in your contract
about nudity?
Definitely.
You may show the dent of the top
of the artist's buttocks but neither cheek.
Or, if there's a stunt bottom being used,
artist must have full consultation.
You have a stunt bottom?
Well, I could have a stunt bottom, yes.
And are people tempted to go for
better bottoms than their own.
Yeah. I mean, I would.
This is important stuff.
Well, it's one hell of a job, isn't it?
I mean, what do you put on your passport?
Profession. Mel Gibson's bottom.
Actually, Mel does his own ass work.
Right.
- Why wouldn't he?
- Absolutely.
It's delicious.
What, the ice cream
or Mel Gibson's bottom?
Both. Equally.
But you wouldn't necessarily lick both?
Well, this is tart.
And fuzz free.
And...
The bedroom, I've put clean sheets on.
Today's been a good day.
Which in the circumstances is unexpected.
Thank you.
Anyway, time for bed.
Or, sofa bed.
- Goodnight.
Oh, my God.
Hello?
Hello.
Spike?
I wonder if I could have a little word?
- Right.
- I don't want to interfere or nothing,
but she's just split up from her boyfriend.
That's right, innit?
Maybe.
And she's in your house.
Yes?
And you get on very well.
Yes.
Well, isn't this perhaps
a nice opportunity to
- slip her one?
- Spike, for God's sake. She's in trouble.
Just get a grip.
Right, you think it's the wrong moment,
fair enough.
Do you mind if I have a go?
- Spike!
- Right, okay.
I'll talk to you in the morning.
Okay. Might be too late, but okay.
Please, sod off.
- Okay, sorry.
- No.
No, no, no, wait,
I thought you were someone else.
I thought you were Spike.
I'm thrilled that you're not.
Wow.
What?
Nothing.
It does strike me as, well, surreal
that I'm allowed to see you naked.
You and every person in this country.
God, yeah, I'm sorry.
What is it about men and nudity?
Particularly breasts.
And how can you be so interested in them?
- Well...
- No, but seriously. They're just breasts.
Every second person in the world has them.
Well, more than that, actually,
when you think about it.
You know, Meatloaf has a very nice pair.
But they're odd looking. They're for milk.
Your mother has them.
You've seen a thousand of them.
What's all the fuss about?
Actually, I can't think what it is, really.
Let me just have a quick look.
No, no, beats me.
Rita Hayworth used to say,
"They go to bed with Gilda,
they wake up with me."
Who was Gilda?
Her most famous part.
Men went to bed with the dream,
and they didn't like it
when they woke up with reality.
Do you feel that way?
You are Iovelier this morning
than you have ever been.
I'll be right back.
Breakfast in bed.
Or it's brunch, or lunch, or something.
My God.
Can I stay a bit longer?
Stay forever.
Okay.
I forgot the jam.
I'll get the jam, you get the door.
Jesus Christ.
What?
What is it?
- Nothing, really.
- You're up to something.
Anna, no, please.
Oh, my God.
And they got a picture of you
dressed like that.
Yes.
Undressed like this, yeah.
Morning, darling ones.
It's me. The press are here.
No, there are hundreds of them.
My brilliant plan was not so brilliant.
I know. I know. I know. Just get over here.
Dammit.
- I wouldn't go outside.
- Why not?
Just take my word for it.
How did I look? Not bad. Not at all bad.
Well-chosen briefs, I'd say.
Chicks love grey.
Nice, firm buttocks.
How are you doing?
How do you think I'm doing?
- I don't know what happened.
- Oh, I do.
Your furry friend thought he'd make a buck
or two, telling the papers where I was.
- That's not true.
- Really?
The entire British press got up this morning
and thought,
"I know where Anna Scott is.
"She's in that house with the blue door
in Notting Hill."
And then you go out
in your goddamn underwear.
- I went out in my goddamn underwear, too.
- Get out.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
This is such an unbelievable mess.
I come to you to protect myself
against more crappy gossip,
and now I've just landed in it all over again.
I mean, for God's sake, I've got a boyfriend.
You have?
Well, as far as they're concerned I do. Yes.
And now, tomorrow, there'll be pictures
of you in every newspaper
from here to Timbuktu.
I know that. But let's stay calm.
- No, you can stay calm!
- Right.
All right,
this is a perfect situation for you, isn't it?
Minimum input, maximum publicity.
Everywhere you go people will say,
"Oh, well done. You slept with that actress.
"We saw the pictures."
That is spectacularly unfair.
Who knows, maybe it'll even help business.
"Buy a boring book about Egypt
from the guy that screwed Anna Scott."
Now, stop. Stop. Stop, I beg you.
Calm down.
- Have a cup of tea.
- I don't want a goddamn cup of tea.
I just wanna go home.
Spike, see who that is.
And put some clothes on, for God's sake.
Looks like a chauffeur to me.
Spike owes you an expensive dinner.
Or holiday.
Depending if he's got the brains
to get the going rate on betrayal.
That is not true. Wait a minute.
This is crazy behaviour.
Can't we just laugh about all this?
Seriously, in the huge sweep of things,
this stuff doesn't matter.
What he's gonna say next is
there's people starving in the Sudan.
Well, there are. And we don't have to go
anywhere near that far.
My best friend slipped.
She slipped down stairs, cracked her back,
and she's in a wheelchair
for the rest of her life.
You know, all I'm asking for
is a normal amount of perspective.
You're right. Of course, you're right.
It's just that I've dealt
with this garbage for 10 years.
You've had it for 10 minutes.
Our perspectives are very different.
I mean, today's newspapers will be
lining tomorrow's wastepaper bins.
Excuse me?
Well, you know, it's just one day.
Tomorrow, today's papers
will all have been thrown out.
You really don't get it.
This story will be filed.
Every time anyone writes
anything about me,
they'll dig up these photos.
Newspapers last forever.
I'll regret this forever.
Right.
I will feel the opposite, if that's okay by you.
And always be glad that you came to stay.
But...
You're probably right. You'd better go.
Was it you?
I may have told a few people down the pub.
Right.
Have I got something for you.
Something which will
make you love me so much,
you will want to hug me every day
for the rest of my life.
Blimey, what is it?
Phone number of Anna Scott's agent
in London and her agent in New York.
Listen, you think about her all the time.
Now you can ring her.
Yeah. Brilliant, thanks.
I'll see you tonight. Hi, Marty. Sexy cardi.
Hello. I have a little speech to make.
I won't stand up
because I can't be bothered.
Exactly a year ago today,
this man here started
the finest restaurant in London.
- Hear, hear.
- Thank you very much.
Unfortunately, no one ever came to eat here.
It's a tiny hiccough.
And so, we have to face the fact that
from next week,
we must find somewhere new to eat.
I just want to say to Tony,
don't take it personally.
The more I think about things,
the more I see no rhyme or reason in life.
No one knows why some things work out
and some things don't.
Why some of us get lucky, and some of us...
- Get fired.
- What?
Yeah, well, it seems
they're shifting the whole outfit
much more towards the emerging markets.
And of course, well, I was total crap, so...
A toast to Bernie,
the worst stockbroker in the whole world.
I thank you.
And Tony, the worst restaurateur.
- Tony and Bernie. Both crap.
- The terrible two.
In their own special ways.
Since it's an evening of announcements,
I've also got one.
I've decided to get engaged.
I've found myself a nice,
slightly odd-looking bloke.
Who I know is gonna make me happy
for the rest of my life.
Well, wait a sec. I mean...
I'm your brother.
I don't know anything about this.
Is he...
I don't know, is he financially viable?
He's an artist with brilliant prospects.
This is a secret
you've been keeping from me?
No. No. I swear.
By the way, it's you.
Me?
What do you think?
Well, yeah.
Groovy.
Excuse me,
are there any more announcements?
Well, actually, yes.
I feel I should apologise to everyone
for my behaviour over the last six months.
I have, as you know,
been somewhat down in the mouth.
Well, there's an understatement.
There are dead people on better form.
But I just wish to make it clear
that I've turned a corner,
and henceforward
intend to be impressively happy.
Oh, God, I'm horribly drunk.
Me, too.
Come here.
So you've laid the ghost?
I believe I have.
Don't give a damn about the famous girl?
No. No, I don't think I do.
Which means you won't be distracted by
the fact that she's back in London,
grasping her Oscar,
and currently to be found filming,
most days, on Hampstead Heath.
Oh, God, no.
So, not over her, in fact.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah.
I'm looking for Anna Scott.
- Does she know you're coming?
- No.
No, she doesn't.
I'm afraid I can't let you through, sir.
Right. I mean, I am actually a friend.
I'm not a lunatic.
- But no, you basically...
- Can't let you through, sir.
Well, this is...
I only found out you were here yesterday.
- Well, I was going to call, but I...
- Anna.
Yes.
Things aren't going very well
and it's our last day.
Absolutely, yeah, you're clearly very busy.
But if you could wait,
there are things to say.
Okay.
Drink tea. There's lots of tea.
Come and have a look.
Are you a fan of Henry James?
- This is a Henry James film?
- Yeah.
This is Harry.
He'll give you a pair of headphones,
so you can hear the dialogue.
- Thank you very much.
- No problem.
- Hi.
- Hi, here we go. Volume's on the side.
- There. Have a seat.
- Thank you.
We are living in cloud cuckoo land.
We'll never get this done today.
Well, we've got to.
I have to be in New York on Thursday.
Stop showing off.
God, that's an enormous arse.
I'm not listening.
No, but seriously, it's not fair.
So many tragic young teenagers
with anorexia,
and that girl has an arse she could
perfectly well share around
with at least 10 other women,
and still be big bottomed.
I would think,
looking at something nice like that,
you and your bony little excuse for an arse
would be well advised to keep quiet.
Now, down to business,
the end of the scene.
I ask you when you're telling everyone,
and you say...
"Tomorrow will be soon enough."
And then I... Right, okay.
So who was that rather diffident chap
I saw you talking to round the back?
No one.
Just some guy from the past.
It's a bit of an awkward situation really.
I don't know what he's doing here.
Of course.
- Thanks, I've got to...
- Any time.
Ladies and gentlemen, can we have
you all on your first marks, please.
On your first marks.
I do hate to disturb you
whilst you're cooking the books,
but there's a delivery for you.
Martin, really, can't you just do it yourself?
But you see, this is not for the shop.
This is for you.
Right, okay.
Now tell me, if I employed a wet rag,
would I have to pay it as much as I pay you?
Hi.
Hello.
You disappeared.
Yeah. Yeah, I had to leave.
I didn't want to disturb.
How have you been?
Fine. Fine.
I don't know, everything much the same,
you know.
When they change the law,
Spike and I will marry immediately.
Whereas you, I've watched in wonder.
Awards, glory.
Oh, no, it's all nonsense, believe me.
I'd no idea how much nonsense it was,
but nonsense it all is.
Well, yesterday was our last day of filming,
so I'm leaving.
But...
I brought this for you from home.
So I thought I'd give it to you.
Thank you.
- Shall I...
- Oh, no, don't open it now,
I'll be embarrassed.
Well, thank you. I don't know
what it's for, but thanks anyway.
I actually had it in my apartment.
I thought you...
But when it came to it,
I didn't know how to call,
having behaved so badly.
Twice.
So it's just been sitting in the hotel.
Then you came, and I figured...
The thing is...
What? What is the thing?
Don't even think about it.
Go away, immediately. Go away.
Right. Sorry.
You were saying?
Yes.
I have to go away today,
but I wondered if I didn't,
whether you might let me see you a little,
or a lot, maybe.
See if you could like me again.
But yesterday that actor asked you
who I was
and you just dismissed me out of hand.
I heard.
You had a microphone, I had headphones.
What, you expect me
to tell the truth about my life
to the most indiscreet man in England?
Excuse me. It's your mother on the phone.
Will you tell her I'll ring her back, please?
I've actually tried that tack,
but she said you've said that once before,
and it's now been about 24 hours
and the foot that was purple
is now sort of blackish in colour and...
Right, right, yeah. Perfect timing as ever.
Martin, hold the fort a second.
Yes, all right.
Could I just say, I thought Ghost
was the most wonderful film.
Is that right?
Oh, yes.
I've always wondered
what Patrick Swayze's like in real life.
I can't say that I know Patrick all that well.
What, he wasn't that friendly during filming?
Well, I'm sure he was friendly to Demi Moore
who acted with him in Ghost.
Oh, right. Sorry.
Right. Always been a bit of an ass.
Anyway, well, it was lovely to meet you.
I'm a huge fan of yours.
And Demi's of course.
Sorry about that.
That's fine.
There's always a pause when the jury
goes out to consider their verdict.
Anna, look...
I'm a fairly level-headed bloke.
Not often in and out of love. But...
Can I just say "no" to your kind request,
and leave it at that?
Yes.
Fine. Of course, I...
Of course.
Well, I'll just be going then.
It was nice to see you.
The thing is, with you I'm in real danger.
It seems like a perfect situation,
apart from that foul temper of yours.
But my relatively inexperienced heart
would, I fear, not recover
if I was once again cast aside,
as I would absolutely expect to be.
There are just too many pictures of you,
too many films.
You know, you'd go,
and I'd be well-buggered, basically.
That really is a real "no," isn't it?
I live in Notting Hill.
You live in Beverly Hills.
Everyone in the world knows who you are.
My mother has trouble
remembering my name.
Fine.
Fine. Good decision.
Good decision.
The fame thing isn't really real, you know.
And don't forget,
I'm also just a girl
standing in front of a boy,
asking him to love her.
Bye.
So, what do you think? Good move?
Yeah, good move.
I mean, when all's said and done,
she's nothing special.
I saw her taking her trousers down
and I definitely glimpsed
some cellulite down there.
Good decision, yeah.
All actresses are as mad as snakes.
Tones, what do you reckon?
Never met her, never want to.
Brilliant. Max?
Absolutely. Never trust a vegetarian.
Great. Thanks. Brilliant.
I was called and I came. What's up?
William's just turned down Anna Scott.
You daft prick.
No, no. No, no, it's actually quite sensible.
That painting isn't the original, is it?
You know, I think it might be, yeah.
But she said
she wanted to go out with you?
Yeah.
Well, that's nice.
What?
Well, you know,
anyone saying they wanna go out with you
is pretty great, isn't it?
It was sort of sweet, actually.
I mean, I know she's an actress and all that,
so she can deliver a line,
but she said she might be
as famous as she can be
but also that she was just a girl,
standing in front of a boy,
asking him to love her.
Oh, sod a dog.
I've made the wrong decision, haven't I?
Max, how fast is your car?
Good luck.
If anyone gets in our way,
we have small nuclear devices.
- Where to?
- The Ritz. All I can think is The Ritz.
- Where's Bella?
- She's not coming.
- Oh, sod that.
- What?
Bernie, sit in the back.
Max, I'm okay.
Come on, baby.
Mind your back.
Which way are you going?
Down Kensington Church Street,
- then Knightsbridge, then Hyde Park Corner.
- No, no, crazy. Crazy.
- Go along Bayswater.
- That's right. Then Park Lane.
No. No. Straight down
to the Cromwell Road, then left.
No!
Stop right there!
I will decide the route. All right?
Sorry, Max.
James Bond never has to put up
with this sort of shit.
- Turn right. Turn right!
- I can't, it's one way.
- Well, do a U-turn.
- Oh, sod it.
Hold on!
- Brilliant!
Bloody hell, this is fun.
Hi. Is Miss Scott staying here?
- No, sir.
- How about Miss Flintstone?
No, sir.
- Bambi?
- No, sir.
Or, I don't know, Beavis or Butt-head?
No, sir.
Thanks. Thanks.
There was a Miss Pocahontas,
but she checked out about an hour ago.
I believe she's holding a press conference
at the Savoy, before flying to America.
We have lift off.
You have message for Takiama?
I'll just check, sir.
Bugger this for a bunch of bananas.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Go. Go.
Hang on. Come on. Wait there!
Come on, come on! Wait!
Go on, go, go, go!
You're my hero!
Down, boy.
Go!
- Excuse me.
- Yes, sir?
Where's the press conference, please?
Are you an accredited member of the press?
Yeah.
There you go.
Yes, that's a Blockbuster Video
membership card, sir.
That's right.
I work for their in-house magazine.
Movies Are Our Business.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- He's with me.
And you are?
Writing an article on how London hotels
treat people in wheelchairs.
Yes, of course, madam.
It's in the Lancaster Room,
though I'm afraid you're rather late.
Run!
Does this mean that Miss Scott
will not be publicising her next ﬁlm?
No, it absolutely does not mean that.
She'll be abiding
by all her present commitments.
She just won't be making any more
for the next year.
When will the ﬁlm be released?
At the moment, the plan is to release
in America towards the end of the autumn,
and over here, around Christmas,
or early in the New Year.
Right! Dominic.
Anna, how much longer are you staying
in the UK then?
No time at all. I leave tonight.
Which is why we have to round things up
now, so final questions, please.
Yes, lady there.
Is your decision to take a year off
anything to do with the rumours about Jeff
and his present leading lady?
Absolutely not.
Do you believe the rumours?
Well, it's really not my business any more.
Though, I will say, from my experience,
rumours about Jeff do tend to be true.
Yeah.
The last time you were here,
there were some fairly graphic photographs
taken of you with a young English guy.
So, what happened there?
He was just a friend.
We're still friends, I think.
Right. Yes, gentleman in the pink shirt.
Yes.
Miss Scott,
are there any circumstances in which
the two of you might be
more than just good friends?
I hoped there would be,
but no, I'm assured there aren't.
- But what would you say if...
- I'm sorry, just the one question, please.
No, it's all right. You were saying?
I was just wondering if it turned out
that this person...
Thacker. His name's Thacker.
Thanks. Thanks.
I just wondered whether
if Mr. Thacker realised
he'd been a daft prick
and got down on his knees
and begged you to reconsider,
whether you would,
in fact, then reconsider?
Yes, I believe I would.
That's very good news.
The readers of Horse & Hound
will be absolutely delighted.
Right, Dominic, if you'd like to ask
your question again?
Yeah.
Anna, how long are you intending
to stay here in Britain?
Indefinitely.
- What happened?
- It was good.
Are you gonna get married?