No matter what they say,
it's all about money.
Imagine that you're
a savings and loan officer.
Watch. One, two, three. See?
You've got it all,
and we've got nothin'.
You have all four. Take a look.
Ah!
I wouldn't trust you with real gold.
That's why this is only worth a penny.
If you wonder where
the other one went, watch.
A penny from the ear.
How much for the rest?
Have you seen Edward?
No. Great party, Philip.
My wife went to a lot of trouble.
She called the caterer.
Howard, how are you?
Edward's taking over Morse Industries?
He's not here to get tan.
Can I get in on it?
Yeah. Just call me.
When?
Hi. I'm Philip Stuckey,
Edward Lewis's lawyer.
Where's the guest of honour?
I don't know.
He's probably in a corner charming
a very pretty lady. How are you?
I told my secretary to make the
arrangements. Didn't she call you?
Yes, she did. I speak to
your secretary more than I speak to you.
I see.
I have my own life too, Edward.
This is a very important week
for me. I need you here.
You never give me any notice.
You think I'm at your beck and call.
I do not believe that you are
at my beck and call.
That's the way you make me feel.
Maybe I should move out.
If that's what you want.
When you get back, we'll discuss it.
Now is as good a time as any.
That's fine with me. Goodbye.
Goodbye, Jessica.
Phil suggested that I...
Phil is just my lawyer, OK?
How did the Morse stock open
on the Nikkei?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Tokyo opened 90 minutes ago.
You have to keep on top of it.
Hello, Mr Lewis.
How you doing?
I want this done as soon as possible.
I gotta get to New York.
I got tickets to The Met.
Your coat, Mr Lewis.
Thank you.
Edward.
Susan.
Hi.
I was sorry to hear about Carter.
Thanks.
I heard you got married.
Well...
Yeah, I couldn't wait for you.
Mm.
Tell me something.
Yes.
When you and I were dating,
did you speak to my secretary
more than you spoke to me?
She was
one of my bridesmaids.
Oh.
Your husband's
a lucky guy. Bye.
Thanks. Bye.
Do you?
Absolutely.
He's leaving.
Edward's leaving.
Excuse me.
Sure.
Is this Mr Stuckey's?
Where are you going?
You got the keys to your car?
What's wrong with the limo?
The limo is buried.
Darryl can't get it out.
Please give me the keys.
I don't think you should drive.
You're excited.
Don't drive my car.
What kind of a system is this?
Can you move these cars out of here?
Look, Edward... Edward.
Are you familiar
with a stick shift?
Yeah.
Just be ginger with it.
It's a new car.
I can do it.
Edward!
Give me a break, please.
I love this car.
I love it too. You don't know where
you're going. You're gonna get lost.
Beverly Hills
is down the hill!
♪ I don't need
to fall at your feet
♪ Just 'cause you cut me
to the bone
♪ And I won't miss
the way that you kiss me
Shit.
♪ We were never carved in stone
♪ If I don't listen
to the talk of the town
♪ Then maybe
I can fool myself
♪ I'll get over you
I know I will
♪ I'll pretend
my ship's not sinking
♪ I'll tell myself
I'm over you
♪ 'Cause I'm the king
of wishful thinking ♪
What do you say, Blondie?
Hi, honey, want some fun?
Hey, you lookin' for a date?
Yeah, we're looking.
Here I am.
I'm Al. This is my friend, Joe.
♪ Well, I'm just out of school
Like I'm real, real cool
♪ Gotta dance like a fool
♪ Got the message that
I gotta be a wild one
♪ Ooh, yeah, I'm a wild one
♪ Gonna break it loose
Gonna keep 'em movin' wild
♪ Gonna keep a swinging baby
I'm a real wild child
Wait a minute.
You don't seem to understand.
That's my job. At the end of the month,
I collect everybody's rent.
Now, gimme the money,
or you're out of here.
♪ Gonna meet all my friends
Gonna have ourselves a ball
♪ Gonna tell my friends
Gonna tell them all
♪ That I'm a wild one
♪ Ooh, yeah, I'm a wild one
♪ Gonna break it loose
Gonna keep 'em moving wild
♪ Gonna keep a swinging baby
I'm a real wild child
♪ I'm a real wild one
And I like a wild fun
♪ In a world gone crazy
Everything seems hazy
♪ I'm a wild one
♪ Ooh, yeah, I'm a wild one
♪ Gonna break it loose
Gonna keep 'em movin' wild
♪ Gonna keep a swinging baby
I'm a real wild child ♪
Welcome to Hollywood!
Everybody comes to Hollywood
got a dream.
What's your dream?
Hey, mister, hey!
Have a good one.
What happened?
Some chick bought it over there.
Detective Albertson.
What do you know about that girl?
I don't know who she hang with.
Come on. We just pulled her out
of a Dumpster. Who was her pimp?
Cocaine her pimp.
She a strawberry.
She be out on these streets,
day in, day out,
trading her sorry self
for some crack.
And what do you do?
I cool.
I'll bet.
Hey, excuse me. Excuse me.
Are you from the press?
No, we're from Orlando.
I don't believe this. I got
tourists photographing the body.
♪ In a world that
can be so insane
♪ I don't think it's
very strange
♪ For me to be
in love with you
♪ I wanna know more
than your brain
Hey, Pops, has Kit been in here?
Upstairs in the poolroom.
♪ ...I expected
Now I smile for your affection
♪ We have made
a soul connection
♪ Just for whom
does your bell toll
♪ Don't be cold
Show me your soul ♪
Yo, Viv.
Is it all gone?
Carlos, my roommate, Vivian.
This is Angel.
I know everybody.
Is it all gone, Kit?
Carlos sold me some great shit.
We had this party. I was hostess.
I can't believe you bought drugs
with our rent. What's going on?
I needed a little pick-me-up.
We need rent money.
Calm down, chica.
She only owes me 200 more.
Carlos!
Another $200?
That was from way before.
That's right, 200, Vivian.
But if you want to work off
her money with me,
we can work something out.
That's a sweet offer, but not now.
Come downstairs.
Work out what?
What are we working out?
You really like her?
You took it while
I was sleeping?
You were unavailable
for consultation.
Let's go.
Snack. Snack.
Besides, it's my apartment.
I have to live there too.
You came here, I gave you money
and a place to stay
and some valuable
vocational advice.
He was on my case. I had to give him
something, so don't irritate me.
This ain't a buffet, Kit.
Irritate you?
I just saw a girl
pulled out of a Dumpster.
I know, Skinny Marie.
But she was a flake.
She was a crackhead.
Dominic tried to straighten her out.
Don't you want to get out of here?
Get out of where?
Where the fuck
you want to go?
Nothin' but garbage.
Excuse me. Can you tell me
how to get to Beverly Hills?
You're here.
That's Sylvester Stallone's
house right there.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hey, yo, Rachel.
What?
You see the stars on the sidewalk?
Yeah.
Well, Vivian and me, we work Bob Hope,
we work the Ritz Brothers,
We work Fred Astaire. We work
all the way down to Ella Fitzgerald.
This is our turf. We got seniority.
You better get off of our corner.
Forgive me.
I was just taking a rest.
Besides, she's new.
Yeah, well, I'm old.
So go rest up by Monty Hall
or Esther Wilson.
Williams.
Esther Williams.
Back off, Kit. You're really
becoming a grouch.
Am I really a grouch?
Yes.
Sometimes.
Well, just 'cause I'm hungry.
I'm gonna get something to eat.
Hey, girls!
Hey, yo, baby.
How about a freebie? It's my birthday.
Dream on.
It's looking
really slow tonight.
Yeah, well... Maybe we
should get a pimp, you know.
Carlos really digs you.
And then he'll run our lives
and take our money. No.
You're right. We say who,
we say when, we say how much.
Do you think I look
like Carol Channing?
I love this look.
It's very glamorous.
Glamour choice.
Oh, yo. Oh, yo.
Catch this.
Wait a minute.
That's a Lotus Esprit.
No, that's rent.
You should go for him.
You look hot.
Don't take less than 100. Call me
when you're through. Take care of you.
Take care of you.
Work it. Work it, baby. Work it.
Work it. Own it.
Yes, you can handle this.
First is here somewhere.
Hey, sugar,
you looking for a date?
No, Beverly Hills.
Can you give me directions?
Sure. For five bucks.
Ridiculous.
Price just went up to ten.
You can't charge me for directions.
I can do anything I want to.
I ain't lost.
All right. OK.
All right. You win. I lose.
Got change for a 20?
For 20, I'll show you personal.
Show you where the stars live.
I've already been to Stallone's.
Right. Down the street.
Lights. Lights would be good.
This is a hot car.
It's a little temperamental.
Yours?
No, it isn't.
Stolen?
Not exactly.
What's your name?
What do you want it to be?
Vivian.
My name is Vivian.
So, what hotel you staying at?
The Regent Beverly Wilshire.
Down the block, right at the corner.
Man, this baby must corner
like it's on rails.
Beg your pardon?
Doesn't it blow your mind?
This is only four cylinders.
You know cars. Where's that from?
Road & Track.
Boys back home I grew up with
were really into Mustangs, Corvettes.
They bought 'em, fixed them up.
I paid attention.
So, how is it you know
so little about cars?
My first car
was a limousine.
So, where is this...
...heavy metal home?
Milledgeville, Georgia.
I think you left
your transmission back there.
You're not shifting right.
This is a standard H.
Standard H? Like I know
what that means.
You ever driven a Lotus?
No.
You're gonna start right now.
You're joking.
No, it's the only way
I can get you off my coat.
Fasten your seat belt. I'm taking you
for the ride of your life.
I'll show you
what this car can do.
Are you ready?
Hang on. Here we go.
This has pedals like a race car.
They're close together.
It's probably easier for a woman
to drive, 'cause they have little feet.
Except me.
I wear a size 9.
You know your foot's as big as your arm
from your elbow to your wrist?
Did you know that?
No, I didn't know that.
It's a little bit of trivia.
Tell me, what kind of money
do you girls make these days?
Ballpark.
Can't take less $100.
Hundred dollars a night?
For an hour.
An hour?
You make $100 an hour,
and you got a safety pin
holding your boot up?
You gotta be joking.
I never joke about money.
Neither do I.
Hundred dollars an hour.
Pretty stiff.
Well, no, but it's
got potential.
Good evening, Mr Lewis.
Will you be needing the car tonight?
I hope not.
Ah, we're here.
Yeah.
So, you'll be all right?
Yeah, I'm gonna grab a cab
with my 20 bucks.
Go back to your office.
Yeah.
My office. Yeah.
Well, thanks for the ride.
See you.
Goodbye.
No taxis?
No, I like the bus.
I was thinking, did you
really say $100 an hour?
Yeah.
Well, if you don't have
any prior engagements,
I'd be very pleased
if you'd accompany me
into the hotel.
You got it.
What is your name?
Edward.
That's my favourite name
in the whole world.
No.
I tell you what, this is fate, Edward.
That's what this is.
Why don't you put this on?
Why?
Well...
This hotel is not an establishment
that rents rooms by the hour.
Ah.
Wow.
It's all right.
Holy shit.
You're gonna be fine.
Come with me.
And stop fidgeting.
Good evening, Mr Lewis.
Hello. You have messages?
Yes, several.
Could you send up
champagne and strawberries?
Of course.
Room service
for Mr Lewis, please.
Oh, honey.
You know what's happened?
I've got a runner in my pantyhose.
I'm not wearing pantyhose.
Well, colour me happy.
There's a sofa in here for two.
First time in an elevator.
Ah.
Close your mouth, dear.
Sorry. Couldn't help it.
Try.
Penthouse.
The penthouse. Ooh.
Yes.
To the left.
I miss keys.
You impressed?
You kidding?
I come here all the time.
They do rent this by the hour.
Sure.
Wow. Great view.
I bet you can see all the way
to the ocean from out here.
I'll take your word for it.
I don't go out there.
Why don't you
go out there?
I'm afraid of heights.
You are?
How come you rented
the penthouse?
It's the best.
I looked for penthouses on
the first floor, but I can't find one.
Well, now that you
have me here,
what are you going
to do with me?
You want to know something?
I don't have a clue.
No?
I hadn't exactly planned this.
Well, do you plan everything?
Always.
Yeah, me too.
I'm actually... No, I'm not
a planner. I wouldn't say I was.
I would say I was a kind of
fly by the seat of my pants gal.
You know, moment to moment.
That's me.
That's... Yeah.
You know, you could pay me.
That's one way to break the ice.
Oh, yeah, I'm sorry.
Uh, I assume cash is acceptable.
Cash works for me. Yeah.
You're on my fax.
Well, that's one
I haven't been on before.
Very cute. Thank you.
All right, here we go.
Pick one.
I got red, green, yellow.
I'm out of purple, but I do have
one gold circle coin left.
The condom of champions,
the one and only.
Nothing is getting through
this sucker. What do you say?
A buffet of safety.
I'm a safety girl.
Let's get one of these on you.
No.
Why don't we talk
for a little bit.
Talk.
Yeah, um, OK.
Edward, are you in town
on business or pleasure?
Business, I think.
Business, you think.
Well...
Let me guess.
That would make you...
A lawyer.
A lawyer?
What makes you think
I'm a lawyer?
You've got that sharp
useless look about you.
I bet you've known
a lot of lawyers.
I've known a lot of everybody.
What is that?
Champagne.
Oh.
Well, might as well
make myself useful.
Take a load off.
Good evening.
Hi.
Where would you like it?
Where would we like it?
Over by the bar.
Excuse me.
It'll be on your bill, Mr Lewis.
Thank you.
What are you looking at?
What is he looking at?
Ah, yes.
Here you go.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, sir.
Have a nice night.
Tip. Wow.
I missed that one.
Don't worry about it.
You mind if I take my boots off?
Not at all.
So, do you have a wife?
Girlfriend?
I have both.
Where are they?
Shopping together?
My ex-wife is now
in Long Island,
in my ex-home
with my ex-dog.
There you go.
My ex-girlfriend, Jessica,
is in New York,
moving out of my apartment
even as we speak.
You should try a strawberry.
Why?
It brings out the flavour
in the champagne.
Oh. Groovy.
Pretty good.
Don't you drink?
No.
Listen, I-I appreciate this whole
seduction scene you got going,
but let me give you a tip.
I'm a sure thing, OK?
I'm on an hourly rate.
Can we move it along?
I'm sensing that this time problem
IS a major issue with you.
Why don't we get through that now?
Let's get started.
How much for the entire night?
Stay here?
You couldn't afford it.
Try me.
Three hundred dollars.
Done.
Thank you.
Now we can relax.
I'll be out in a minute.
That champagne got to me.
What did you say?
I said I'd be out in just a minute.
What is... What do you have?
What are you hiding?
Nothing.
All right, I do not want
any drugs here.
I don't want this.
Get your money and please leave.
I don't do drugs. I stopped
doing drugs when I was 14.
What is this?
This is dental floss.
Yeah? So?
I had all those
strawberry seeds.
And you shouldn't
neglect your gums.
I'm sorry.
Please, continue.
Thank you.
Are you gonna watch?
No, I'm going.
Thank you.
It's just that, uh,
very few... people surprise me.
You're lucky. Most of them
shock the hell out of me.
You're watching.
I'm going.
Yes, that may be true.
I still need the numbers
on Morse Industries.
Uh-huh.
I got them from London.
I need them from Tokyo.
I'll call down and get them
when I want them.
Thank you very much.
I have a little
carpet picnic here.
Are you sure you
don't want a drink?
I'm high on life.
Can't you tell?
You know,
I never saw this episode.
What do you want?
What do you do?
Everything.
But I don't kiss on the mouth.
Neither do I.
Hey, how you doing?
Good, thank you.
Good morning.
Morning, Mr Thompson.
Good morning, sir.
Morning, Marjorie.
Morse is going to fight.
It's to be expected.
He's run his company
for a long time.
He's not ready to have
his name taken off the stationery.
He wants to meet you
face-to-face.
OK.
I wouldn't do it.
You wouldn't, but do it anyhow.
Tonight. Dinner.
Oh, Edward, it's really not
a good idea that you see him,
definitely not alone.
He's a feisty old guy.
We say the wrong thing,
we could wind up in court.
There's always a possibility
things'll go wrong.
That's why I enjoy this so much.
By the way, Phil, about your car...
Oh, God, what?
It corners like it's on rails.
What? What does that mean?
Edward? Edward?
Hi.
Well, good morning.
Red.
Better.
You didn't wake me.
I can see you're really busy.
I'll be out in a minute.
There's no hurry.
Are you hungry?
You must be.
Why don't you sit
and have something to eat?
I...
...took the liberty
of ordering everything.
I didn't know
what you'd like.
Thanks.
All right? Good.
Did you sleep well?
Yeah. Too good.
Forgot where I was.
Occupational hazard?
Yeah.
Did you sleep?
Uh, yes, a little
on the couch.
I was, uh, working last night.
You don't sleep, you don't do drugs,
you don't drink.
You hardly eat.
What do you do, Edward?
'Cause I know you're not a lawyer.
That's right.
There are
four other chairs here.
Oh.
So, what do you do?
I buy companies.
What kind of companies?
Well, I buy companies that are
in financial difficulty.
If they have problems,
you must get a bargain.
Well, the company
I'm buying this week
I'm getting for the bargain
price of about one billion.
A billion dollars?
Yes.
Wow. You must be
really smart, huh?
I only got through
eleventh grade.
How far did you go
in school?
I went all the way.
Your folks must be
really proud, huh?
So, you don't actually have
a billion dollars, huh?
No, I get some of it
from banks, investors.
It's not an easy thing to do.
You don't make anything and
you don't build anything?
What do you do with the companies?
I sell them.
Here, let me do that.
You sell them?
Well, I don't sell
the whole company.
I break it up into pieces
and sell that.
If it's worth more than the whole.
So, it's like, um...
stealing cars and selling them
for the parts?
Yeah, sort of. But legal.
Mm-hm.
There. Now it's perfect.
Not bad. Not bad at all.
Where'd you learn to do that?
Well, I screwed
the debate team in high school.
I had a grandpa.
He was nice to me.
He liked ties on Sundays.
Mind if I take a swim
in your tub before I go?
Not at all. Just stay
in the shallow end.
Hello?
It's Phil. I wanted to let you know
Morse is set for tonight.
That's good.
He's bringing his grandson.
He's grooming him to take over.
Oh, yes. A very intense
young man named David.
Plays polo.
Look, I gotta say this again.
I don't like you going alone.
♪ I just want your extra time
I just think it would be
better if you went with a date.
Keep it social.
♪ You got to not talk dirty, baby
You hear me?
Yes, I'm here.
What is that?
♪ If you want to impress me
Housekeeping is singing.
♪ You can't be too flirty, mama
♪ I know how to undress me
I know a lot of nice girls.
No, you don't.
♪ I just want your extra time
and your
♪ Kiss
Besides, I already have one.
♪ If you want to impress me
Find out what Morse is up to.
♪ You can't be too flirty, mama
I'm on my way.
♪ I know how to undress me
♪ Mm, yeah, baby
♪ I want to be your fantasy
♪ Well, maybe
you could be mine
♪ Mm-hm you just leave it
all up to me ♪
Don't you just love Prince?
More than life itself.
Don't you knock?
Vivian, I have a business
proposition for you.
What do you want?
I'm gonna be in town until Sunday.
I'd like you
to spend the week with me.
Really?
Yes.
Yes, I'd like to hire you
as an employee.
Would you consider
spending the week with me?
I will pay you to be
at my beck and call.
I'd love to be your
"beck and call" girl, but...
...you're a rich,
good-looking guy.
You could get
a million girls free.
I want a professional.
I don't need any
romantic hassles this week.
If you're talking 24 hours
a day, it's gonna cost you.
Ohh. Yes, of course.
All right. Here we go.
Give me a ballpark figure.
How much?
Six full nights.
Days too.
Four thousand.
Six nights at 300 is 1800.
You want days too.
Two thousand.
Three thousand.
Done.
Holy shit!
Vivian.
Vivian, is that a yes?
Yes.
Yes!
I'll be gone most of the day.
I want you to buy some clothes.
You should get
traveller's checks.
We may be going out.
You'll need something to wear.
Like what?
Nothing too flashy.
Not too sexy. Conservative.
You understand?
Boring.
Elegant.
Any questions?
Can I call you Eddie?
Not if you
expect me to answer.
I would've stayed
for two thousand.
I would've paid four.
I'll see you tonight.
Baby, I'm gonna
treat you so nice,
you're never gonna
want to let me go.
Three thousand for six days.
And, Vivian, I will let you go.
But I'm here now.
Three thousand dollars!
Ooh.
Hello.
I called and called. Where were you?
Ma?
It's Viv.
Oh, hi. I had to party.
Where are you?
Oh, man,
are you ready for this?
The guy? The Lotus?
I am in his hotel room
in Beverly Hills, the penthouse.
His bathroom is bigger
than the Blue Banana.
Do I have to hear this?
He wants me to stay
the whole week.
You know what he's gonna
give me? You'll never guess.
Three thousand dollars.
Bullshit!
I swear to God,
and extra money to buy clothes.
Oh, man, I am bummed!
I gave that guy to you!
Three thousand. Really?
Is he twisted?
No.
Ugly?
He's good-looking.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Did he give you the money?
At the end of the week.
That's what's wrong.
Well, he gave me 300
for last night, and, Kit,
I'm gonna leave some
at the front desk for you.
I'm at the Regent Beverly
Wilshire. Write it down.
Are you writing it down?
You'll forget it. Write it down.
"Reg. Bev. Wil."
One more thing. Where do I go
for the clothes? Good stuff, on him.
In Beverly Hills?
Yeah.
Rodeo Drive, baby.
Hi.
Yes, ma'am. May I help you?
I'm leavin' this here for Kit De Luca.
She's gonna pick it up.
Don't open that.
No, ma'am.
Miss Wilson, do you know her?
No, sir.
♪ Wild women do
and they don't regret it
♪ Wild women show
what they're goin' through
♪ Oooh
♪ Wild women do
what you'd think they'll never
♪ What you only dream about
wild women do
♪ Oh, yes they do
♪ You tell me you want
a woman who
♪ Is simple as a flower
♪ Well, if you want me
to act like that
♪ You got to pay me
by the hour
♪ Wild women do
and they don't regret it
♪ Wild women show
what they're goin" through
♪ Oooh, yeah
♪ Wild women do what
you'd think they'd never
May I help you?
I'm just checking things out.
Are you looking for
something particular?
No... Well, yeah.
Uh, something conservative.
Yes.
You got nice stuff.
Thank you.
How much is this?
I don't think this would fit you.
Well. I didn't ask if it would fit.
I asked how much it was.
How much is this, Marie?
It's very expensive.
Look, I got money
to spend in here.
I don't think we have
anything for you.
You're obviously
in the wrong place.
Please leave.
Tiffany's taking
the corner space.
We're very excited about
the whole thing.
Do you realise Via Rodeo
is the first new street
in Beverly Hills in 75 years?
Excuse me. May I help you?
I'm going to my room.
Do you have a key?
I forgot that cardboard thing.
I'm on the top floor.
You're a guest here?
I'm with a friend.
Who would that be?
Edward.
Edward?
Edward... uh...
He knows me.
Dennis.
Dennis, did you just
come off the night shift?
Yes, sir.
Do you know this young lady?
She's with Mr Lewis.
Mr Lewis?
That's it. Edward Lewis.
Thanks, Dennis.
Evidently she joined him last night.
Thank you.
Oh, God, what now?
What? What?
What is with everybody?
Come with me and have a chat.
I'm coming.
Thank you, Dennis.
What is your name, miss?
What do you want it to be?
Don't play with me, young lady.
Vivian.
Thank you. Vivian.
Well, Miss Vivian,
things that go on
in other hotels
don't happen at
the Regent Beverly Wilshire.
Mr Lewis, however,
is a very special customer,
and we like to think of our
special customers as friends.
As a customer,
we would expect Mr Lewis
to sign in
any additional guests,
but as a friend,
we're willing to overlook it.
Now, I'm assuming
that you're a...
...relative?
Yes.
I thought so.
Then you must be his...
Niece?
Of course.
Naturally,
when Mr Lewis leaves,
I won't see you
in this hotel again.
I assume you have
no other uncles here?
Then we understand each other.
I encourage you
to dress more appropriately.
That will be all.
That's what I was trying to do.
I tried to go get a dress
on Rodeo Drive today,
and the women wouldn't help me.
I have all this money,
and no dress.
Not that I expect your help,
I have to buy a dress
for dinner tonight.
And nobody will help me.
Oh, man, if you are calling
the cops...
Yeah, call the cops. Great.
Tell them I said hi.
Women's clothing.
Bridget, please.
Bridget, hello.
This is Barnard Thompson
here at the Regent Beverly Wil...
Thank you. Yes, but I'd like you
to do a favour for me, please.
I'm sending someone over.
Her name is Vivian.
She's a special guest.
She's the niece
of a very special guest.
This is the jewel
in Morse's crown.
Prime industrial property
straddling Long Beach and Los Angeles.
Possibilities are endless.
Most of the yard
we'll just level.
I just got the information.
Edward, we just got the Morse update.
Don, can you hold
the projection, please?
Yeah? What?
Speak.
Old man Morse just got the inside track
on a $350 million contract
to build destroyers
for the navy.
Navy contract.
I can't believe this.
I thought you said
they had nothing in the hopper.
I thought they didn't.
That could cost a lot more.
Stocks could go through the roof.
No shit, Sherlock.
Maybe we're lucky to get
this information now, sir.
We can still walk away.
Walk away?
We got a thousand man-hours on this.
Nobody's walking away.
I think he's right.
I don't want to hear it!
Gentlemen, relax. Relax.
Who do we know on the Senate
Appropriations Committee?
Senator Adams.
Senator Adams. Find out where he is.
The navy's not going to spend
$350 million on anything
without going
to Appropriations first.
I don't understand
what's going on.
That's why I hired you,
to do my worrying for me.
I'll be in your office.
Bob, send over the geologicals.
No problem.
Thank you.
Listen, everything all set
for the meeting tonight?
Mm-hm.
Who is this girl you're going with?
Nobody you know.
Edward Lewis Enterprises.
Phil Stuckey.
Yes, I have him right here.
Don't worry, Mrs Ramey.
I'll call you when it comes in.
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
Hello. You must be Vivian.
My name's Bridget.
Yeah, hi. Barney said
you'd be nice to me.
He's very sweet.
What are your plans
while you're in town?
I'm gonna have dinner.
Don't sit there, dear.
You're gonna go out? Dinner?
Mm-hmm.
You'll need a cocktail dress, then.
Come with me.
I'm sure we'll find something
that your uncle would love.
You're a size six, right?
Yeah.
How'd you know that?
That's my job.
Bridge, he's not really my uncle.
They never are, dear.
Barney. Sorry, mister.
I got a dress.
I'd rather hoped you'd be wearing it.
I didn't want to mess it up.
I got shoes. Wanna see?
No, I'm sure they're
quite lovely. Thank you.
I didn't mean to interrupt,
Bridget was great,
and I wanted to say thanks.
You're cool.
You're welcome, Miss Vivian.
Hello.
Never, ever pick up the phone.
Why are you calling me?
Did you buy clothes today?
I got a dress, a cocktail one.
That's good.
I'll be in the hotel lobby
7:45 sharp.
You're not coming to the door?
This isn't a date. It's business.
Where are you taking me?
To a restaurant
called the Voltaire.
Very elegant.
All right.
I'll meet you in the lobby
'cause you're paying me to.
Well, thank you very much.
Get her back for me, please.
Mr Stuckey wanted to see you.
Yes, tell him I'm in the middle
of an important phone call.
Hello.
I told you not to pick up the phone.
Then stop calling me.
Sick.
Barney.
It didn't fit.
Oh, no, no, no.
I've got a little problem.
Right, Miss Vivian, one more time.
Dinner napkin.
Dinner napkin,
laid gently in the lap.
Good. Elbows off the table.
Don't slouch.
Shrimp fork.
Salad fork.
Dinner fork.
I have the salad fork.
The rest of the silverware
is a little confusing.
If you get nervous,
just count the tines.
Four tines, dinner fork.
And sometimes there are three tines.
The salad fork.
And sometimes...
Pardon me, Mr Lewis.
I'm Mr Thompson,
the manager of the hotel.
I want to make one call.
I have a message for you.
From who?
From your niece, sir.
My what?
The lady who's staying
with you in your room.
Oh.
We both know she's not my niece.
Of course.
The reason I know that
is that I am an only child.
Yes, sir.
What's the message?
She's waiting in the lounge.
Intriguing young lady,
Miss Vivian.
Intriguing.
Have a good evening, sir.
Thank you, Mr...
Thompson. I'm the...
...manager of the hotel, sir.
You're late.
You're stunning.
You're forgiven.
Shall we go to dinner?
This way.
Your party's waiting.
Stop fidgeting.
Mr Morse.
Yes, Mr Lewis. I'm Jim Morse.
This fireball
is my grandson, David.
I don't know about fireball,
but grandson's true enough.
I'm pleased to meet you both.
This is Vivian Ward.
I'm glad to meet you.
Mr Morse. David.
Please sit.
Excuse me.
Where are you going?
I'm going to the ladies' room.
Upstairs, to the right.
OK.
Excuse me.
Shall I order for you?
Yeah.
Please do so.
Thank you.
I'll do that.
My grandfather believes men who
create a company control its destiny.
Where's the salad?
The salad comes
at the end of the meal.
But that's the fork I know.
Let me
put it another way.
Between your public statements
and the rumours flying around,
it's hard to figure out
what your intentions are.
I've never been able
to figure which goes with what.
At one time we built
ships the size of cities.
Men like my grandfather
made this country.
Who ordered this?
The gentleman did.
Bon appetit.
These are escargot.
It's French for snails.
It's a delicacy. Try it.
David.
If you were to get control,
and I don't think you will,
but if you did,
what do you plan
to do with the company?
Break it up
and sell off the pieces.
I'm sure you'll understand
I'm not thrilled at the idea
of your turning 40 years
of my work into your garage sale.
At the price I'm paying
for this stock,
you are going to be a very rich man.
I'm rich enough.
I just want to have
my shipyard.
Slippery little suckers.
It happens all the time.
I met your father.
What's his name?
Carter.
Yeah, Carter.
Carter Lewis.
He's not quite the bastard
everybody says he is.
No, I have the franchise on that.
Does that make him proud?
I doubt it.
It doesn't really matter now.
He passed away.
I hadn't heard. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too.
Mr Morse, you asked
for this meeting.
What can I do for you?
Leave my company alone.
I can't do that.
I own ten million shares.
I'll buy your stock back.
You don't have money.
We're getting a contract
to build destroyers.
There will be no contract.
It is now buried in Appropriations,
and it will remain there.
How did you pull that? Do you got...
You got dirty politicians
in your pockets?
Easy.
Calm down, David.
Mr Lewis plays hardball.
Yes, I do.
I've heard enough.
Vivian, it was a pleasure.
I'm sorry.
I've got to get some air.
Mr Lewis.
I'd better join my grandson.
You two enjoy your dinner.
I'm sure it will be delicious.
Good luck, miss.
Watch out, Lewis.
I'm gonna tear you apart.
I look forward to it, sir.
Edward.
You said you never
come out here.
Well, I'm only halfway out.
You didn't say much in the car
on the way home.
You thinking about dinner?
I was a maniac.
I mean, the business was good,
I think.
He's in trouble.
You want his company.
He doesn't want to let it go.
Thanks for the recap.
Problem is,
I think you like Mr Morse.
I would like for you to get down.
You're making me nervous.
It's making you nervous?
What if I just lean back like this?
Would you rescue me if I fell?
Vivian, I'm serious.
I'm not looking.
It's really high.
Look, no hands. No hands.
OK. All right, I'm sorry.
The truth is,
it really is totally irrelevant
whether I like this man or not.
I will not let myself become
emotionally involved in business.
I know.
Kit's always saying to me,
"Don't get emotional
when you turn tricks."
That's why no kissing.
It's too personal.
Like what you're saying.
Stay numb, don't get involved.
When I'm with a guy,
I'm like a robot. I just do it.
I mean... except with you.
Of course, not with me.
You and I are such
similar creatures, Vivian.
We both screw people for money.
I'm sorry to hear
about your dad.
When did he die?
Last month.
Do you miss him?
I hadn't spoken to him
in 14 and a half years.
I wasn't there when he died.
Do you want to talk about this?
No.
Well, I'll tell you what.
"Cause I got an idea.
Let's watch old movies all night.
We'll just veg out
in front of the TV.
"Veg out"?
Yeah.
Be still like vegetables.
Lay like broccoli.
I'll tell you what.
I'll be back.
We'll do broccoli tomorrow.
Where are you going?
Downstairs for awhile.
Did you say marriage license?
Don't change the subject.
Just give me the stamp.
Oh, I love you, Adam,
Alex, Peter, Brian,
whatever your name is.
Oh, I love you.
Hi. I'm in the penthouse.
The guy that was here...
Mr Lewis? Have you
seen him down there anywhere?
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I didn't know you played.
I only play for strangers.
I was getting lonely upstairs,
all by myself.
Gentlemen?
Would you mind
leaving us, please?
Thank you.
People always do
what you tell them to do?
I guess so.
Wake up.
Time to shop.
If you have any trouble using this card,
have them call the hotel.
All right?
More shopping?
Mm-hm.
I'm surprised you didn't buy
more than one dress yesterday.
It wasn't as much fun
as I thought it'd be.
Why not?
They were mean to me.
Mean to you?
People are looking at me.
They're not looking at you.
They're looking at me.
Stores are not nice to people.
I don't like it.
Stores are never nice to people.
They're nice to credit cards.
OK. Stop fidgeting.
Get rid of your gum.
I don't believe you did that.
I am Mr Hollister, the manager.
May I help you?
Edward Lewis.
Yes, sir.
You see this young lady over there?
Yes.
Do you have anything in this shop
as beautiful as she is?
Oh, yes.
Oh, no.
No, no.
I'm saying we have many things
as beautiful as she...
...would want them.
That's the point.
I think we can all
agree with that.
You know what we're
gonna need here?
We're gonna need more people helping us.
I'll tell you why.
We are going to be spending
an obscene amount of money in here.
We're gonna need a lot
more help sucking up to us,
'cause that's what
we really like.
Sir, if I may say so, you're in
the right store, and the right city.
Anything you see here we can do.
Get ready to have fun.
OK.
Mary Pat, Mary Kate,
Mary Francis, let's see it.
This is absolutely divine.
Excuse me, sir.
Exactly how obscene an amount
of money were you talking about?
Profane, or really offensive?
Really offensive.
I like him so much.
Mr Lewis, sir.
How's it going so far?
Pretty well, I think.
I think we need some major sucking up.
Very well, sir.
You're handsome
and powerful.
I could see you were
someone to reckon with...
Hollister?
Yes, sir?
Not me. Her.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm sorry.
How are we doing, ladies?
Edward, where are you?
The word's all over the street.
Morse is gonna raise your offer.
He's countering?
God, he is a tough old bird.
Contracts are stalled.
Where's he getting money?
I think he's throwing in
with the employees.
He needs someone
to underwrite the paper.
Find out.
I'll be in in an hour.
OK. You got it.
You're on your own.
I have to go back to work.
You look great.
She has my card.
And we'll help her use it, sir.
♪ Pretty woman
Walking down the street
The kind I like to meet
♪ Pretty woman
♪ I don't believe you
You're not the truth
♪ No one could look
as good as you
♪ Mercy
Edward would love that.
Give her the tie.
Take it off. Give her the tie.
The tie.
He wants to do this.
He would go crazy for this.
Who ordered pizza?
♪ Pretty woman stop awhile
♪ Pretty woman talk awhile
♪ Pretty woman
give your smile to me
♪ Pretty woman,
yeah, yeah, yeah
♪ Pretty woman look my way
♪ Pretty woman
say you'll stay with me
May I help you?
Hi. Do you remember me?
No, I'm sorry.
I was in here yesterday.
You wouldn't wait on me.
Oh.
You work on commission, right?
Uh, yes.
Big mistake.
Big. Huge.
I have to go shopping now.
♪ Pretty woman
Don't walk on by
Don't make me cry
♪ Pretty woman
♪ Don't walk away
Thank you.
♪ Oh
♪ Pretty woman ♪
Mr Lewis.
Gentlemen.
Let's finish this afternoon.
Jake, set something up
with Blair.
2:00, 2:30 would be good.
You were right about Morse.
He mortgaged everything he owns
to secure a loan
from the bank.
And not just any bank.
Plymouth Trust.
Mm.
So, it goes without saying,
your business means
more to them than Morse.
All you gotta do
is call the bank.
Yeah.
Edward, excuse me
for saying this,
but what is wrong
with you this week?
Are you giving Morse
a chance to get away?
You know what I used to love
when I was a kid, Phil?
What?
Blocks.
Building blocks.
Erector sets.
So, I liked Monopoly.
Boardwalk, Park Place...
What's the point?
We don't build anything.
We don't make anything.
We make money, Edward.
We worked for a year on this.
It's what you said you wanted.
I'm handing it to you.
Morse's jugular is exposed.
It's time for the kill.
Let's finish this.
Call the bank.
How was your day, dear?
Nice tie.
I got it for you.
Well, my mother
was a music teacher...
...and married my father,
whose family was
extremely wealthy.
Then he divorced my mother
to be with another woman.
And he took his money with him.
And then she died.
I was very angry with him.
It cost me $10,000 in therapy
to say that sentence:
"I was very angry with him."
I do it well, don't I?
I'll say it again. I was angry.
Hello, my name is Mr Lewis.
I am very angry with my father.
I would've been angry
at the $10,000.
My father was president
of the third company
I ever took over.
I bought it. I sold it off,
piece by piece.
What did the shrink say?
Said I was cured.
Well, so you got even.
That must've made you happy.
Did I mention my leg
is 44 inches from hip to toe?
So basically,
we're talking about
88 inches of therapy
wrapped around you
for the bargain price...
...of $3,000.
$3,000.
Yeah.
Garbers passes to Keenan.
This is Phil Fricker
giving you play-by-play
of this event.
Watch where you walk, if you step
in something, we're not going back.
And not near the tree.
I don't like the ants. Hello.
Have you seen Edward anywhere?
What if someone recognises me?
Not likely.
They don't spend time
on Hollywood Boulevard.
Come on.
Let go. Let go.
All right. You look great.
You look like a lady.
We're gonna have
a wonderful time.
OK, don't fidget.
And smile.
...coming around the side.
Penalty on that play.
This is Gwen and Gretchen,
the infamous Olsen sisters,
who have made marrying well
an art form.
Edward.
Wait just a sec.
So, you're the flavour
of the month.
Uh, she's just being testy.
Edward's our most
eligible bachelor.
Everybody is trying to land him.
I'm not trying to.
I'm just using him for sex.
Well done.
Well done!
Whoo, whoo, whoo!
Tell me again
why we're here.
Business.
Business mingling?
Yeah.
That's the chukker, ladies and
gentlemen. Falcons 7, Gems 4.
Excuse me. Edward! Edward.
Over here.
Phil.
Good to see you.
I want you to meet a friend, Vivian.
Hi. Philip Stuckey.
This is my wife, Elizabeth.
It's always a pleasure
meeting one of Edward's girls.
Oh, my God.
It's Tate Whitley Wallington.
Tate. It's me, Elizabeth,
from Work Out World.
She's a bit
of an aerobics queen.
Feel the burn.
Let me get you a drink.
Vivian, why don't you start with that?
I'll be right back.
Senator Adams is here.
Mm-hm. I asked him.
That is why I have pledged
my eternal love to you.
Real genuine guy.
Who is he?
He's my lawyer.
He's all right.
You could freeze ice
on his wife's ass.
We'll try that later.
Are these people your friends?
I spend time with them, yeah.
Well, no wonder.
No wonder what?
No wonder why you
came looking for me.
I need help from you ladies
and gentlemen in the audience.
We need help replacing
some divots here on the grass.
So, come on out now.
Come on, come on, folks.
You heard her.
The stomping of the divots.
This is
a time-honoured tradition.
As old as the game
of polo itself.
Kings and queens
used to do this.
She's sweet, Edward.
Wherever did you find her?
Only one word of advice.
Avoid the steaming divot.
It's all part of
the game of polo.
Your shoes are polished
by a member of the club.
I've got something that'll buff that.
Thank you.
Vivian. Hi, David Morse.
Excuse me.
David.
How are you?
I'm OK.
I thought that was you.
I like this hat.
It's new.
Come meet my horse, Vivian.
Edward's waiting for me.
I don't want...
He's right here.
OK, just for a second.
I didn't know
you were playing today.
I was asking for directions.
There she was.
So, you just ran into her?
That's great.
So, what does she do?
Does she work?
She's in sales.
That's terrific. That's good.
What does she sell?
Why do you want to know?
Just hear me out on this, OK?
I've known you a long time.
I see some differences in you
this week, like the tie...
I'm wondering if this girl
is the difference.
Especially when I see her
talking to David Morse.
I introduced them
the other night.
So now they're best friends?
This girl appears from nowhere.
Now she's talking to this guy.
That's a little convenient,
don't you think?
How do you know she hasn't
attached herself to you
and is bringing
information to Morse?
This happens. Industrial espionage.
Phil, Phil.
Listen to me.
She's not a spy.
She is a hooker.
I picked her up
on Hollywood Boulevard.
In your car.
Yes.
You're the only millionaire
I've heard of
who's looking
for a bargain streetwalker.
Edward.
I'm sorry I told you.
Senator. Senator Adams,
I'm pleased you could make it.
I hope the information
I gave you was helpful.
Absolutely.
No change?
No, it's still bogged down.
Having a nice time, Vivian?
Yeah, I'm having a great time.
Must be quite a change
from Hollywood Boulevard.
What?
Edward told me.
Don't worry. Your secret
is safe with me.
Listen, maybe...
...you and I could get together
sometime after Edward leaves.
Yeah, sure.
Why not?
We'll just have to do that, hmm?
Philip.
I'd like to mention
a couple of our silver sponsors,
Jacobs Distributors,
Norell Saddlery,
and we'd like to give a big thanks
to our platinum sponsor,
Edward Lewis Enterprises.
The ball is in
for chukker number four.
Ai ..
You all right?
I'm fine.
Fine? That's good.
Seven "fines" since
we left the match.
Could I have
another word, please?
Asshole. There's a word.
I think I liked "fine" better.
Just tell me one thing.
Why'd you make me
get all dressed up?
For one thing,
the clothing was appropriate.
No. What I mean is, if you were gonna
tell everybody I'm a hooker,
why didn't you let me wear my clothes?
I did not...
In my own clothes, when someone
like Stuckey comes up to me,
I can handle it,
I'm prepared.
I'm very sorry. I'm not happy
with Stuckey at all
for saying that or doing that.
But he is my attorney.
I've known him for ten years.
He thought you were an industrial spy.
The guy's paranoid.
Are you my pimp now?
You think you can pass me around
your friends? I'm not some toy.
You're not my toy.
I know you're not...
Vivian! Vivian, I'm speaking
to you. Come back here.
I hate to point out the obvious,
but you are a hooker.
You are my employee.
You don't own me. I decide.
I say who, I say when,
I say who!
I refuse to spend the next days
fighting with you.
I said I was sorry.
That's the end of it.
I'm sorry I ever met you.
I'm sorry
I got into your stupid car.
As if you had so many more
appealing options.
I've never had anyone make me
feel as cheap as you did today.
Somehow I find that
very hard to believe.
Where are you going?
I want my money.
I want to get out of here.
Come on.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't prepared to answer
questions about us.
That was stupid and cruel.
I didn't mean it.
I don't want you to go.
Will you stay the week?
Why?
I saw you talking
to David Morse.
I didn't like it.
We were just talking.
Down?
You hurt me.
Yes.
Don't do it again.
The first guy I ever loved
was a total nothing.
The second was worse.
My mom called me
a "bum magnet.”
If there was a bum
within 50 miles,
I was completely attracted to him.
That's how I ended up here.
I followed bum number three.
Mm.
So, here I was.
No money, no friends.
No bum.
And you chose this
as your profession?
I worked at a couple
of fast food places.
Parked cars at wrestling.
I couldn't make the rent.
I was too ashamed to go home.
That's when I met Kit.
She was a hooker
and made it sound so great.
So one day I did it.
And I cried
the whole time.
But then I got
some regulars, and...
You know, it's not like
anybody plans this.
It's not... your childhood dream.
You could be so much more.
People put you down enough,
you start to believe it.
I think you are very bright.
A very special woman.
The bad stuff is easier to believe.
You ever notice that?
I don't want to talk to him.
I'll call him Monday.
Did he sign this?
He had to leave.
You can't disappear now.
We're in too deep.
Don't panic. Morse isn't
going anywhere. I'll be back.
Did you send the tickets to the hotel?
Yes.
Where are you going?
I have a date.
With the hooker?
Be careful, Philip.
Do I look OK?
Mm.
"Mm"?
Something's missing.
Well, nothin' else is gonna fit
into this dress, I'll tell you.
Maybe something
in this box.
I don't want you to get
too excited. It's only on loan.
They let you borrow this
from the jewellery store?
I'm a very good customer.
To buy this,
how much would it cost?
A quarter of a million.
A quarter of a million dollars?
So where are we going?
It's a surprise.
If I forget
to tell you later,
I had a really good time tonight.
Thank you.
When you're not fidgeting,
you look beautiful.
And very tall.
♪ You're a dream coming true
♪ I can't believe how
♪ I have fallen for you
♪ You are the one
♪ Who's led me to the sun
♪ How could I know
You want to go
to San Francisco this evening?
I've never been on a plane.
How'd you get to LA?
Bus.
♪ And I want to tell you
♪ You control my brain
♪ And you should know that
♪ You are life in my veins ♪
This should be
a smooth flight.
The weather's clear
to San Francisco.
We should be there
in about 50 minutes.
We're late.
No, it's all right.
Opening night never starts on time.
OK.
Program, sir.
Thank you.
Right this way,
Mr Lewis.
Doris. Nice to see you.
How are you, Edward?
Sir.
Evening, Edward.
Congratulations.
Come here and look.
It's all right.
I've already seen it.
If you're afraid,
why do you sit up here?
Because they're the best.
Is there anything else, sir?
No, thank you.
The glasses are there.
Enjoy the opera.
So, you said this is in Italian.
Mm-hm.
How am I gonna know what they're saying?
These are broken.
Mine are broken.
That's OK. It's all right.
Oh.
You'll know. You'll understand.
The music's very powerful.
There's a band.
People's reaction to opera
the first time they see it
is dramatic.
They either love it
or they hate it.
If they love it, they will
always love it. If they don't...
...they may learn
to appreciate it,
but it will never become
part of their soul.
Mm.
Bravo! Bravo!
Did you enjoy the opera, dear?
Oh, it was so good
I almost peed my pants.
What?
She said she liked it better
than Pirates of Penzance.
Oh.
I moved the queen.
You can't move the queen.
Do you really
want to do that?
Why don't we finish this tomorrow?
I have to work.
Why don't you not go to work tomorrow?
Take the day off?
Me not work?
Yeah.
I do own the company.
Here are the storage reports you wanted.
And Mr Lewis called.
What'd he say?
He said he's taking the day off.
He's taking the day off?
That's what he said.
I'm starving.
There's a Snap Dog vendor.
Do you have any money?
I have money.
I don't know what a Snap Dog is.
I'm gonna...
You'll buy a Snap Dog.
We'll cop a squat
under a tree somewhere.
Cop a what?
Cop a squat.
Al right,
read the first two pages.
OK.
I was talking to someone.
He sleeps.
I love you.
What are you thinking about,
sitting by yourself?
The fact that this will be
our last night together.
Then you'll finally
be rid of me.
Well, you've been
pretty tough to take.
My business is almost over,
so I'm going back to New York.
I'd really like
to see you again.
You would?
Yes.
Yes, I would. I've arranged
for you to have an apartment,
have a car,
have a wide variety of stores
that'll suck up to you
anytime you want to go shopping.
Everything's done.
What else?
You gonna leave some money
by the bed when you pass through?
It really wouldn't be like that.
How would it be?
For one thing,
it'd get you off the streets.
That's just geography.
Vivian, what is it you want?
What do you see happening between us?
I don't know.
When I was a little girl,
my mama used to lock me
in the attic when I was bad,
which was pretty often.
And I would...
I would pretend
I was a princess,
trapped in a tower
by a wicked queen.
And then, suddenly, this knight
on a white horse,
with these colours flying,
would come charging up
and draw his sword,
and I would wave.
And he would climb up the tower
and rescue me.
But never, in all the time...
...that I had this dream
did the knight say to me,
"Come on, baby. I'll put you up
in a great condo."
Yes.
I had to call.
I just got off the phone
with Morse. Get this.
He wants to meet
with you. Today.
Why?
He wouldn't say.
Edward, his nuts
are on the block.
We got him.
He's really caving in.
I want him to commit his stocks
to us this afternoon.
It's no good. If he's really caving in,
I don't want to wait.
Have Morse meet me downtown
this morning. Goodbye.
I have to go now.
I want you to understand.
I heard everything you said.
This is all
I'm capable of right now.
It's a very big step for me.
I know.
It's a really good offer
for a girl like me.
I've never treated you
like a prostitute.
You just did.
Barnard Thompson, Miss Vivian.
Could you come to
the front desk?
Someone here
wants to speak to you.
Her name is Miss De Luca.
Let me talk to her.
Let me just talk to her.
Yo, Viv, babe,
would you come down here?
The sphincter police
won't let me through.
OK. She's on her way.
Fine.
Mr Thompson.
Yes?
The window washer
is refusing to come down.
It's a Saturday.
Wait here, please. Watch her.
Yes, sir.
Fifty bucks, grandpa.
For 75, the wife can watch.
I've been calling you.
Yeah, they told me
at the Banana.
You were supposed to come Tuesday.
I was hiding from Carlos.
If you picked up the money,
you wouldn't have to.
I was busy. I had a life.
Nino got beat up.
I had to visit him in the hospital.
Rachel got arrested.
Anyway, I got the money.
Thank you for saving my ass.
Now Carlos can get off it.
He was talking about you last night.
He would bust something
if he saw you in this outfit.
I was afraid to hug you.
I might wrinkle you.
You look really good.
No, something with shade.
You clean up real nice.
Sure don't fit in on the boulevard,
not that you ever did.
Well, thanks.
It's easy to clean up
when you got money.
Yeah.
So, when does he leave?
Tomorrow.
You get to keep the clothes?
Yeah.
Edward asked me
if I wanted to see him again.
But I think, definitely no.
I mean, it's just
another week, right?
Definitely no?
Yeah.
Oh, no.
What?
I know this weepy look on your face.
Oh, no, don't.
You fell in love with him.
No. Kit, please stop it.
You've fallen in love with him?
Did you kiss him? On the mouth?
Uh, yeah, I did.
You kissed him on the mouth?
It was nice.
You fall in love and kiss him?
Did I not teach you?
I'm not stupid.
I'm... I'm not in love with him.
I just... I like him.
You like him?
Yeah.
You definitely like him?
Well, he's not a bum.
He's a rich, classy guy.
Who's gonna break
my heart, right?
Ohh, no. Come on.
You don't know that.
Hey, he asked you, right?
Maybe you guys could like...
...you know, get a house
and buy some diamonds and a horse.
I don't know.
Anyway, it could work. It happens.
When does it happen, Kit?
When? Who does it
really work out for?
Did it work out
for Skinny Marie or Rachel?
Those were very specific cases
of crackheads.
I just want to know
who it works out for.
Give me one example
of someone we know
that it happened for.
Name someone?
Like, give you a name?
Yeah, I'd like a name.
God, the pressure of a name.
Cinda-fuckin'-rella.
Mr Morse, you said you wished
to speak to Mr Lewis.
Mr Lewis is now listening.
I've reconsidered my position
on your acquisition offer.
On one condition:
I'm not so concerned
about me, but...
...the people who work for me.
No problem.
They'll be taken care of.
Now, if we could
address ourselves
to the contracts in front of you...
Excuse me, Phil.
Gentlemen, I'd like to speak
to Mr Morse alone.
Thank you.
You heard the man.
Please wait outside.
You too, Phil.
What do you mean?
I mean, I would like to speak
to Mr Morse alone.
Why does he get to stay?
Please.
I'll be right outside.
Good.
Is that better?
It's all right.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
Black.
Mr Morse,
my interests in your company
have changed.
What is it you're after now,
Mr Lewis?
Well, I no longer wish to buy
your company and take it apart.
I don't want
anyone else to either.
And it is still
extremely vulnerable.
So I find myself
in unfamiliar territory.
I want to help you.
Why?
Mr Morse, I think we can
do something very special
with your company.
What about our navy contracts?
Eh, they weren't dead.
Just delayed.
I bluffed a little bit.
You're very good at it.
Thank you very much. It's my job.
I think we can leave the details
up to the others.
I find this hard to say without
sounding condescending, but...
...I'm proud of you.
Thank you.
I think we can let in
the other suits now.
Let's continue the meeting.
Come in, gentlemen.
Sit down.
Please, what was this all about?
It's all yours, Phil.
Finish it up.
Hold it.
These aren't signed.
These aren't signed. Can someone
tell me what the fuck is going on?
Mr Lewis and I are
going to build ships together.
Great big ships.
I think I'm going to go for a walk.
Just stay here awhile.
Yes, sir, Mr Lewis.
Well, well.
Hello again.
I'm looking for Edward.
Edward's not here.
I thought he was with you.
No.
Edward is definitely
not "with me."
No. If Edward were with me...
When, actually...
When Edward was with me,
he didn't blow off
billion-dollar deals.
I think that Edward's with you,
that's what I think.
Mind if I have a drink?
No.
No, thank you.
Well.
I'll just wait.
Uh, Edward will be back soon.
Any minute, he'll be home.
You know...
...this is not home.
This is a hotel room.
And, uh, you are not...
...the little woman.
You're a hooker.
Maybe you're a very good hooker.
Maybe if I do you, then I wouldn't care
about losing millions of dollars.
Because I have to be very honest
with you right now, Vivian.
Right now, I really do care.
I really do.
And right now,
I am really pissed, you know?
Right now I am just
freaking out.
So maybe if I screw you...
...and take you to the opera,
I can be a happy guy.
Hey! Get off me!
Goddamn it! Ow!
Ow!
Come on! Come on!
I'm gonna...
Get off me! Get off!
Is this 20 bucks? 30 bucks?
Get off me!
You a fifty-dollar whore?
What are you doing? Get off!
You want to hurt me?
You already did.
Get out of here!
She's a whore. She's a goddamn...
Shut up!
Oh, damn!
Shit. Goddamn it.
I think you broke my nose.
Get out.
What is wrong with you? Come on!
I've been there ten years!
I devoted my whole life to you!
That's bullshit.
This is such bullshit.
It's the kill you love, not me.
I made you a very rich man
doing exactly what you loved.
Now, get out of here!
Get out!
Why do guys
know how to hit a woman
right across the cheek, wham,
and it feels like your eye
is going to explode?
What do they do? Do they pull you aside
in high school and show you how?
Is that... Ow!
Hey.
Not all guys hit.
I heard about what you did
with Morse.
It was a business decision.
It was good.
It felt good.
I think this is OK.
I gotta get going.
Yes, I noticed you'd packed.
Why are you leaving now?
Edward, there'll always
be some guy,
even some friend of yours,
thinking he can treat me like Stuckey,
thinking that it's allowed.
What are you gonna do?
You gonna beat up everybody?
That's not why you're leaving.
Look, you made me
a really nice offer.
And a few months ago,
no problem.
But now everything
is different.
You changed that,
and you can't change it back.
I want more.
I know about wanting more.
I invented the concept.
The question is, how much more?
I want the fairy tale.
Impossible relationships.
My special gift
is impossible relationships.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
If you ever need anything...
...dental floss, whatever,
you give me a call.
I had a good time.
Me too.
You want me
to get you a bellboy?
No, I got it.
I'll carry this.
Thanks.
Stay.
Stay the night with me.
Not because I'm paying you,
but because you want to.
I can't.
Goodbye.
I think you have
a lot of special gifts.
I didn't do it, sir.
No, I didn't say that.
Call maintenance.
Have them deal with it.
Delegate authority.
Yes, sir.
Hi, Barney.
Miss Vivian.
Thank you.
I wanted to say goodbye.
Then you're not accompanying
Mr Lewis to New York?
Come on, Barney. You and me
live in the real world.
Most of the time.
Have you arranged transportation?
I'm gonna call a cab.
Allow me. Darryl.
Yes, sir.
Please take Miss Vivian
anywhere she wishes to go.
Yes, sir.
It's been a pleasure
knowing you.
Come and visit us
again sometime.
Stay cool.
♪ Lay a whisper
♪ On my pillow
♪ Leave the winter
♪ On the ground
♪ I wake up lonely
♪ This air of silence
♪ In the bedroom
♪ And all around
♪ Touch me now
♪ I close my eyes
♪ And dream away
♪ It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ It must have been good
♪ But I lost it somehow
♪ It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ From the moment we touched
♪ Till the time had run out ♪
Is that everything, sir?
Yes, everything.
I'll meet you downstairs.
Thank you.
We look so dopey.
San Francisco's not that great,
you know.
It's a bad climate.
It's foggy.
It's unpredictable.
I'll wear a sweater.
What are you
gonna do there?
Get a job.
Finish high school.
I got things I can do. I used to make
pretty good grades in high school.
I can see that about you.
I can see that.
Sure you won't
come with me?
And leave all this?
Not in a million.
Come here.
Whoa. Whoa.
What is this?
It's part of the
Edward Lewis Scholarship Fund.
We think you got a lot
of potential, Kit De Luca.
You do?
You think I got potential?
Oh, yeah.
Don't let anybody
tell you different, OK?
OK.
Take care of you.
No, I can't. I can't.
It's your favourite.
What time's your bus?
An hour.
Yeah, well, I gotta split,
"cause goodbyes make me crazy.
Take care of you.
Whoa.
Mr Lewis.
You don't have any messages
for me, do you?
No, I'm afraid not, sir.
I'll need a car to the airport.
Darryl will take you
wherever you need to go.
The limousine out front.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, Darryl.
One last thing. If you could return this
to Fred's for me, please?
Yes, of course.
May I, sir?
Of course. Please.
It must be difficult to let go
of something so beautiful.
You know, Darryl also drove
Miss Vivian home yesterday.
I'll take care of it.
Thank you, Mr Thompson.
Your plane
is leaving as scheduled, sir.
You should be back
in New York on time.
I'm gonna have to charge you
more rent than Vivian.
I got this beauty course
I'm looking into,
and I'm not gonna
be there much.
You know, you just can't
turn tricks forever.
You gotta have a goal.
Do you have a goal?
I always wanted
to be in Ice Capades.
Help you, love?
Here you go.
Thank you very much.
You got a lot of stuff?
Carlos burned most of my stuff
when I said
I was moving out.
Vivian!
Princess Vivian!
Come down!
It had to be the top floor, right?
It's the best.
All right. I'm coming up.
So, what happened after
he climbed up the tower
and rescued her?
She rescues him right back.
Welcome to Hollywood.
What's your dream?
Everybody comes here.
This is Hollywood,
the land of dreams.
Some dreams come true,
some don't.
But keep on dreamin'.
This is Hollywood.
Always time to dream,
so keep on dreamin'.