[water trickling]
[gasping and coughing]
Help! Someone help me!
Is someone there?
Hey!
Oh, shit. I'm probably dead.
- [man] You're not dead.
- Who's that?
Who's that?
[man] There's no point in yelling.
I already tried that.
Turn on the lights!
[man] I would if I could.
What the fuck is going on?
Where am I?
[man] I don't know yet.
What is that smell?
[man] Shh. Hang on a second.
I think I found something.
[groaning]
Holy shit.
[vomiting]
Aah! Help!
Help!
[panting]
No one can hear you.
What the fuck is this?
Calm down. Just-just calm down.
[breathing heavily]
Are you hurt?
I don't know. Yeah!
What's your name?
My name is very fucking confused.
What's going on here?
My name is Lawrence Gordon.
I'm a doctor.
I just woke up here, just like you.
[grunting]
Aah!
[Lawrence] Recognize him?
No.
Well, do you have any idea
how you got here?
No.
What's the last thing you remember?
Nothing. I went to bed
in my shithole apartment
and woke up in an actual shithole.
What about you, huh?
There's. .. there's not much to tell.
I was on my way home from work, and, uh,
I don't remember anything else.
First dead body I've ever seen.
Look different in real life.
They don't move.
From the looks of these chains,
someone didn't want us
to go very far, either.
[gasps, grunts]
Do you see any scars?
- What?
- Huh?
This is what they do, man!
They kidnap you and drug you.
Before you know it,
you're lying in a bathtub,
and your kidneys are on eBay.
No one has taken your kidneys.
How can you tell from way over there?
Because you'd either be in terrible agony
or you'd be dead by now.
Trust me.
- What are you, a surgeon?
- Yeah.
So...
you gonna tell me your name or what?
Adam.
Well, Adam...
What we need to do...
is start thinking about why we're here.
Whoever brought us here could have
killed us by now, but they didn't.
They must want something from us.
The question is what.
- That clock.
- What about it?
It's brand-new.
So?
So... somebody obviously
wanted us to know the time.
Wait. I think I might be able
to reach the door.
[grunting]
What is that?
Excuse me.
It's a tape.
- Well, where'd you find it?
- It was in my pocket.
It says, "Play me."
[grunting]
Come on. Come on.
Throw it over here.
Huh?
[key rattles]
[grunts]
No?
[key rattles]
[grunting]
Use your shirt.
- What?
- Your shirt.
[grunts] Come on.
It won't work.
Well, look around. There--
there must be something else you can use.
There's nothing.
Well, there must be something.
Come on. You can do it.
Come on. Come on.
Again.
[sinister voice] Rise and shine, Adam.
You're probably wondering where you are.
I'll tell you where you might be.
You might be in the room that you die in.
Up until now,
you've simply sat in the shadows,
watching others live out their lives.
But what do voyeurs see
when they look into the mirror?
Now, I see you as a strange mix
of someone angry yet apathetic,
but mostly just pathetic.
So, are you going to watch
yourself die today, Adam,
or do something about it?
I don't get it.
[tape deck pops open]
Throw me the player.
No.
You throw me your tape.
Look, we're gonna have to work together
if we want to get out of here.
Now just throw it to me.
I'm not gonna risk breaking it.
You throw me your tape.
[winces]
[sinister voice] Dr. Gordon...
this is your wake-up call.
Every day of your working life,
you have given people the news
that they're going to die soon.
Now you will be the cause of death.
Your aim in this game is to kill Adam.
You have until 6:00 on the clock to do it.
There's a man in the room with you.
When there's that much
poison in your blood,
the only thing left to do
is shoot yourself.
[coughing]
There are ways to win this
hidden all around you.
Just remember,
"X" marks the spot for the treasure.
If you do not kill Adam by 6:00,
then Alison and Diana will die,
Dr. Gordon...
and I'll leave you in this room to rot.
Let the game begin.
[tape clicks]
Give me that.
Now.
[tape rewinding]
[tape clicks]
[sinister voice] Then Alison and Diana
Will die, Dr. Gordon...
and I'll leave you in this room to rot.
Any idea who that is?
[sinister voice] Let the game begin.
- He knows us.
- Wait a minute.
[tape rewinding]
[Adam] What do you think?
- Probably a joke, right?
- Shh! Shh!
[sinister voice] Let the game begin.
Listen. Listen.
[sinister voice] Follow your heart.
[static]
[tape clicks]
[Adam] What the hell does
“follow your heart" mean?
There, right next to you,
on the toilet.
Come on. Come on.
Oh, man.
[groaning]
[spits]
Anything?
No solids.
Take off the lid.
Come on.
I really wish I had
checked in there first.
[chuckles]
What is it?
Hey.
Mind passing me the other one?
Fuck. Fuck!
Fuck!
He doesn't want us
to cut through our chains.
He wants us to cut through our feet.
I think I may know who's done this to us.
What did you say?
Well, it's--
it's not someone I know personally.
It's... just someone I know of.
Jesus Christ. Tell me. Who is it?
Last I heard...
police still hadn't caught him.
And the only reason I know that
is because I was a suspect.
I'll start from the beginning.
[flies buzzing]
This one's not fresh anymore.
At least three weeks out.
Victim's a 46-year-old male.
[camera clicking]
Died of massive blood loss,
mostly through the femoral artery.
He started at the back of the cage
and tunneled his way
through that razor wire so fast
it's amazing he got as far as he did.
Cut himself so deep, we found traces
of stomach acid on the floor.
We also found this.
[click]
[sinister voice] Hello, Paul.
You are a perfectly healthy,
sane, middle-class male,
yet last month, you ran a straight razor
across your wrist.
Did you out yourself
because you truly wanted to die,
or did you just want some attention?
Tonight, you'll show me.
The irony is that if you want to die,
you just have to stay where you are,
but if you want to live,
you'll have to out yourself again.
Find a path through
the razor wire to the door.
But hurry, At 3:00, that door will lock,
and then this room becomes your tomb.
How much blood will you shed
to stay alive, Paul?
[screaming]
Door was on a timer.
It was unlocked until 3:00.
Then it slammed shut.
He was given two hours.
[screaming]
[door slams]
[man] A jigsaw piece.
[camera clicking]
I think we're gonna be here
for a while, Sing.
[Lawrence]
The newspapers started calling him
the Jigsaw Killer.
Actually, technically speaking,
he's not really a murderer.
He never killed anyone.
He finds ways for his victims
to kill themselves.
[camera clicking]
[sinister voice] Hello, Mark.
If you're so sick, then why do I have
so many photos of you up and about?
Let's put your so-called
illness to the test.
Right now, there's a slow-acting
poison in your veins.
The antidote is inside the safe.
Help!
[sinister voice]
The combination to the safe...
is written on the wall.
Hurry up and program it in,
but watch your step.
And by the way,
that's a flammable substance
smeared on your body.
So I would be careful
with that candle, if I were you.
Help!
Or all the people
you've burned with your act
just might have their revenge.
I found something else.
Well, uh, two things, actually.
There was someone standing outside here,
watching through this peephole.
Looks like our friend Jigsaw
likes to book himself
front-row seats
to his own sick little games.
He was there at the last one as well.
Only this time...
he left us his penlight.
Hmm...
Get a rush on the prints.
Copy that.
OK, this patient has an inoperable
frontal-lobe tumor
extending across the midline.
It started as colon cancer.
Patient has come in
for a standard checkup,
by which we are able to monitor the rate
at which his condition is declining.
The patient had--
His name is John...
Dr. Gordon.
He's a very interesting person.
Thank you for that information, Zep.
As you can see, our orderlies form
very special bonds with the patients.
Continuing on, the patient had--
[woman on speaker] Dr. Lawrence Gordon,
please page the operator.
Obviously, someone doesn't want me
to tell you what the patient had.
Excuse me.
[door opens]
Dr. Gordon. I'm Detective Tapp.
This is Detective Sing. City Homicide.
Very impressive.
- Oh, thank you.
- [Tapp chuckles]
I do my best.
Sorry to interrupt you
while you're working.
It's fine. Now, how can
I help you gentlemen?
Are you able to tell us
where you were between the hours
of 11:00 pm. and 1:00 am.
last night, Doctor?
Why is it that you're interested?
We'd like to ask you
a few questions about it.
For your sake, I think it's best
if we do it down at the station.
Would you like to follow us there?
[scoffs]
I'm afraid that's-that's quite
out of the question.
I can't just leave.
I have work to do, and--
Plus, my wife has the car today, so--
That's OK. You can ride with us...
Doc.
[chuckles] I'm sorry.
You'll have to tell me again.
What is this all about?
Is this yours, Doctor?
[man] So, you have no idea
how your penlight
showed up at the murder scene?
Of course not, Brett.
Well, I have to ask...
what were you doing last night?
I was seeing someone.
Who?
Look, if you can't be honest with me--
I was visiting someone.
It wasn't a patient.
All right?
What am I gonna do?
Well, as your lawyer and your friend,
my advice to you is to bite the bullet
and give them your alibi now,
'cause no one's gonna believe you later.
[sighs]
That was five months ago.
He tried to set me up for murder.
OK.
We checked your alibi. It holds up.
Good. Can I go home now?
[Sing] We have one of the victims
who managed to escape.
We want to know if you
wouldn't mind sticking around
and listening to her testimony.
Maybe it'll trigger something.
- I'd like to help, really, but--
- Well, we'd really appreciate it.
- She's the only one who made it.
- OK.
Amanda...
in your own time...
tell me the first thing you remember.
[Amanda] I woke up.
All I could taste was blood...
[straining]
And metal.
[sinister voice]
Hello, Amanda.
You don't know me, but I know you.
I want to play a game.
Here's what happens if you lose.
The device you're wearing is hooked into
your upper and lower jaws.
When the timer on the back goes off,
your mouth will be
permanently ripped open.
Think of it like a reverse bear trap.
Here, I'll show you.
[clock ticking]
[muffled screams]
There's only one key to open the device.
It's in the stomach of your dead cellmate.
Look around, Amanda.
Know that I'm not lying.
You better hurry up.
Live or die. Make your choice.
[clock ticking]
[yelps] No!
[sniffles]
And then I saw the body.
[panting]
[clock ticking]
[electricity buzzing]
There was a knife.
[groaning]
[screaming]
[Sing] He'd been injected
with an opiate overdose.
Couldn't move or feel much of anything.
You mean... he was alive?
Was.
What happened after you took it off?
[screaming]
[sinister voice thorough puppet]
Congratulations. You are still alive.
Most people are so ungrateful
to be alive, but not you.
Not anymore.
You are, in fact, a drug addict.
Isn't that right, Mandy?
Do you think that is why he picked you?
[crying]
[Tapp] Are you grateful, Mandy?
He...
helped me.
[light buzzing]
Are you sure it's him?
Yeah, I'm sure.
How do I know you're telling the truth?
You could be the one
who put me in this room!
I'm in exactly the same situation
that you're in.
Wrong. Wrong!
You've got one thing I don't; information!
You know who did this.
Now, you either tell me
what is really going on,
or I'll cut you with this!
You hear me? I'll cu--
- What?
- It's a two-way mirror.
[man] I can see you.
[Adam] 80, that's What this is...
reality TV.
[man] Don't look at me. I can't help you.
Can you hear me in there, huh?
I'm having a blast.
This is the most fun
I've had without lubricant.
Make sure you're getting everything.
That's not gonna do anything.
You just want to leave it running on us?
[Lawrence] Well, you won't stop it.
Well, that's why we
can't cut through these chains.
It's why you won't break that glass.
Every possible angle
has been pre-thought out by him.
You make it sound like
you admire this prick.
To overcome something,
you have to understand
what a perfect engine it is.
That's how you fight disease.
Now the tape told us to find an "X."
That "X“ has to be
somewhere in this room.
Help me find it.
How can you be the calm doctor guy
when your wife and kid are out there?
He's got them, too.
He could be doing anything
to them right now.
- Are you thinking about that?
- I am thinking about that.
I've been thinking about
the last thing I said to my daughter.
[wind chimes ringing]
[wood banging softly]
[clock ticking]
Diana, honey, are you OK?
Diana, honey, can you hear me?
Mommy.
What is it, sweet pea?
There's a man in my room.
Oh, honey, are you sure
he's not just hiding in your imagination?
He talked to me.
[sighs] OK. I'll come and check your room.
I want Daddy. He'll get the scary man.
All right, if you want.
Come on.
Larry, sorry to bother you,
but your daughter had a bad dream again.
Just a minute.
She wants you to check her room.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Just-just got to finish this paragraph.
Come on, sweetie. I'll check with you.
Nope. I'm done.
See? There's no one in your room.
There's no such thing as the bad man.
Now can you go to sleep?
- I'm still scared.
- You are?
Give me your tootsie.
[grunts]
Oh, what a big tootsie.
Remember this one?
This little piggy went to market.
This little piggy stayed home.
This little piggy had roast beef.
This little piggy had none.
And this little piggy went...
- Whee. .. all the way home!
- [pager beeping]
I hate that thing.
Well, I have to go to work, sweetheart.
You know what daddy's job is like.
Now, come on.
Let's see.
Try and get some sleep now, OK?
OK.
You're not gonna leave us,
are you, Daddy?
What?
What are you talking about?
You mean leave you and Mommy?
[soft chuckle]
No. No, sweetheart. I...
I would never do that.
Who gave you that idea?
No one.
Well, it's not true, OK?
OK.
How much do I love you?
- Love you very much.
- ...very much.
- That's right. That's right.
- [laughs]
- Good night, sweetie.
- Good night, Daddy.
Tomorrow...
I'll read you your favorite story.
- OK.
[Alison] I don't know how much longer
I can do this, Larry.
[Lawrence]
Do what? What are you talking about?
[Alison] How can you walk through life
pretending that you're happy?
- I am happy.
- That is complete bullshit.
I would rather you just break down
and tell me that you hate me.
At least there would be
some passion in it.
[clock ticking]
Would you like to see her?
[Adam] She's beautiful.
[Lawrence] Thank you.
You gonna have any more kids?
Ah, we've talked about it,
but, uh... with our schedules it's...
it's difficult enough
to concentrate on one.
So, where's the lucky wife?
There's another picture
behind the one you're looking at.
It's my favorite one because...
we're all in it together.
Someone, usually me,
has to hold the camera,
which means I'm always
missing from the photos.
[sinister voice]
"X" marks the spot.
Sometimes you see more
with your eyes shut.
It's, uh... it's not here.
What?
This photo you're talking about
is not here.
Really? Are you sure?
Yeah. Just... Oh!
Why, he... he must have taken it. I...
[Alison] How can you walk through life
pretending that you're happy?
- I am happy.
- That is complete bullshit.
I'd rather you break down
and tell me that you hated me.
At least there would be
some passion in it.
We'll talk about this later, OK?
[siren blaring in distance]
Just leave.
[door creaks]
[panting]
[sinister voice]
Good night, little girl.
[screams]
Diana?
[gasps]
[screaming]
Diana!
[Diana crying, moaning]
[Alison panting]
[Alison muffled]
Get away from her!
[heartbeat]
Mommy!
[crying]
[heartbeat]
[heartbeat increasing]
[Alison muffled]
Let go of her!
[Tapp] Oh, you little man, I see you.
Does Dr. Gordon know
you're at home with his wife?
I know you know something.
What are you doing in there?
Waiting for the doctor?
I'm waiting for the doctor, too.
I never should have let you go.
[man screaming]
[woman] There was someone
standing outside here watching.
[sinister voice]
I want to play a game.
[man screaming]
[Tapp] Jigsaw piece.
I think we're gonna
be here for a while, Sing.
Dr. Gordon, are you able to tell us
where you were last night?
And you have no idea how your
penlight showed up at the murder scene?
- We checked your alibi. It holds up.
- Isn't that right, Doctor?
I never should have let you go.
Here we are.
That was, uh, quite an amazing story
that poor woman told.
Look, I'm...
I'm sorry I can't be of more help
to your investigation.
You know, we arrested a dentist last week.
He liked to play with kids a bit too much.
He lived two blocks from here.
The sewer lines run under
this neighborhood, too... Doctor.
[engine starts]
[sinister voice] Hello, Amanda.
You don't know me, but I know you.
I want to play a game.
Here's what happens if you lose:
There's a timer at the back
of the device you're wearing.
- [man] Hey.
- When the timer goes off...
[indistinct chatter]
[videotape fast-forwarding]
[Sing] Hey, I'll catch
you guys down there.
[sinister voice]
Think of it like a reverse bear trap.
- I'll show you.
- [clock ticking]
- Hey, Tapp.
-Hmm?
We're gonna go down
to the grill to get a beer.
- You want to come?
- I don't think so. Thanks anyway.
Well, you know, I always ask.
- There's only one key to open...
- I'll leave you to have fun up here.
- Mm-hm.
- It's in the stomach
of your dead cellmate.
Hey, Tapp,
I don't mean for this to be disrespectful.
Maybe you should
find yourself a girlfriend.
[both laugh softly]
[sinister voice] It's in the stomach
of your dead Gel/mate.
Look around--
Look around, Amanda.
Know that I'm not lying.
You better hurry up.
Wait, wait, wait. Hey, Sing.
- Get back here.
- What?
Mm!
[sighs]
What?
Hey...
Remember 118th street?
Uh... K2K.
That gang's territory
was only about four blocks.
Now listen to this.
[alarm ringing faintly]
We got to check the records
for all the fire emergencies
that occurred in that area
within the last two weeks.
Go, right now. Mmm!
[Sing]
On the night of Tuesday the 17th,
we got a fire alarm going off
in the rear wing of 213 Stygian Street.
It's an old listing.
Used to be a mannequin factory.
You think we have enough
for a warrant, though?
Who said anything about a warrant?
- Right now?
- Why not?
Yeah, why not?
[gun being loaded]
[Tapp] At least we'll have
the cover of darkness.
[Sing]
Yeah. Well, so will anybody else.
[banging]
[grunts]
I got you.
What the hell is this?
Oh, Shit.
[groaning]
[Sing] Oh, fuck!
[muffled shouts]
[door opens]
- Wait, Sing.
- What?
- Let's see what he's gonna do.
- Why? we fuckin' got him.
- I just wanna make sure--
- What?
We don't know what he looks like.
Let's see what he's gonna do.
- [Sing] No fucking way.
- Sing!
- Fuck that. I'm gonna take him.
- Sing, Sing!
- [muffled]
- What the fuck? Shit!
[muffled shouts continue]
[man] Awake already, Jeff?
I need more powerful
tranquilizers next time.
Don't cry.
I've given your life a purpose.
You're a test subject
for something greater than yourself.
- Freeze! Police!
- Hold it right there! Don't move!
Put your fucking hands in the air!
[drills whirring]
[man] Now you'll make a choice.
In 20 seconds,
the life of this man will be ended.
- Shut it off and get down here!
- What'd you do? Turn it off!
- [shouting]
- [Tapp] Sing, stop that thing.
- I'm taking this bastard down.
- Fine.
- Move!
- How do you turn it off?
- Tell him how to stop it, asshole!
- One key will unlock it.
- Where is it?
- [man] It's in the box.
Box?
Fuck!
- Which key? Which key?
- Tell him which key it is!
Time's running out.
Shut up and get down here
right now, asshole!
What's more important to you, Officer,
arresting me or the life
of another human being?
Get down on your knees, asshole!
Hands behind your head!
- [Sing] Tapp!
- Sick bastard!
Yes, I'm sick, Officer.
Tapp, there's like--
There's 100 keys here!
Sick from the disease
eating away at me inside,
sick of people who don't
appreciate their blessings,
sick of those who scoff
at the suffering of others.
I'm sick of it all!
Tapp!
No! No! Tapp! Tapp! Shit!
You're OK. Let me see.
[panting]
- I'm gonna be back. I'm gonna be back.
- OK.
Freeze, or I'll shoot!
[groaning]
[grunting]
[police radio chatter indistinct]
I had you.
I had you on your knees.
But you're running. You're running.
You're running scared because we had you.
We're gonna close this case.
We-- We're gonna close it.
Right, Sing? Right?
We're gonna close it, Sing.
[Lawrence] "X" marks the spot.
"X" marks the spot.
We need to search this room again.
What are you doing over there?
Excuse me.
Just because I'm stuck
in this room with you
doesn't mean I have to report to you
every ten seconds.
I really don't see the point
in us not helping one another.
What do you want me to do?
I'm on a leash.
That's exactly why we need to talk.
We need to think.
I am thinking!
Then don't keep me in the dark
about what you're thinking!
Turn off the lights.
What?
Turn them off now, please.
Why?
Just turn them off for a second.
Jesus. Behind you.
How come we didn't see that before?
The lights in here hadn't charged it.
It must be glow-in-the-dark
paint or something.
[beeping]
- Open it.
- It's locked.
The key, the one from my envelope,
where is it?
Where the fuck? Here.
[soft chuckle]
A cell phone.
The most beautiful invention
on this planet.
[laughs]
Make that second most
beautiful invention.
- Give me that.
- Are you joking?
You're gonna put something
that you found in this room in your mouth?
Yes. I'm willing to risk it.
Give me that sweet cancer.
I don't care. I really don't.
Give me one of those.
[sinister voice]
The cigarettes are harmless, I promise.
Smoking is only poisonous
when it ends in bloodshed.
Think about this;
you don't need a gun to kill Adam.
May I please have a cigarette?
I'm trying the police.
[dialing]
[beeping]
- [beeping]
- Shit.
This was meant to receive calls,
not make them.
Wait a minute.
This has happened before.
Last night, after I finished
at the hospital...
I was walking back to my car.
I thought I was alone, but...
I'm sure someone else was there.
[camera clicks]
[busy signal]
Great.
[dialing]
[beeping]
That... thing was waiting for me.
How did you know to turn off the lights?
Who cares? It worked.
Yeah, but how did you know?
- Instinct.
- Instinct?
Yeah.
You know what?
You're a terrible liar.
You say that like you know me.
What else aren't you telling me?
[scoffs]
Well, um, let's see.
On my sixth birthday,
my best friend at the time,
Scott Tibbs, stabbed me with a rusty nail.
I didn't tell you about that.
I didn't tell you
that my last girlfriend,
who was a feminist vegan punk,
broke up with me
because she thought I was too angry.
I haven't told you
that one of my toenails is slightly--
Just stop it!
You knew to turn off these lights.
Whatever.
I'm dealing with a juvenile.
- You want to know?
- Yeah!
Here it is.
Come.
Oh, God.
Wh-where did you get this?
It was in your wallet...
behind the photo of your daughter.
Wh-why didn't you show me this before?
I couldn't.
[whimpering]
I'm sorry.
What are you doing to them, you bastard?!
OK. OK.
OK, I've got to think now.
[sinister voice] Think about this.
You don't need a gun to kill Adam.
When there's that much
poison in your blood,
the only thing left to do
is shoot yourself.
[Adam] What are you doing?
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
[Lawrence whispering]
Shh. Adam, listen to me.
I want you to play along with me on this.
[indistinct whispering]
[Lawrence] You got that?
So, you, uh...
you still want that cigarette?
Um, yeah.
Sure.
[lighter clatters]
[choking sounds]
There! I've done it!
I've killed him with the poison
just like you wanted!
Now where's my family?
Where are they?
- [electrical buzzing]
- [yelling]
Jesus Christ!
- What are you-—
- [panting]
- I-I just got electrocuted!
- What?
Jesus, that was our way out.
Did you hear what I said?
Get this thing off me! Get it off!
Stop acting!
You think I would make that up
just to mess up
your stupid fuckin' Charade?!
All right, that's it.
[grunting]
Damn it!
[panting]
I remember everything now.
I remember how I got here.
[music playing loudly on headphones]
[music stops]
[exhales]
Ah...
[scoffs]
Great.
[door closes]
[door creaking]
Is someone there?
[flash recharging]
[floorboards creaking]
I can hear you.
[flash recharging]
[floorboards creaking]
- [electronic laughter]
- [gasps]
What the.. .?
What the fuck is that?
- [laughter stops]
- [panting]
What the.. .?
- [rattling]
- [gasps]
Who is that?
Who's in there?
- [creaking]
- Come out!
I'll kill you, you motherfucker!
[creaking]
[panting]
[yells]
[clock ticking]
[cell phone ringing]
[beep]
Who is this?
[Diana on phone] Daddy.
Diana.
Daddy, is that you?
[crying]
Yeah, baby, it's me. I'm here.
I'm scared, Daddy.
Don't worry, honey.
Everything's gonna be OK.
Where's Mommy?
She-she's here with me.
Let me talk to her, sweetie.
OK? Put Mommy on.
The bad man from my room is here.
He has us tied up...
and he has a gun.
Wh-what man?
Please come home, Daddy.
Hello? Hello?
Diana?
Diana!
Larry.
Ali?
Is that you?
Is Adam there?
Well, how do you know...
Ali...
What is going on?
Don't believe Adam's lies.
He knows you.
He knew all about you before today.
[dial tone]
Hello? Ali?
Ali?
Hello!
God damn you!
If you so much as lay a finger on them,
I'll kill you!
You hear me, you son of a bitch?!
[crying]
Fuck!
Are they OK?
My wife, she, uh...
She mentioned your name.
What did she say?
She told me...
not to believe you.
Believe me about what?
She told me you knew me.
Who are you?
You know who I am.
Stop the lies! You're a liar!
I need to know the truth!
I'm a liar?
What did you do last night, Lawrence?
Work at a hospital, saving sick children?
You told me that after you
left your house last night,
you went to work at a hospital.
That's because it's the truth.
No, it's not.
Your wife is right, Larry.
You don't recall getting
your picture taken in that parking lot?
I can prove that you didn't go
anywhere near a hospital last night.
It's not the first time
I've done it, either, Larry.
I've been taking pictures of you
for a few days now.
- Why?
- You want to know what I do?
I get paid to take pictures
of rich guys like you
who go to seedy, out-of—the-way motels
to fuck their secretaries.
Last night, I went to your house
and watched you leave.
I followed you...
all the way to that shit-bag hotel.
You've, uh, had these with you
the whole time?
No, I found them in there
with the hacksaws.
I don't know how they got there.
Yeah, right. You're so full of it!
Ah, face it, Larry.
We're both bullshitters.
But my camera isn't.
It doesn't know how to lie.
It only shows you
what's put right in front of it.
Just out of curiosity,
what did you do in that motel room?
You got out of there pretty fast.
Why did you, um...
deem it necessary to page me
when you knew I was at home?
I didn't know if you were gonna make it.
But I-I gave you a precise time
at which to page me.
You-you can't do that.
It's not like I know the rules
for this sort of stuff.
[baby crying in other room]
What's wrong, Dr. Gordon?
Look, urn...
it was wrong of me to make you come here.
- But I thought we--
- No, no. Please.
I'm sorry.
[phone ringing]
You tell anyone you were here?
No.
[ringing continues]
Hello.
It's for you.
For me?
Hello.
[man whispering on phone]
[know What you're doing, Doctor.
I——
[dial tone]
[hangs up telephone]
- I have to go.
- What happened?
I got to go.
[sighs]
[camera clicks]
Who was it?
Who was what?
The person who paid you
to follow me, who was it?
He calls himself Bob,
and he gives me the money up front.
Two-hundred bucks a night.
If I'd known I was gonna end up here,
I would have asked for
a hell of a lot more.
What-what does that mean?
Does that mean you saw
what happened to me?
What I saw was you get into your car.
That's it.
I didn't ask your name.
I didn't know who you were.
I don't know how I got here.
I don't know how you got here.
I just took the shots
and went straight home to develop them.
Next thing I know, I'm chained to a pipe
in some prehistoric bathroom,
staring at the guy
I've been taking shots of all night.
Clearly, whoever paid you
to take pictures of me
- is the one who put us here.
- Maybe.
What do you mean "maybe"? Of course it is.
What did he look like?
- I don't know, he's just a guy.
- Was he tall? Was he skinny, obese, what?
I don't take notes about his appearance.
- You must remember something about him.
- I can't!
You're telling me you don't remember
a thing about the guy?
- I told you--
- Oh, for fuck's sake! I give up!
He's a tall black guy.
He's got a scar around his neck, OK?
Tapp.
Detective Tapp.
[Adam] Whoa.
The guy who paid me
to take these photos was not a cop.
No, no, no. He was-- He was discharged
from the police force.
He broke down
after his partner was killed.
But that didn't stop him
from harassing me.
The guy became obsessed.
He convinced himself that I must have
somehow been involved with the murders.
- I mean-- He's crazy.
- [laughing]
And you helped him.
You took money from him
to invade my privacy.
- How could you do that?
- Call it my need to eat.
Right. Right. You know what, Adam?
You're not a victim of this game;
you're part of it.
Oh, really? Obviously, this cop
thinks you're the one behind it all.
I told you, he's not a cop.
He's a bottom feeder, just like you.
What are you more pissed off about:
the fact that I took some shots of you,
or the fact that I took some shots of you
while you were cheating on your wife?
I did not cheat on her!
What do you care what I think anyway?
I don't give a crap
if you covered yourself in peanut butter
and had a 15-hooker gang bang.
How did I get here?
I-- I had everything in order.
My whole life was in perfect order.
[Alison sniffles]
[crying]
[door closes]
[spits]
Sweetheart, are you OK?
Mommy just needs you to be
really, really, really,
really strong right now.
I'm not gonna let anybody hurt you.
You got that?
OK. That's my good girl.
[Adam] Hey, was there someone else
at your house last night,
besides your wife and daughter?
[Lawrence] No.
[Adam] Well, there's someone here.
[static buzzes]
[Lawrence] I know him.
Zep.
[Adam] Who?
His name is Zep.
He's an orderly at my hospital.
Zep. You perverted little psychopath.
I'm gonna take great pleasure
in seeing you pay for this,
you bastard fuck!
Look.
We're out of time.
Shh, shh, shh.
Sweetie, sweetie, sweetie.
- Mommy, help me!
- Shh...
Dr. Gordon's time is up.
Now I've got to do what I've got to do,
and I'm afraid it has to be you
that tells him he failed.
[cell phone rings]
Is that you, Zep, you bastard?!
I know it's you, you son of a bitch!
[Alison over phone] L-Larry.
Ali?
You failed.
[grunting]
Hello?
Wait.
[panting]
Don't move! Stay on the ground.
Give me-- Give me the phone.
Give it to me!
- Larry.
- Ali.
Honey, are you all right?
No. No-- No, we're not.
Get down!
Larry, where are you?
I don't know.
I'm being held captive
in a room somewhere.
What-what are you talking about?
- [Lawrence] I'm so sorry, Ali.
- Honey, we need you here.
I'm so sorry for everything.
It's my fault.
Please forgive me.
I've always been happy with you.
Mommy. [cries]
- [grunts]
- [screaming]
Jesus!
[screaming]
Ali!
[gunshot]
[screaming]
Ali! Ali!
Mommy, help me!
[yells]
Freeze!
[screams]
[gunshots and screaming over phone]
[sobbing]
- What?
- Oh, no.
- [gun clicking]
- What the fuck?
[yelling]
- [grunting]
- [panting]
[sobbing]
Mrs. Gordon?
Diana!
I'm gonna kill your husband now,
Mrs. Gordon.
[grunting]
[yelling]
[sobbing]
[electrical buzzing]
Lawrence!
Lawrence, get up!
Get up!
I need you!
Oh, thank God.
I thought you were dead.
[groaning]
He-he... he electrocuted me.
I-I told you.
The same thing happened to me.
See? I wasn't lying. See?
Fuck this shit!
[tires screeching]
[grunting]
[cell phone ringing]
[groaning]
[ringing]
[grunting]
[man hole cover slides open]
- [ringing continues]
- No!
[crying]
Lawrence, calm down.
There must be a way out of this.
Oh, shut up! Just shut up!
My family needs me!
[sobbing]
No! God!
God! No!
[screaming]
Lawrence! I have a family, too!
I don't see them! That's my mistake!
It's a mistake I'd like to fix!
[Tapp] I'm gonna kill you,
you sick asshole!
- [screaming]
- [ringing continues]
Lawrence! Stop it.
[grunting]
Lawrence, just calm down.
There's a way out of here.
There's a way out!
Lawrence!
No! What-- No! Oh, my God!
What are you doing?
[both screaming]
[grunting]
[screaming]
- [screaming]
- [sobbing]
[gasps]
What... are you doing?
What are you... what are you...
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Lawrence, don't! No!
No, Lawrence, please!
I'm begging you!
Lawrence!
It's not me who did this to you!
[gun cocks]
You have to die.
No! I want to live!
- I want to live!
- I'm sorry.
- My family.
[yells]
[crying]
There!
I've done it!
Now show them to me!
Show them to me.
[man] Thank you very much, Officer.
- [Alison] Larry?
- Did you get through to him?
- No. There's still no answer.
- It's all right. I've called the police.
Everything is OK.
[indistinct chatter]
[loud banging]
You bastard!
I'll fucking kill you!
You fucking bastard!
- [gun clicking]
- I'll fucking kill you.
[breathing heavily]
You're too late.
Why?
It's the rules.
[yells]
[gunshot]
[flesh smashing]
[groans]
[yells]
You're gonna be all right.
You're just wounded-wounded
in the shoulder.
I have to go and get help.
Don't leave me!
No! No! No!
No!
[yells]
Lawrence!
Don't-don't worry.
I'll bring someone back.
I promise.
OK.
Key. Key.
[sinister voice] Hello, Mr. Hindle...
or as they called you
around the hospital... Zep.
I want you to make a choice.
[Diana screaming]
There's a slow-acting poison
coursing through your system
which only I have the antidote for.
Will you murder a mother and her child
to save yourself?
Dr. Gordon's time is up.
Mrs. Gordon!
[sinister voice]
Listen carefully if you will.
There are rules.
Why?
It's the rules.
[sinister voice] The key
to that chain is in the bathtub.
He's a very interesting person.
His name is John.
He has an inoperable frontal-lobe tumor.
[sinister voice] I'm sick from the disease
eating away at me inside.
Looks like our friend Jigsaw.
[sinister voice] I'm sick of people
Who don't appreciate their blessings.
It looks like our guy
likes to book himself
front-row seats
for his own sicko games.
[sinister voice] Hello, Mark, Paul,
Amanda, Zep, Adam, Dr. Gordon.
I want to play a game.
[yells]
[electrical buzzing]
[yelling]
[gasping]
[sinister voice] Most people
are so ungrateful to be alive...
but not you, not anymore.
[screaming]
Game over.
[Adam screaming]
Don't! Don't!
Don't!
[screaming]
[screaming fades]