Hello?
- Hello.
- Yes?
Who is this?
Who are you trying to reach?
What number is this?
What number are you trying to reach?
I don't know.
Well, I think you have the wrong number.
- Do I?
- It happens. Take it easy.
Hello?
I'm sorry.
I guess I dialed the wrong number.
Well, so why'd you dial it again?
To apologize.
You're forgiven. Bye now.
Wait. Wait. Don't hang up.
- What?
- I want to talk to you for a second.
They've got 900 numbers for that. See ya.
Hello?
Why don't you want to talk to me?
Who is this?
You tell me your name, I'll tell you mine.
I don't think so.
What's that noise?
- Popcorn.
- You're making popcorn?
I only eat popcorn at the movies.
Well, I'm getting ready to watch a video.
Really? What?
Oh, just some scary movie.
You like scary movies?
What's your favorite scary movie?
I don't know.
You have to have a favorite.
What comes to mind?
Halloween.
You know, the one
with the guy in the white mask
who walks around and stalks babysitters.
- Yeah.
- What's yours?
Guess.
Nightmare on Elm Street.
Is that the one
where the guy had knives for fingers?
Yeah, Freddy Krueger.
Freddy. That's right.
I like that movie. It was scary.
Well, the first one was,
but the rest sucked.
So, you got a boyfriend?
Why? You wanna ask me out on a date?
Maybe. Do you have a boyfriend?
- No.
- You never told me your name.
Why do you want to know my name?
'Cause I want to know who I'm looking at.
What did you say?
I want to know who I'm talking to.
That's not what you said.
What do you think I said?
What?
Hello?
Look, I gotta go.
Wait. I thought we were gonna go out.
Nah, I don't think so.
Don't hang up on me.
Shit.
Yes?
I told you not to hang up on me.
- What do you want?
- To talk.
Well, dial someone else, okay?
Listen, asshole...
No, you listen, you little bitch!
You hang up on me again,
I'll gut you like a fish, understand?
Yeah.
Is this some kind of joke?
More of a game, really.
Can you handle that...
Blondie?
Can you see me?
Listen. I am two seconds away
from calling the police.
They'd never make it in time.
We're out in the middle of nowhere.
What do you want?
To see what your insides look like.
Who's there?
I'm calling the police.
You should never say, "Who's there?"
Don't you watch scary movies?
It's a death wish.
You might as well come out here to
investigate a strange noise or something.
Look
you've had your fun now, so I think
you'd better just leave or else.
Or else what?
Or else my boyfriend
will be here any second,
and he'll be pissed when he finds out.
I thought you didn't have a boyfriend.
I lied! I do have a boyfriend,
and he'll be here any second,
so your ass better be gone.
Sure.
I swear.
He's big, and he plays football,
and he'll kick the shit out of you!
I'm getting scared.
I'm shaking in my boots.
So you'd better just leave.
His name wouldn't be...
Steve, would it?
How do you know his name?
Turn on the patio lights
again.
Oh, God!
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
- Where are you? Where are you?
- Guess.
Please don't hurt him.
That all depends on you.
Why are you doing this?
- I want to play a game.
- No.
- Then he dies right now.
- No! No!
Which is it?
What kind of game?
Turn off the light.
You'll see what kind of game.
Just do it!
Casey! No! No!
No! Casey!
Here's how we play.
I ask a question.
If you get it right, Steve lives.
- Please don't do this.
- Come on. It'll be fun.
- Please. Please.
- It's an easy category. Movie trivia.
I'll even give you a warm-up question.
Don't do this. I can't...
- Name the killer in Halloween.
- No.
Come on. It's your favorite
scary movie, remember?
He had a white mask.
He stalked the babysitters.
- I don't know.
- Come on. Yes, you do.
- No. Please.
- What's his name?
- I can't think.
- Steve's counting on you.
Michael. Michael Myers.
Yes! Very good.
Now for the real question.
- No!
- But you're doing so well.
We can't stop now.
Stop! Leave us alone.
Then answer the question. Same category.
Oh, please, stop.
Name the killer in Friday the 13th.
Jason! Jason! Jason!
I'm sorry. That's the wrong answer.
No, it's not! No, it's not. It was Jason!
Afraid not. No way.
Listen. It was Jason.
I saw that movie 20 goddamn times!
Then you should know Jason's mother,
Mrs. Voorhees was the original killer.
Jason didn't show up until the sequel.
I'm afraid that was a wrong answer.
You tricked me.
Lucky for you, there's a bonus round,
but poor Steve. I'm afraid he's out.
Hey, we're not finished yet.
Final question. Are you ready?
Please. Please leave me alone.
Answer the question, and I will.
What door am I at?
What?
There are two main doors to your house,
a front door and the patio doors.
If you answer correctly, you live.
Very simple.
Don't do this. I can't. I won't.
Your call.
Did you water over here today?
No, it was just that water from the rain.
They look great, don't they?
Don't they smell strong?
I told you we could send it back.
Mom.
- Jesus!
- What is it?
Casey!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Casey? Casey?
Casey!
- Where is she?
- Call the police.
Casey!
- Casey, you upstairs?
- Oh, my God.
Casey, baby?
- Where is she?
- She's here.
- Mom... Mom...
- Oh, my God. I can hear her.
Where is she?
Oh, my God. I can hear her.
Get in the car.
Drive down to the Mackenzies.
No, not my daughter.
- Just go.
- Not my daughter.
Call the police.
- It's just me.
- Billy, what the... What're you doing here?
- Sorry. Don't hate me.
- Oh, my God.
What, you sleep in that?
Yes, I sleep in this. My dad is
in the other room. You can't be in here.
- I'll just stay a sec.
- No, you can't...
Oh, no. You gotta go. Go. Go.
What's going on in there?
- Are you okay?
- Can you knock?
- I heard screaming.
- No, you didn't.
No?
Oh, well.
I'm hitting the sack. My flight
leaves first thing in the morning.
Now, the expo runs all weekend,
so I won't be back till Sunday.
There's cash on the table,
and I'm staying at...
- The Hilton.
- Out at the airport, so call if...
- If I need anything. Yeah, I got it.
- I could've sworn I heard screaming.
Have a good trip, okay?
Sleep tight, sweetie.
Close call.
Billy, what are you doing here?
Well, it occurred to me that...
I've never snuck through
your bedroom window.
Right, and now
that it's out of your system...
I was home watching television, and...
The Exorcist was on.
Got me thinking of you.
It did?
Yeah. It was edited for TV.
You know, all the good stuff
was cut out and
it got me thinking of us.
How two years ago,
we started off hot and heavy.
Nice, solid R rating,
on our way to an NC-17.
And how things have changed, and...
Lately, we're just
sort of edited for television.
So, you thought
you would climb in my window,
and we'd have a little raw footage?
No, no. I wouldn't dream
of breaking your underwear rule.
I just...
I thought maybe we could do
a little on top of the clothes stuff.
Okay.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Hey.
Okay. Okay, okay. Time's up, stud bucket.
You see what you do to me?
You know what my dad will do to you?
Yeah.
- I'm going.
- Okay.
Bye.
You know,
I appreciate the romantic gesture.
Hey, about the sex stuff?
You know,
I'm not trying to rush you at all.
I was only half-serious.
Okay.
Hey, Billy.
Would you settle for a PG-13 relationship?
What's that?
My God. You're just a tease.
35-14... Situation under control.
Roger, dispatch. 35, I copy.
All right.
...are dealing drugs,
that they are high in the classrooms,
and that they are involved in the occult.
Occult?
The small town of Woodsboro, California
was devastated last night
when two young teenagers
were found brutally murdered.
Authorities have yet to issue a statement,
but our sources tell us
that no arrest has been made,
and the murderer could strike again...
- Do you believe this shit?
- Tatum, what is going on?
- You don't know?
- No.
Casey Becker and Steve Orth
were killed last night.
What? No way.
And we're not just talking killed,
we're talking splatter-movie killed,
ripped open from end to end.
Casey Becker?
She sits next to me in English.
Not anymore.
It's so sad. Her mom and dad
found her hanging from a tree,
her insides on the outside.
Oh, my God. Do they know who did it?
Fucking clueless. I mean,
they're interrogating the entire school,
teachers, students, janitors.
- They think it's school-related?
- They don't know.
Dewey was saying this is the worst crime
they've seen in years, even worse than...
Well...
It's bad.
- Here you go, Mrs. Taylor.
- Thank you, Jimmy.
Sidney?
It would appear to be your turn.
Who's up next?
- Sidney Prescott.
- Prescott.
She was daughter of...
- Sidney. Thank you.
- Okay.
Hi, Sidney.
Sheriff Burke. Dewey.
That's Deputy Riley today, Sid.
How is everything?
Good.
And your dad? How's he doing?
We're fine, thanks.
We're gonna keep this very brief, Sidney.
The police just wanna ask you
a few questions. You okay?
Sidney, were you very close
to Casey Becker?
Remember, your principal loves you,
and I want you to be safe.
All students are encouraged to return to
their homes promptly from school grounds.
Avoid strangers
and walk in twos and threes...
- How many questions did they ask you, Sid?
- Well, they asked me if I knew Casey.
- Yeah, they asked me that, too.
- Hey, did they ask if you like to hunt?
Yeah, they did. They ask you?
Hunt? Why would they ask you
if you like to hunt?
Because their bodies were gutted.
Thank you, Randy.
They didn't ask me if I liked to hunt.
That's 'cause there's no way
a girl could've killed them.
That is so sexist.
The killer could easily be female.
Basic Instinct?
That was an ice pick.
Not exactly the same thing.
Yeah, Casey and Steve
were completely hollowed out.
And the fact is, it takes a man
to do something like that.
Or a man's mentality.
How do you gut someone?
You take a knife,
and you slit them from groin to sternum.
Hey, it's called tact, you fuckrag.
Hey, Stu, didn't you used to date Casey?
Yeah, for, like, two seconds.
Before she dumped him for Steve.
- I thought you dumped her for me?
- I did. He's full of shit.
Are the police aware
that you dated the victim?
Hey, what are you saying?
That I killed her?
It would certainly improve
your high school "Q."
Stu was with me last night. Okay?
Yeah, I was.
Was that before or after
he sliced and diced?
Fuck you, nutcase.
Where were you last night?
Working, thank you.
At the video store?
I thought they fired your sorry ass.
Twice.
I didn't kill anybody.
Nobody said you did.
Thanks, buddy.
Besides, it takes a man
to do something like that.
Yo, I'm gonna gut your ass
in a second, kid.
Tell me something, did you really put
her liver in the mailbox?
'Cause I heard that they found her liver
in the mailbox
next to her spleen and her pancreas.
Randy, you goon-fuck,
I'm trying to eat here.
She's getting mad, Randy.
You better "liver" alone.
Liver alone!
Liver, liver! Live? It was a joke.
See you, Sidney.
I'll talk to you tomorrow, Sid.
So you sure I can stay over?
'Cause my dad won't be back till Sunday.
No prob. I'll pick you up after practice.
You okay?
It's just, you know,
the police and reporters and everything,
it's like déjà vu all over again.
I'll be there by 7.-00, I promise.
- Thanks, Tatum.
- Later.
...the bodies of 17.-year-old Casey Becker
and her 18-year-old boyfriend Steven Orth
were discovered late last night
by the girl's...
The Woodsboro double-murder case.
Authorities are baffled
by the lack of clues and the savage...
The town's in shock, and no one
can quite believe what has happened here.
Although this is not the first time
this small community of Woodsboro
has endured such tragedy.
Only a year ago, Maureen Prescott,
wife and mother,
was found raped and murdered
not far from this peaceful town square.
Hello?
Practice ran late. I'm on my way, okay?
It's past 7:00.
Don't worry. Casey and Steve
didn't bite it till way after 10.:00.
That's comforting.
I'm gonna swing by the video store.
I was thinking Tom Cruise
in All the Right Moves.
You know, if you pause it just right,
you can see his penis.
Whatever. Just hurry, okay?
Ta-ta, Sid.
Tatum, just get in the car...
Hello, Sidney.
Hi. Who is this?
You tell me.
Well, I have no idea.
Scary night, isn't it?
With the murders and all, it's like
right out of a horror movie or something.
Randy, you gave yourself away.
Are you calling from work?
'Cause Tatum's on her way over.
Do you like scary movies, Sidney?
I like that thing you're doing
with your voice, Randy.
It's sexy.
What's your favorite scary movie?
Oh, come on.
You know I don't watch that shit.
Why not? Too scared?
No. No. It's just, what's the point?
They're all the same.
Some stupid killer stalking some
big-breasted girl who can't act,
who's always running up the stairs
when she should be going out
the front door. It's insulting.
Are you alone in the house?
Randy, that's so unoriginal.
I'm disappointed in you.
Maybe that's because I'm not Randy.
So, who are you?
The question isn't, "Who am I?"
The question is, "Where am I?"
So, where are you?
Your front porch.
Why would you be calling
from my front porch?
That's the original part.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I call your bluff.
So where are you?
Right here.
Can you see me right now?
Okay. What am I doing?
What am I doing? Hello?
Nice try, Randy.
Tell Tatum to hurry up, okay? Bye, now.
If you hang up on me,
you'll die, just like your mother!
Do you want to die, Sidney?
Your mother sure didn't.
Fuck you, you cretin.
No!
Come on.
Shit!
Billy!
Door's locked.
I heard screaming. You all right?
The killer's here. He's in the house.
No, he's in the house.
He's gonna... He's gonna kill us.
He's gone.
It's all right.
What?
Sid, what?
Wait, wait, wait!
Sidney, wait!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Come on! Sidney, come back!
Sidney!
Sorry. I found this.
Come on!
All right, hold your hands together!
Do you wish to give up
your right to remain silent?
I didn't do anything.
Do you wish to give up
your right to speak to an attorney
and have him present during questioning?
Ask her. She'll tell you.
- Ask her.
- What have you got, Dewey?
- I caught him, Sheriff.
- Wait!
- Who is that?
- Billy Loomis.
Sir... Sheriff, call these guys off.
I didn't do it.
Sheriff, wait, wait. Listen. Call my dad.
Please call him.
He'll tell you. Just call him.
Sidney! Sidney!
- How's she doing?
- Sid's tougher than she looks.
You'd have to be,
all the shit she's been through.
Sid!
Well, we're seeing a lot of you today.
You gonna be able to come to the station
and answer a few questions, Sid?
Oh, shit. Sidney!
God, Sid, I'm so sorry I was late.
Are you all right?
Tatum, you can't be here.
This is an official crime scene.
It's okay.
Her dad's out of town, all right?
She's staying with us tonight.
- Does Mom know?
- Yes, doofus.
- Let's get you out of here.
- She'll be okay.
- Come on, Sid.
- You won't believe this.
What?
Creepy, huh?
- I'll be damned.
- What?
Jesus, the camera! Hurry!
My name isn't Jesus.
Sidney, is that you in there?
Excuse me, is that Sidney Prescott
they took away?
I'm not talking to you.
- What happened to her?
- None of your damn business.
I heard something about a costume.
Is that true?
Can you tell me anything?
Yeah, you're a real pain in the ass.
Leave Sid alone.
Where's she going?
- Look... Kenny?
- Yeah?
I know that you're about
50 pounds overweight,
but when I say hurry,
please interpret that as
move your fat, tub-of-lard ass now!
Did you find him?
You're sure it was the Hilton?
At the airport.
He's not registered there.
Could he have stayed somewhere else?
I don't know. I guess.
Don't worry, Sid.
We'll find him.
Dewey, they got that mask in.
- Roger, dispatch.
- I'll be right back.
Let me ask you this,
what are you doing
with a cellular telephone, Son?
Everybody's got one, Sheriff.
I didn't make those calls. I swear.
Why don't you check the phone bill,
for Christ's sake. Call Vital Phone Comp.
- They got records of every number dialed.
- Thanks, Hank. We're on top of it.
What were you doing over
at Sidney's house tonight?
I wanted to see her, that's all.
And last night? Sidney said you crawled
through her window last night, too.
You went out last night?
I was watching TV. I got bored.
I decided to go for a ride.
You happen to ride by
Casey Becker's house?
No. No, I didn't.
Sheriff, I didn't kill anybody.
We're gonna have to hold you, Son,
till we get those phone records.
This is crazy.
You know that? I didn't do it.
- Camera two!
- No, I do!
- Okay!
- Yeah.
Are there any more donuts in there?
Move it, Kenny.
- They're not letting anybody in.
- I'm not just anyone.
Bitch goddess.
- Kenny, are we on?
- Yeah, go.
Hi. Gale Weathers reporting live
from the Woodsboro Police Station,
where we hope to get a glimpse
of Sidney Prescott.
Hey, watch her, Larry!
Hey, watch the hand.
You know who you're dealing with here?
Tell them. Come on, Dad. Tell them.
- Sidney...
- Just wait for the lawyer, Billy.
- Sidney, come on. You know me.
- Come on, come on.
- Sidney, look at me!
- Don't give us any trouble.
Come on!
Sid, I'm gonna get you out of here, okay?
You okay?
They sell this costume
in every five-and-dime in the state.
There's no way to track the purchase.
What about that cellular phone bill?
Well, we're pulling Loomis's account.
We won't know anything until the morning.
Oh, come on!
You think he did it?
Twenty years ago,
I would've said not a chance.
But these kids today
damned if I know.
Hey, Dewey, can we go now?
Hold on a second.
Goddamn it, Dewey!
What did Mom tell you?
When I wear this badge,
you treat me like a man of the law.
I'm sorry, Deputy Dewey boy,
but we're ready to go. Now, okay?
Take them out the back way.
Avoid that circus out there.
Go on, big brother.
- Come on.
- Don't touch me.
He's my superior.
The janitor's your superior.
Let's get back to work!
Isn't there a back way out of this place?
Yeah. Down that alley, I think.
You guys just stay here.
I'm gonna get the car.
Don't move. Don't make a sound.
There she is. Sidney!
Hi. Some night. What happened?
Are you all right?
She's not answering any questions.
Leave us alone.
No. No, Tatum. It's okay.
She's just doing her job, right, Gale?
Yes, that's right.
So how's the book?
Well, it'll be out later this year.
I'll look for it.
I'll send you a copy.
Geez.
- Nice shot.
- Bitch.
- No, I mean, the camera. Nice shot.
- Where'd you learn to punch like that?
God, I loved it. "I'll send you a copy."
Bam! Bitch went down.
"I'll send you a copy." Bam!
Sid, superbitch! You are so cool.
Thought you might want some ice
for that right hook.
Thanks.
I'll be right next door.
Try to get some sleep.
Yeah, yeah.
Do you really think Billy did it?
He was there, Tatum.
He was destined to have a flaw.
I knew he was too perfect.
Telephone, honey.
- Who is it?
- It's for Sid.
My dad?
I don't think so.
- Take a message.
- No. I'll get it.
How's she doing?
Hello?
Hello, Sidney.
No!
Poor Billy boyfriend.
An innocent guy
doesn't stand a chance with you.
Leave me alone!
Looks like you fingered the wrong guy...
- Dewey!
- ...again.
- Who are you?
- Dewey!
- Hang up, Sid.
- Don't worry. You'll find out soon enough.
- I promise.
- Dewey!
What?
- "What?"
- What?
Hello?
Sidney Prescott, who escaped
a vicious attack last night,
is the daughter of Maureen Prescott,
who was brutally killed last year
when convicted murderer Cotton Weary
broke into their home
and savagely raped and tortured
the deceased.
Cotton Weary is currently awaiting appeal
for the death sentence handed down
after the young Sidney
testified against him.
She was the key witness
in the state's case against the...
It's never gonna stop, is it?
Billy was released.
His cellular bill was clean.
He didn't make those calls.
We're checking every cellular account
in the county.
Any calls made to you or Casey Becker
are being cross-referenced.
It's gonna take some time,
but we'll find him.
Okay?
Don't worry, Sid. It's school.
You'll be safe here.
How does it feel
to be almost brutally butchered?
Hey! Hey, now, leave her alone.
People want to know!
They have a right to know!
- Leave her alone.
- How does it feel?
She just wants to get an education.
Turn that thing off.
What?
Just a sec.
Stop right there.
I'm not here to fight.
I just need to talk.
Kenny, camera, now.
- Off the record. No cameras.
- Forget it.
Please? You owe me.
I owe you shit.
You owe my mother!
Your mother's murder
was last year's hottest court case.
Somebody was gonna write a book about it.
Right. It had to be you
with your lies and bullshit theories.
What is your problem?
You got what you wanted.
Cotton Weary's in jail.
They're gonna gas him.
A book is not gonna change that.
- Do you still think he's innocent?
- Your testimony put him away.
It doesn't really matter what I think.
During the trial, you did all those
stories about me. You called me a liar.
I think you falsely identified him, yes.
- Have you talked to Cotton?
- Many times.
- And has his story changed?
- Not one word.
He admits to having sex with your mother,
but that's all.
He's lying.
She never would've touched him.
He raped her, and then
he butchered her.
Her blood was all over his coat.
He was drunk that night.
He left his coat at your house
after your mother seduced him.
I saw him leave wearing it.
No, you saw someone leave
wearing that coat,
the same someone who planted it
in Cotton's car, framing him.
No.
Cotton murdered my mother.
You're not so sure anymore, are you?
Nice welt, sweetie. Let's go, Sid.
The killer's still on the loose, isn't he?
Come on, Sid.
Those murders are related.
I'm sorry I mangled your face.
Wait. Sidney, don't go.
Just stop, all right?
Jesus Christ.
An innocent man on death row.
A killer still on the loose.
Kenny, tell me I'm dreaming.
- You want to go live?
- No, no. Not so fast.
- We don't have anything concrete.
- This is huge. You can't just sit on it.
I know. That's why we need proof.
If I'm right about this,
I could save a man's life.
Do you know what that
could do for my book sales?
This is a mistake. I shouldn't be here.
I want you to meet me
right here after class. Okay, Sid?
All right.
Hey, I haven't seen Billy around.
Is he really pissed?
You mean after you branded him
the Candy Man?
- No. His heart's broken.
- Stu!
Why are they doing this?
Are you kidding me?
Look at this place. It's like Christmas.
- Stupidity leak!
- Easy!
Sidney!
Jesus! Shit!
It's just me.
You still think it's me.
No. No, I don't.
It's just... somebody was there...
Hey, Christie, wait up.
Billy, someone tried to kill me.
I know. I know.
The cops said I scared them away.
It wasn't me, Sid.
I know. He called me again last night
at Tatum's house.
You see? Couldn't have been me.
I was in jail. Remember?
I'm so... sorry. Please understand.
Understand what?
That I have a girlfriend
who would rather accuse me
of being a psychopathic killer
than touch me?
You know that's not true.
Then what is it?
What... is it?
Billy, I was attacked
and nearly filleted last night.
I mean between us.
I mean, you haven't been the same since...
since your mother died.
Is your brain leaking? My mom was killed.
I can't believe you're bringing this up!
No, it's been a year.
Tomorrow. One year tomorrow.
I know. I think it's time
you got over that.
I mean, when my mom left my dad,
I accepted it.
It's the way it is. She's not coming back.
Your parents split up.
This is not the same thing.
Your mom left town.
She's not lying in a coffin somewhere.
Okay. Okay. Okay. I'm sorry.
It's... it's a bad analogy.
It's just that...
I want my girlfriend back.
Sid!
I am sorry if my traumatized life
is an inconvenience to you
and your perfect existence.
What? What are you...
Nobody said that! Sid!
Stupid.
You make me so sick.
Your entire havoc-inducing, thieving,
whoring generation disgusts me.
So, two of your fellow students
were just savagely murdered,
and this is the way that you show
your compassion and sensitivity, huh?
Let me tell you something...
You're both expelled. Get out!
- Come on, Mr. Himbry! It was just a joke!
- That's not fair!
You're absolutely right. It is not fair.
Fairness would be to rip your insides out,
hang you from a tree so we can expose you
for the heartless,
desensitized little shits that you are.
She was never attacked.
I think she made it all up.
Why would she lie about it?
For attention.
The girl has some serious issues.
What if she did it?
What if Sidney killed Casey and Steve?
And why would she do that?
Maybe she had the hots for Steve
and killed them both in a jealous rage.
What would Sidney want with Steve?
She has her own
bubble-butt boyfriend Billy.
Maybe she's a slut just like her mother.
- You're evil.
- Please. It's a common fact.
Her mother was a tramp.
Cut some slack.
She watched her mom get butchered.
Yeah, and it fucked her up royally.
Think about it.
Her mother's death
leaves her disturbed and hostile
in a cruel and inhumane world.
She's delusional. "Where's God?"
Et cetera. Completely suicidal.
One day, she snaps.
She wants to kill herself,
but she realizes that teen suicide
is out this year,
and homicide is a much healthier,
therapeutic expression.
Where do you get this shit?
Ricki Lake.
You are pathetic!
"Pathetic."
Sidney.
Is someone there?
In what appears to be a prank,
several students were seen
wearing scary masks.
School officials have yet to comment,
but this is known to be the same costume
worn by the killer.
Seventeen-year-old Casey Becker
and her boyfriend Steven Orth
have already lost their lives. Who's next?
You can literally feel
the fear on this campus.
Hi. Gale Weathers,
field correspondent, Top Story.
I know who you are, Miss Weathers.
How's the eye?
It's productive.
Is there a problem on campus?
No. Everything's under control.
Well, of course. You're here.
You're not supposed to be here.
I know. I should be in New York
covering the Sharon Stone stalker,
but who knew?
You look awfully young
to be a police officer.
I'm 25 years old.
You know, in a demographic study,
I proved to be most popular
amongst males 11 to 24.
Guess I just missed you.
Of course, you don't look a day over 12,
except in that upper-torso area.
- Does the force require you to work out?
- No, ma'am.
'Cause of my boyish good looks,
muscle mass has increased my acceptance
as a serious police officer.
I need your attention now, kids.
Due to the recent events
that have occurred,
effective immediately, all classes
are suspended until further notice.
The Woodsboro Police Department
has issued a citywide curfew
beginning at nine o'clock tonight.
Looks like we've got
a serial killer on our hands.
Well, a serial killer
is not really accurate.
Gotta knock off a couple more
to get that title.
Well, we can help, can't we?
I mean, we certainly don't have any leads.
Have you located Sidney's father yet?
No, not yet.
Well, he's not a suspect, is he?
We haven't ruled him out as a possibility.
- If you'll excuse me.
- I'm sorry. Am I keeping you?
If I may say so, Miss Weathers...
you are much prettier in person.
So you do watch the show.
I'm 25. I was 24 for a whole year.
Please, call me Gale.
It was just some sick fuck
having a laugh, Sidney.
No, it was him, Tatum. I know it.
You're not to be alone anymore, right?
If you pee, I pee. Is that clear?
Kizool, 'cause schizzool is izzout.
I don't know what you did, Sidney,
but on behalf of the entire student body,
- we all say thank you!
- Stop it, Stu.
No, I say impromptu party tonight,
my house,
to celebrate this little siesta.
What do you say?
Are you serious?
Parents are out of town,
and if this little vixen doesn't invite
the entire world, we'll be fine.
Intimate gathering, intimate friends.
What do you say, Sid?
I mean, pathos could have its perks.
Totally protected. Yo, I am so buff.
- I got you covered, girl.
- No...
Come on, Sid.
For me? It could be fun.
Okay, whatever.
Yeah? Nice.
Cool. You guys bring food, all right?
Yes?
Hello?
Damn it.
- Damn little shits.
- What'd you call me?
- Not you, Fred.
- Prick.
What if Cotton Weary is telling the truth?
Maybe he was having an affair
with your mom.
I mean, your dad was always
out of town on business. Maybe
maybe your mom
was just a very unhappy woman.
If they were having an affair,
then how come
Cotton couldn't prove it in court?
Well, you can't prove a rumor.
That's why it's a rumor.
Right, created by
that little tabloid twit Gale Weathers.
It goes further back, Sid.
There's been talk about other men.
And you believe it?
Well...
I mean, you can only hear
that Richard Gere gerbil story
so many times
before you have to start believing it.
I'm sorry.
You know, if I was wrong
about Cotton Weary,
then the killer's still out there.
Don't go there, Sid.
You're starting to sound like
some Wes Carpenter flick or something.
Don't freak yourself out, okay?
We've got a long night ahead of us.
Okay?
Let's boogie.
It's alive!
In the name of God!
- Watch it, jerk.
- I'm sorry.
Dork.
Jesus, this place is packed tonight, man.
We had a run in the mass murder section.
Coming to my fiesta?
- Yeah, I'm off early. Curfew, you know?
- Cool.
What's that werewolf movie
with ET's mom in it?
The Howling. Horror, straight ahead.
Okay, thanks.
Oh, now, that's in poor taste.
What?
If you were the only suspect
in a senseless bloodbath,
would you being standing
in the horror section?
Well, it was just a misunderstanding.
He didn't do anything.
You're such a little lap dog.
He's got "killer"
printed all over his forehead.
Okay, really?
Why'd the cops let him go, smart guy?
Because obviously
they don't watch enough movies.
This is standard horror movie stuff.
Prom Night revisited, man.
Yeah? Why would he want to kill
his own girlfriend?
There's always some stupid bullshit reason
to kill your girlfriend.
That's the beauty of it all. Simplicity.
Besides, if it gets too complicated,
you'll lose your target audience.
Well, what's his reason?
Maybe Sidney wouldn't have sex with him.
What, is she saving herself for you?
Maybe. Now that Billy
tried to mutilate her
do you think Sid would go out with me?
No, I don't, at all. No.
Know who I think it is?
You know, I think it's her father.
Why can't they find her pops, man?
Because he's probably dead.
His body will come popping up
in the last reel somewhere,
eyes gouged out, fingers cut off,
teeth knocked out!
See, the police are always
off track with this shit.
If they watched Prom Night,
they'd save time.
There's a formula to it,
a very simple formula!
Everybody's a suspect!
I'm telling you, the dad's a red herring.
It's Billy.
How do we know you're not the killer?
Hi, Billy.
Maybe your movie-freaked mind
lost its reality button.
Ever think of that?
You're absolutely right.
I'm the first to admit it.
If this were a scary movie,
I'd be the prime suspect.
That's right.
And what would be your motive?
It's the millennium.
Motives are incidental.
Millennium?
Millennium, I like that.
That's good. "It's the millennium."
Good kid.
"Millennium." Good word, my man.
Now, you're telling me
that's not a killer?
Sure is quiet.
God, look at this place.
It's The Town That Dreaded Sundown.
Yeah, I saw that movie.
It's about a killer in Texas, huh?
Hey, Sid, just think,
if they make a movie about you,
who's gonna play you?
I shudder to think.
I see you as a young Meg Ryan, myself.
Thanks, Dewey. With my luck,
they'd cast Tori Spelling.
I'm just gonna be a few minutes.
You girls don't go too far.
Is Billy gonna be there tonight?
He better not be.
I told Stu to keep his mouth shut.
I think we can live without
the endorphin rush for one night.
Billy's right, you know. Whenever
he touches me, I just can't relax.
So you have a few intimacy issues as
a result of your mother's untimely death.
It's no big deal, Sid. You'll thaw out.
Yeah, but he has been so patient with me,
you know, with all this sex stuff.
How many guys will put up
with a girlfriend who's sexually anorexic?
Billy and his penis
don't deserve you, all right?
Dewey, where the hell you been?
I was keeping an eye on Sidney.
Thought you quit.
I did, but damn it...
Dewey, Vital Phone just faxed us.
Those calls are listed to Neil Prescott,
Sidney's father.
He made the calls with a cellular phone.
It's been confirmed.
Well, there's no way his cellular
could've been cloned?
There's more. Guess what tomorrow is?
The anniversary of his wife's death.
We'll keep the roadblocks and the curfew
in effect through the night.
If he's not picked up by morning,
then we'll do a house-to-house.
Where's Sidney?
She's with my sister.
You want me to bring her in?
Not just yet. Let's find Neil first,
make sure he's our man.
You stay close to Sidney.
Don't let her out of your sight.
Yes, sir.
All right. You girls have fun.
Not too much fun, or I'll bust ya.
- Bye.
- Bye, Sid.
We are here.
Yeah!
Oh, that's superb.
You guys are tardy for the party
so we started without you.
My man! Yeah!
Well, were we spotted?
I don't think so. Now get the camera.
Ma'am...
Sorry, I didn't mean to scare you.
Deputy, that's okay.
What brings you to these parts?
Well, you just never know
when or where a story will break.
Not much of a story here.
Just a bunch of kids cutting it loose.
Then what are you doing here?
Just keeping an eye on things.
I'm gonna check the party out.
Do you mind if I join you?
Not at all.
Let me just get my coat.
All right.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Oh, yeah.
How many Evil Dead?
- Yeah!
- How many Hellraiser?
Hellraiser right here.
The Fog, Terror Train, Prom Night.
How come Jamie Lee Curtis
is in all of these movies?
She's the... scream queen.
I mean, with a set of lungs like that,
she should be.
Yeah.
Tits. See?
I'll get it.
Hey, Tate, grab me another beer,
would you?
There's beer in the garage.
What am I, the beer wench?
She was nominated.
- She was nominated for Terror Train.
- You are not gonna believe who's here.
It's that chick from Top Story.
- Gale Weathers?
- Here.
You're underage, son.
I'm kidding. Have a good time.
Watch the driving.
- Dewey?
- Hi.
Dewey?
What is she doing here?
She's with me.
I'm just checking things out.
So you did. Now leave.
And take your media muff with you.
- I just think you're awesome.
- Thank you very much.
- I watch your show religiously.
- That's great.
- Hey.
I'm getting a camera.
- Have you found my father?
- I'm afraid not.
Should I be worried?
Not yet.
Jesus!
Tatum, it's okay.
Shit.
Hey, shitheads!
Hello?
Shit. Piss.
Is that you, Randy?
Cute. And what movie is this from?
I Spit On Your Garage?
Lose the outfit.
If Sidney sees it, she'll flip.
You wanna play psycho killer?
Can I be the helpless victim?
Okay, let's see.
No, please don't kill me, Mr. Ghostface.
I want to be in the sequel.
Cut, Casper. That's a wrap.
Randy, what the hell are you doing?
Don't... What?
Stop!
Fucker!
No! No!
Happy curfew.
Nice party, Stu.
Tatum, come on!
Nobody here but us chickens!
- Do you know where she is?
- No, I haven't seen her.
Billy, hey.
Billy. What are you doing here?
I was hoping I could talk to Sid alone.
You know, if Tatum sees you here,
she'll draw blood.
Tell you what, why don't you guys
go up to my parents' room?
You know, you guys can talk
whatever.
"Subtlety," Stu, you should look it up.
No, it's okay. We do need to talk.
What's Leatherface doing here?
He came to make up.
There goes my chance with Sid. Damn it.
As if. That's all I'm saying. As if.
Oh, really, Alicia?
As if.
I'm gonna go check on them.
Come on!
Okay, everyone.
It was nice to meet all of you.
Thank you.
You're a genius.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
- I got a delay.
- How long is it?
I don't know. What'd it take you
to walk from the house, 30 seconds?
It'll be fine. Just record it.
- All right.
- The placement is perfect.
Tell me, Kenneth,
has a cheesy tabloid journalist
ever won the Pulitzer?
First time for everything.
You're damn right.
So...
Look, I'm sorry.
I've been selfish,
and I want to apologize.
No. Billy, I'm
the one who's been selfish
and self-absorbed
with all this post-traumatic stress.
You lost your mom.
Yeah, I know, but you're right.
Enough is enough. I can't wallow
in the grief process forever, and...
And I can't keep lying to myself
about who my mom was.
Yeah, I think I'm really...
scared
that I'm gonna turn out just like her,
you know?
Like the bad seed or something.
And I know it doesn't make sense.
Yeah, it does.
It's like Jodie Foster
in Silence of the Lambs
when she keeps having flashbacks
of her dead father.
But this is life.
This isn't a movie.
Sure it is, Sid.
It's all... it's all a movie. It's all
one great big movie.
Only you can't pick your genre.
Why can't I be a Meg Ryan movie?
Or even a good porno?
- What?
- You heard me.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
I think so.
Look, look. Here it comes.
Oh, man,
the color of the blood is all wrong.
Now why do they do that? It's too red!
Wait, here comes another one.
Here, here...
Yes! Yes!
Predictable. I knew he was gonna bite it.
How can you watch this shit over and over?
When do we see breasts?
I want to see Jamie Lee's breasts.
- When do we see Jamie Lee's breasts?
- Yes. Yes!
Breasts? Not until Trading Places in '83.
Jamie Lee was always the virgin
in horror movies.
She never showed her tits
till she went legits.
Could afford a decent pair.
What'd you say?
That's why she always outsmarted
the killer in the chase scene at the end.
Only virgins can do that.
Don't you know the rules?
What rules?
You don't...
Jesus Christ! You don't know the rules?
Have an aneurysm, why don't you?
There are certain rules
that one must abide by
in order to successfully survive
a horror movie.
For instance, number one,
you can never have sex.
No! No!
Big no-no! Big no-no!
I'd be a dead man.
Sex equals death, okay?
Number two,
you can never drink or do drugs.
No, the sin factor.
This is sin.
It's an extension of number one.
And number three, never, ever, ever,
under any circumstances, say,
"I'll be right back,"
'cause you won't be back.
I'm getting another beer. You want one?
- Yeah, sure.
- I'll be right back!
You see, you push the laws,
and you end up dead, okay?
I'll see you in the kitchen with a knife.
Only virgins can outsmart the killer
in the big chase scene at the end.
Don't you know the rules?
- What rules?
- You don't know the rules?
There are certain rules that one must abide
by in order to successfully survive...
Boring.
The sheriff just radioed.
Somebody reported a car in the bushes
down the road.
I'm gonna go check it out.
You care to join me?
I'd love to.
If you're sure it's all right.
Ma'am, I'm the deputy of this town.
Be right back.
You see, you push the laws
and you end up dead, okay?
Excuse me, ma'am.
I thought maybe we'd walk.
It's such a nice night out.
I got a flashlight.
You're not scared, are you?
No.
- All right.
- Great.
Do you know what that constellation is?
No. What is it?
I don't know. That's why I was asking you.
Take it easy, guys. You guys drive safe.
- So what happened to Tatum, Stu?
- Probably got pissed at me and bailed.
- Bye.
I'm just kidding. I'm just kidding you.
Hey.
Look! Here comes the obligatory tit shot.
- Yes!
- Lovely!
Oh, my God.
I'll leave you guys alone.
You are so
amazing.
Hello?
Yeah.
Holy shit.
No...
Listen up.
They found Principal Himbry dead.
He was gutted and hung
from the goalpost on the football field.
What are we waiting for?
Let's go over there
before they pry him down.
Hey.
Hey, where'd he say he was?
The football field! Come on!
Where you guys going?
We were just getting to the good part.
Hello?
Yeah.
Come on! Let's go!
So, is Dewey your real name?
No, it's Dwight.
Dwight?
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
Dewey's just something I got stuck with
a long time ago.
Well, I like it.
Sexy.
Sexy?
It's just this town's way
of not taking me serious.
What about Gale Weathers?
Sounds like I'm a meteorologist
or something.
People treat me like I'm the Antichrist
of television journalism.
I don't think you're that bad.
- No?
- No.
I think that's just 'cause
you kind of like me.
They sure are coming fast.
Slow down. Freeze!
I'm sorry.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I'm on duty.
Is that what you're looking for?
My whole life.
- Damn.
- What?
- What is it?
- This is Neil Prescott's car.
- Sidney's father?
- Yeah.
Jesus. What's he doing here?
We got to get back.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Who'd you call?
What?
Well, I don't know. When you're arrested,
you're allowed one phone call,
so I was just curious. Who'd you call?
I called my dad.
No. Sheriff Burke called your dad.
I saw him.
Yeah. But when I called,
I didn't get an answer.
You don't still think it was me, do you?
No.
I was just thinking if it were you,
it'd be a very clever way
to throw me off track.
You know, using your one phone call
to call me
so that I wouldn't think it was you.
That's all.
Really?
What do I have to do to prove to you
that I'm not a killer?
Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
- Sidney.
Billy, watch out!
Sid.
Shit.
Help me, somebody! Help me!
Help me!
No, Jamie.
Watch out.
Watch out, Jamie. You know he's around.
You... You know...
There he is. I told you.
I told you. He's right around the corner.
Jamie... Jamie.
Jamie, look behind you.
Look behind you. Turn around.
Behind you. Turn...
Behind you.
Behind you, Jamie.
Jamie, turn around.
All right! You turned around.
Help me! Help!
Let me in!
- The killer's after me. He's in the house.
- Where?
Wait a minute.
There's a camera in the house. Look.
Behind you!
- Oh, shit.
- No.
Jamie, Jamie...
- Behind you, kid!
- Randy!
- Behind you!
- Look around.
Shit.
- What?
- We're on a 30-second delay.
Oh, my God.
- Is there a phone in the van?
- Yeah.
Lock yourself in it.
Call the sheriff for backup.
Be careful.
Neil?
Mr. Prescott?
Kenny, I need the cellular!
Kenny!
- 911.
- What's going on?
Oh, God.
Oh, God, Kenny, I'm sorry,
but get off my fucking windshield!
Stop!
No!
Dewey!
Dewey, where are you?
Sidney?
Dewey!
Shit.
Hello? Help me, please.
I'm at Stu Macher's house on Turner Lane.
It's 261 Turner Lane. Please!
He's gonna try and kill me!
Oh, God!
Sidney!
Sidney, Jesus,
we got to get the fuck out of here!
- Stop right there!
- Don't shoot! It's me!
I found Tatum.
She's dead! I think Stu did it.
- Don't listen to him, Sidney!
- Stay back.
- Stu did it!
- He killed Billy.
- He killed my Tatum. He killed Billy.
- Stu did it.
- No, I didn't!
- He's lying!
Sidney, baby, please give me that gun.
Give me that gun! He killed Billy.
No, I didn't, Sid. He did it!
He did it, Sidney!
Please, I didn't do it. He did it. Please!
- Please, Sidney!
- Fuck you both!
- Please.
- No! No!
Sidney!
- Open up, Sid!
- We won't make it!
Help me, he's gone crazy!
- Sidney!
- Go away!
Sidney?
Leave me alone.
- Sid.
- Billy.
- Billy! Are you okay?
- I'm okay.
Oh, God. I thought you were dead.
No. I mean, I got stuck pretty bad...
Get up.
- You okay?
- You're bleeding.
- Oh, my God.
- Gotta get help.
No! He's out there!
No. Give me the gun. Give me the gun.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
Careful.
- Please help me!
- Get in. Get in.
Stu's flipped out! He's gone mad!
We all go a little mad sometimes.
- No, Billy!
- Oh, fuck!
Anthony Perkins, Psycho.
Corn syrup.
Same stuff they used
for pig's blood in Carrie.
No. No.
Stu, help me, please.
Surprise, Sidney.
No!
Oh, now.
What's the matter, Sidney?
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Why are you doing this?
It's all part of the game, Sidney.
- It's called Guess How I'm Gonna Die!
- Fuck you!
No, no, no, no. We already played
that game, remember?
You lost.
See, fun and games, Sidney.
See, we ask you a question.
If you get it wrong
you die.
If you get it right, you die.
You're crazy, both of you.
Actually we prefer the term psychotic.
You'll never get away with this.
Oh, no?
Tell that to Cotton Weary.
You wouldn't believe
how easy he was to frame.
Watch a few movies, take a few notes.
It was fun.
- No!
- Where you going?
Why?
Why did you kill my mother?
You hear that, Stu?
I think she wants a motive.
I don't believe in motives, Sid.
- I mean, did Norman Bates have a motive?
- No.
Did they ever really decide why
Hannibal Lecter liked to eat people?
Don't think so.
See, it's a lot scarier
when there's no motive, Sid.
We did your mom a favor, Sid.
That woman was a slutbag whore
who flashed her shit all over town
like she was Sharon Stone or something.
Yeah, we put her out of her misery,
'cause let's face it, Sidney,
your mother was no Sharon Stone.
Is that motive enough for you?
How about this?
Your slut mother was fucking my father...
and she's the reason
my mom moved out and abandoned me.
How's that for a motive?
Maternal abandonment
causes serious deviant behavior.
Certainly fucked you up.
It made you have sex with a psychopath.
That's right. You gave it up.
Now you're no longer a virgin.
I said "virgin."
Now you gotta die. Those are the rules.
Just pretend it's all a scary movie, Sid.
How do you think it's gonna end?
This is the greatest part!
You're gonna love this.
We got a surprise for you, Sidney.
Yeah, you're gonna love this one.
It's a scream, baby!
Hold on a sec. I'll be right back.
Know what time it is, Sid?
It's after midnight.
It's your mom's anniversary.
Congratulations. We killed her exactly
one year ago today.
Attention.
What do we have
behind door number three, Sidney?
- Daddy!
- Hold it. That's enough.
Guess we won't be needing
this anymore, huh?
And, oh, look at this. Ring, ring.
Won't need this.
Got the ending figured out yet, Sid?
Come on, Sidney,
you think about it now, huh?
Your daddy's the chief suspect.
We cloned his cellular.
Evidence is all right there, baby.
What if your father snapped,
your mother's anniversary set him off,
and he went on a murder spree
killing everyone?
Except for Billy and me.
We were left for dead.
Then he kills you
and shoots himself in the head.
Perfect ending.
I thought of that.
Watch this.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Yeah! I'm ready, baby! Hit it!
Giddyap! Yeah, man! Giddyap! Hit it!
Good one, man! Jesus!
Oh, shit! My turn.
Don't forget.
Stay to the side and don't go too deep.
Okay. I'll remember.
Fuck!
Fuck! God damn it, Stu!
Sorry, Billy.
I guess I got a little too zealous, huh?
- Give me the knife.
- No.
Give me the knife!
Now!
You see, Sid? Everybody dies, but us.
Everybody dies, but us!
We get to carry on and plan the sequel
'cause let's face it, baby,
these days, you gotta have a sequel!
You sick fucks.
You've seen one too many movies.
No, Sid, don't you blame the movies!
Movies don't create psychos.
Movies make psychos more creative!
Stop it, man, would you? All right?
I can't take any more.
I'm feeling a little woozy here!
All right.
You get the gun,
and I'll untie Pops, okay?
Now!
Okay.
Houston, we have a problem here.
What?
The gun, man. The gun.
I put it right here, and it's not there.
Where the fuck is it?
Right here, asshole.
- Man, I thought she was dead.
- She looked dead, man. Still does.
I've got an ending for you.
"The reporter left for dead
in the news van
comes to, stumbles on you two dipshits,
"finds the gun,
foils your plan, and saves the day."
I like that ending.
I know something you don't.
Yeah, man!
Yeah.
So sweet.
Works better without the safety on.
"This is Gale Weathers, signing off."
Baby, you are gonna love this.
Shit.
What?
Where are they? Where are they?
I don't know, Billy, but I'm hurting, man!
Fuck!
Should I let the machine get it?
- Hello?
- Are you alone in the house?
Bitch! You bitch! Where the fuck are you?
Not so fast.
We're gonna play a little game.
It's called
Guess Who Just Called the Police
and Reported Your Sorry Motherfucking Ass!
Find her, you dipshit! Get up!
I can't, Billy. You cut me too deep.
I think I'm dying here, man.
Talk to her. Talk to her.
Hello?
Aw, Stu, Stu, Stu.
What's your motive? Billy's got one.
The police are on their way.
What are you gonna tell them?
Peer pressure. I'm far too sensitive...
I'm gonna rip you up, you bitch!
Just like your fucking mother!
You've gotta find me first,
you pansy-ass mama's boy!
Fuck!
Fucking hit me with the phone, dick!
Fucker, where are you?
You fuck!
Did you really call the police?
You bet your sorry ass I did.
My mom and dad are gonna be so mad at me.
Bitch!
My eyes!
I always had a thing for you, Sid!
God.
Bitch.
In your dreams.
Sid! I'm sorry. It's all right.
Oh, my God, Randy.
I thought you were dead.
I probably should be. I never thought
I'd be so happy to be a virgin.
Fucker!
Say hello to your mother.
It's okay.
Guess I remembered the safety that time,
you bastard.
Careful.
This is the moment when the supposedly
dead killer comes back to life
for one last scare.
Not in my movie.
Dad.
Randy, help me out.
Are you okay?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Hang in there, buddy.
- All right.
- It collapses.
- Where's Gale?
Okay, I think it's gonna go
something like this. Just stay with me.
Hi. This is Gale Weathers
with an exclusive eyewitness account
of this amazing breaking story.
Several more local teens are dead,
bringing to an end the harrowing mystery
of the mass killing
that has terrified this peaceful community
like the plot of some scary movie.
It all began with a scream over 911
and ended in a bloodbath
that has rocked the town of Woodsboro,
all played out here
in this peaceful farmhouse,
far from the crimes and the sirens
of the larger cities
that its residents have fled.
Okay, let's take it back to one.
Come on. Move it.
This is my big shot. Let's go.