...to give further details
of the case.
It is believed that
the indictment
is only one of a series
to be handed down as a result
of a special grand jury
investigation.
Grave robbing in Texas
is this hour's top news story.
An informant led officers
of the Muerto County
Sheriff's Department
to a cemetery just outside
the small rural Texas community
of Newt early this morning.
Officers there discovered
what appeared to be
a grisly work of art,
the remains of a badly
decomposed body
wired to a large monument.
A second body was
found in a ditch
near the perimeter
of the cemetery.
Subsequent investigation
has revealed
at least a dozen empty crypts,
and it's feared more will turn
up as the probe continues.
Deputies report that
in some instances
only parts of a corpse
had been removed;
the head or in some cases
the extremities removed,
the remainder of the
corpse left intact.
Evidence indicates the
robberies have occurred
over a period of time.
Sheriff Jesus Maldonado
refused to give details
of the ghoulish case
and said only that
he did have strong evidence
linking the crime to elements
outside the state.
Area residents have reportedly
converged on the cemetery,
fearing the remains of relatives
have been removed.
No suspects are in custody
as the investigation
at the scene continues.
Oil storage units continue
to burn out of control
at the huge Texaco refinery
near the Texas-Louisiana border.
Three storage units exploded
into flames during the night
killing at least three workers
and injuring a dozen more.
Fire fighting units from
three Texas cities
continue to battle the blaze
in an effort to confine
40 foot flames.
Smoke from the fire
has reached Houston residents
some 60 miles to the south.
Health officials from
San Francisco reluctantly admit
they may have a cholera epidemic
on their hands.
Some 40 cases of the
highly infectious disease
have been confirmed...
Huston police are puzzled
over an outbreak of violence
apparently touched off
by a suicide.
A young man reportedly angered
by a local television blackout
of a sports event,
jumped from the 10th story
window of his apartment.
A second man who allegedly
threatened to leap to his death
from the same window
but was restrained by police.
Witnesses to the incident
reported...
...Was taken into custody.
She offered no explanation
for the attack.
The Lieutenant was treated
for minor wounds at
Ben Taub Hospital and released.
A 16 story building under
construction in downtown Atlanta
collapsed today killing
at least 29 persons.
The engineering firm responsible
for the structural design
of the building
could offer no explanation
of the collapse.
The local construction crew say
there was no logical reason
for the collapse
and suspect sabotage.
Police in Gary, Indiana have
been unable to identify
the bodies of a young man
and woman discovered
by children...
...Stab wounds
and their features carved away.
The man's genitals
had been removed
and the police first identified
the victims as two women.
Just stay right there.
You okay?
Franklin!
Ah!
You okay?
I was...
Shit.
Okay...
This heat is
just driving me crazy.
I don't know if I can
take much more.
Listen,
"The condition of retrogradation
is contrary or inharmonious
to the regular direction
of actual movement in the zodiac
and is, in that respect, evil.
Hence, when malefic planets
are in retrograde."
And Saturn's malefic, okay.
"Their maleficence
is increased."
Have you been doing
those Reader's Digest
word power columns again?
Jerry, it just means that
Saturn's a bad influence.
It's just particularly
a bad influence now
because it's in retrograde.
Hey, man,
you believe all that stuff
your old lady's hawkin' me?
I don't know.
My granddaddy's buried here.
Could we find out if anything
happened to him?
What's your granddaddy's name?
Honey, that big heavy feller
that's standing with that
flashlight in his hand,
that's the Sheriff.
You go tell him your
granddaddy's buried in there.
- Okay.
- He'll let you in.
Thank you.
Say, fella, I'm going to run off
with your girl a minute.
You don't mind do you?
Honey, I'll get you to
the Sheriff. Come on.
Hey, folks,
let us through here,
this girl's granddaddy's
buried here.
Been in there the whole time,
unbeknownst to Clyde.
Clyde didn't know either.
They didn't know why...
Things happen hereabout
they don't tell about.
I see things.
You see,
they say it's
just an old man talking.
You laugh at an old man.
There's them that laughs
and knows better.
Yes, they're sure.
The man said they could tell
if the grave had been dug up.
Franklin, don't worry,
I saw it myself.
It didn't look dug up to me.
Oh, what's that?
What smells?
What is that stench?
Roll up the window.
Hey...
that's the old slaughterhouse.
That's where grandpa
used to sell his cattle.
Hey, we got an uncle
that works at one of those
places outside of Ft. Worth.
Hey, you see those
buildings there?
That's where they kill them.
They bash them in the head
with a big sledgehammer.
Oh, that's awful.
It usually wouldn't kill "em
on the first lick.
I mean, they'd start squealing
and freaking out and everything,
and they'd have to come up
and bash 'em two or three times.
And then sometimes
it wouldn't kill them.
I mean,
they would skin them sometimes
even before they were even dead.
Oh, that's horrible.
People shouldn't kill
animals for food.
Well, they don't do it
like that anymore.
Now they got this big air gun
that shoots a bolt into their
skull and then retracts it.
It's just boom!
It goes boom!
And boom!
Franklin, I like meat.
Please change the subject.
That's terrible but
it's still going on.
Oh, man, it's hot in here.
Hitchhiker.
Should we pick him up?
Oh, yeah, man, pick him up,
he'll asphyxiate out there.
What does he look like?
The son of a bitch
is going to smell
just like the slaughterhouse.
Oh, give the guy a break.
He can sit by Franklin.
What do you want to do?
- Oh, he's weird looking.
- Pick him up, man.
No!
Well, I think we
just picked up Dracula.
Where you headed, man?
South.
You work at that place?
Oh, no.
How did you get
stuck way out here?
I was at the slaughterhouse.
I got an uncle that works
at a slaughterhouse.
Hey, my, my
brother worked there.
My, my grandfather, too.
My family's always been in meat.
A whole family of Dracula's.
Hey, man, did you go in
that slaughter room
or whatever they call it?
The place where they shoot
the cattle in the head
with that big air gun thing?
Oh, that,
that...that gun's no good.
I was in there once
with my uncle.
The old way...with a sledge!
See, that was better.
They died better that way.
How come?
I thought the gun was better?
Oh, no, no.
With the new way,
people are put out of jobs.
You do that?
Look.
I was the killer!
Damn.
Let me see them.
They don't send the heads away.
You took these, huh?
Yeah.
Franklin!
See, they make...head cheese.
They...
they take the head
and they boil it,
except for the tongue,
and they scrape all the flesh
away from the bone.
They, they use everything,
they don't throw nothing way.
They use the jowls
and the muscles
and the eyes and the
ligaments and everything.
- Oh.
- Look at this.
The nose and the gums
and all the flesh
and they boil it down
into a big jelly of fat.
Wow, I didn't know that's
what was in that stuff.
It's really good.
You like it?
Oh, yeah, sure, I like it,
it's good.
Oh, it sounds horrible.
Is it possible we could
talk about something else?
Oh, you'd probably like it
if you didn't know
what was in it.
No, I wouldn't and I wish
you'd stop talking about it.
Oh.
Come on, Franklin,
you're making everybody sick.
Oh, all right.
What are you doing?
Hey, man, put that knife up.
Oh, come on.
Oh!
Oh, what are you doing
to yourself?
Oh, my God!
Why are you doing that?
Put the knife away.
I...I have this knife.
You can put that one away too.
It's a good knife.
I'm sure it is, man.
Put it up.
Hey, you took my picture.
Hey, you, you could
take me to my house.
I live right off this road.
Well, I don't know, man,
we're in pretty much of a hurry.
How close is it?
It's real close.
Well, couldn't you just walk?
I mean, if it's so close...
You could have dinner with us.
You like head cheese?
My brother makes it real good.
You'll like it.
I think we better push on, man,
don't you, Jerry?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
It didn't turn out so good.
It's a nice picture.
- You can pay me now.
- Huh?
Two dollars.
It's a good picture.
No, man.
Franklin, give him back
the damn picture.
He wanted Franklin
to pay him for that picture.
- You're kidding?
- No, I'm serious.
What are you doing?
Hey, Jerry, pull us over!
Hey, man, what is that?.
What are you doing?
Hey man,
what are you doing?
Ah, oh, my God!
Oh, I'm about half-ready
to call a cop.
That's the last goddamn
hitchhiker I ever pick up.
Hey, listen to Franklin's
horoscope.
Oh, Sally...
“Travel in the country,
long-range plans,
and upsetting persons around you
could make this a disturbing
and unpredictable day.
The events in the world
are not doing much either
to cheer one up."
That's just perfect.
Franklin,
I think that'll be all right.
And now read Sally's.
- She's a Capricorn.
- Okay.
Oh, no.
Capricorn's ruled by Saturn.
"There are moments when
we cannot believe
that what is happening
is really true.
Pinch yourself and
you may find out that it is."
Okay, everybody out.
Hurry up so we can get goin'.
Here comes somebody.
How are you?
Would you fill her up, please?
I got no gas.
You're out of gas?
My tank's empty.
The transport won't be here
until late this afternoon,
maybe not even until
tomorrow morning.
I told you we should've
stopped to get gas.
Hey, do you know where the
old Franklin place is?
The old Franklin place?
Yeah, it's an old
two-story rock house
and it's sitting up on a hill.
I think you have to turn on
that road back there
but I'm not real sure.
Yeah,
maybe I seen something
like that up that way.
Well, now look,
you boys don't want to go
messin' around no old house.
Well, those things is dangerous.
You're liable to get hurt.
We'll be careful.
You don't want to go fooling
around other folks property.
Some folks don't like it
and they don't mind showing you.
Oh, my father owns it.
That's your Daddy's place, huh?
Yeah.
Look, I got some good
barbeque here.
Why don't you fellas stick
around here awhile?
That transport will be
by in a little while.
Well, you want to get
some barbeque?
Them...them girls, now they,
they don't want to go messing
around no old house.
It's best you stick around here.
You know, we should've asked him
if there's another
gas station around.
Don't you think he would've
told us if there was?
Man, it wouldn't
hurt to ask, you know?
Okay, I'll go ask.
Damn it to hell, we should've
stopped back there for gas.
- Press it.
- I'm pulling it down.
Press it.
There.
Hey, you think this place
has room service?
Franklin, you maniac,
you're tearing up the van.
Oh, yeah,
I just started doing that.
Hey, I bet that's
some of that guy's blood.
Look at that.
You think that's blood?
Yeah, I guess so.
Oh, that's blood all right.
And that guy cut the hell
out of himself.
You think you could do
that to yourself?
I'm not crazy.
Yeah, but you know...
It takes something, though.
I mean, just to do that to
yourself like he did.
God!
Hey, you think I said
something made him mad?
Well, what?
Franklin,
you're crazier than he was.
Hey, I got us some barbeque.
Newt's the closest place
to get gas.
Aw.
We're going out to
Grandpa's place, aren't we?
Let's go.
Well, there's a creek,
you could go swimming.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
Come on, Sally, we're going
out to Grandpa's place.
Let's go.
Hey, that guy smeared blood
all over the van.
It looks like he was trying
to write something.
What?
What'd he do?
Did he write something
on the van?
Let me see your knife.
Thank you.
Franklin, if we run out of gas
before we get back to
that service station
you're towing us
back in your chair.
Hey,
you think that guy's just
trying to scare us by,
you know, blowing up
my picture like that?
Aw, I wish they hadn't let
the place fall apart.
It looks like the birthplace
of Bela Lugosi.
- Hey, I'm scared.
- I'll help you with that.
See that window over there...?
Hey, watch my arms,
watch my arms.
Watch my arm. Watch out.
Go straight.
- Come on down.
- You got it?
- Hey.
- I'll get you from here.
I don't see that,
that smear that guy made.
- Oh, man.
- Now, that's weird.
I wonder if that
means something.
It's the mark of Zorro.
He's going to get you.
- Jerry, come on.
- Kirk, why don't you wash it off, okay?
I want to show you the inside.
- Jerry!
- Okay.
Hey, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
- Wait a minute.
- Come on, Kirk.
Here, man, you wash it off.
Hey, you don't think that guy
would try and follow us,
do you?
What for?
Where's my knife?
Kirk?
It looks like it must've been a
nursery room or something.
- Oh, this is great.
- Oh, this is my room.
I got to stay here once
when I was eight years old.
Right after my
grandmother died.
What happened?
What happened to
my grandmother?
Yeah. She died.
What do you think of
the wallpaper?
I think it's seen some
better days, personally.
No, these animals used
to talk me to sleep
when I was little kid.
- Look at the zebras, see?
- Uh-huh.
I had these fascination
for the zebras.
Sally!
Hee, hee, hee, hee,
hee, hee, hee, hee.
Hee, hee, hee, hee.
Hee, hee, hee, hee, hee, hee.
“Come on, Franklin.
It's gonna be a fun trip.”
If I have any more fun today,
I don't think I'm going
to be able to take it.
Ah!
Ow, that hurt!
Oh.
Hey, Franklin.
Hey, Franklin, how's your arm?
Didn't you say there was a
swimming hole around here?
Yeah.
Well, Pam and I would like
to go swimming, man.
There used to be a trail down
between those two old sheds.
Come on, we'll find it.
Are Jerry and Sally going?
No. We'll see you
in an hour or so.
Yeah...
We'll see you
in about an hour or so.
Sally?
Sally--
Sally!
...Zero in the world.
Just shoot him and put us
out of our misery.
There's snakes!
- There's spiders!
- Stop it!
There's scorpions!
Man-eating lizards!
Kirk, help.
- Kirk!
- Ow.
- Oh.
Crap.
This must be it.
Oh, are you okay?
How the hell did Franklin
ever get down here anyway?
Somebody must've carried him
when he was little.
Franklin never was little.
Gasoline!
I can leave them my guitar,
you know,
give 'em a couple bucks.
We got to come back
by here anyway,
I can pick up my guitar and
give him a couple more dollars
and bring him back some gas.
They don't want your guitar.
They're not going to want
to sell us some gas.
Let's just go back now.
Hey, come here.
Come here and look at this.
A generator.
What?
For electricity.
Hey, hello in there!
Is anybody here?
Hello, is anybody home?
I got something for you.
Ah!
Oh.
Let's go!
Hello?
Hello?!
Hey, Pam, come look at this.
Let's go!
Hello?
Is anybody home?
Hey, Pam...
Hello?
Kirk?
Oh, God!
Kirk!
He's going to get you, Franklin.
He's coming to get you.
You don't think it
means anything?
We'll protect you
if he tries to get you.
I'll bet it's about me.
He's going to kill you,
Franklin.
It probably doesn't mean
anything, huh?
You worry too much.
Well, he couldn't
find us anyway.
I mean,
he doesn't even know our names.
I gave him your name, Franklin.
I told him where you live.
I even gave him your zip code.
He's going to kill you.
Jerry.
What are you doing?
I can't find my knife.
That knife won't
do you any good.
He likes that knife, remember?
When did you have it last?
Well, I didn't have it last.
You had it last.
I gave it to you, remember?
What did you do with it?
Well, I don't know.
Didn't I give it back to you?
No, I didn't have it
when I got out of the van.
You just never gave it
back to me.
All right, I'll look for it.
Listen, I think I'll
walk down to the creek
before it gets too dark.
How do I get there, Franklin?
Well, there's a trail down there
between them two old sheds.
Can I go, too?
I think you better stay here.
All right.
I can't find it.
Are you mad at me?
No, I'm not mad at you.
You really are mad, huh?
Oh, I don't blame you.
I'm
Kirk!
You really didn't want me
to come, did you?
Oh, Franklin, I'm just tired.
It's been a long day.
Sally, did you believe
in all that stuff
that Pam was telling about
Saturn and retrograde
and all that?
I don't know.
Everything means something,
I guess.
Yeah.
You don't think that guy
would try and follow us, do you?
Well, I mean, there's no way
that he could follow us.
He's probably afraid
Kirk will kill him.
Sally?
What now?
Oh, nothing.
Never mind.
Kirk!
Hello?
Is anybody home?
Excuse me,
I'm looking for some friends.
Hello?
Is anybody here?
Damn...
Kirk?
Are you guys in there?
Hey, guys, quit playing games.
Quit goofing on me.
Pam, is that you?
Okay, you guys.
Come on out.
Come on!
Kirk?
Ooh!
They must be lost.
They don't have a flashlight
or anything.
If they're not back in a minute
we've got to go look for them.
Well, well,
what if we get lost, too?
Sally, we ought to go to that
gas station and get help.
I'm not leaving here
without Jerry.
Jerry!
- Jerry!
Hey!
They'll probably be back
in a minute or so.
Sally, we ought to go
to that gas station.
Sally?
I think we ought to go.
Are the keys in the van?
Could I see the flashlight
for a minute?
What for?
Franklin,
let me see the flashlight.
I'm gonna to go look for them.
You don't have to go.
Now, Sally, don't go.
I don't think that's a
good idea, Sally.
I don't think you ought to go.
Look, I'm going to honk
the horn one more time.
Just give me the flashlight!
No, now, I'm...
I'm going to honk the horn
and we're going to wait
a minute,
and then if they don't come,
well, we'll go.
All right?
Sally, they took the keys.
- We don't have any keys.
- Oh.
They took the keys with them.
Stop it!
Stop it! Franklin!
- Jerry took the keys with him.
- Give me that flashlight!
No, Sally, we can't go!
Look, what if they came
back and we weren't here?
Franklin,
give me that flashlight!
No, I've got to take
the flashlight.
- All right, all right.
- I'm going to go look for them.
Give me that flashlight!
I'll go with you.
I'll go with you, all right?
No, Sally, come on,
I'll go with you.
Sally, I'll go with you
but I'm going to
keep the flashlight.
Give me the flashlight!
Look, look, I'll go with you,
I'll go with you.
I can't push you down that hill!
Sally, look, I know.
Oh!
Look, I'll go with you
but I'm going to hold--
Never mind,
I'll just go without it.
All right, all right.
Sally, wait!
Sally, wait a minute!
I'm coming with you.
Sally?
Hold up a minute now.
All right, let's go.
Let's go.
I'll go with you.
Sally, I can't keep up with you.
Sally?
Sally, wait a minute.
Hold up.
Jerry!
- Jerry!
Wait.
I thought I heard something.
There's a light.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Oh.
It looks like a house.
Well, come on, push.
Come on, push.
Push down. There.
It's a house.
Yeah?
I can't see it very well.
Oh, Franklin,
this is impossible.
Come on, Sally.
Get back and push down.
This is impossible...
I hear something out there.
Look!
Hey, Jerry!
- Jerry!
Sally, I hear something.
Stop.
Stop!
Somebody please!
Help!
Help me please!
Help me! Help me!
Help!
Please! Please!
Please help me!
Please.
Help!
Help me!
Help! Help!
Oh God help, help!
Close the door.
Whoa there, whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa,
come over here. Whoa, whoa.
...Trying to kill me.
Help me
Whoa, now.
You're all right, you're okay.
- Oh now, take it easy.
- Call the police.
He might come...
Now what happened?
He, he killed...
Now, now, take it easy.
He killed Franklin.
I don't know.
Call the police!
Take it easy.
And Jerry...
I, I don't, I don't know
what happened to the others.
There's nobody out there now.
Come on.
Come on now, take it easy.
Come on, take it easy.
Oh, please...
What happened?
Please, call the police.
There's no phone here.
We...we have to, we have to
drive over to Childress
Yeah, yeah.
Now, you take it easy.
Take it easy.
I'll get the truck.
Now, now, take it easy.
- Take it easy.
- Don't go.
- Don't go...
Area weather is expected
to continue warm
and clear to party cloudy
for tomorrow with no
chance of precipitation
in the immediate forecast
The high today is going
to be in the upper nineties.
Expect a low tonight
of 81 degrees.
Our current temperature is 96
with winds out of the southeast
at three miles a hour.
Humidity 98,
barometer at 29.9 and rising.
Acting on a tip from
Clyde Haywood of Newt,
the Muerto County
Sheriff's office
began an investigation
early this morning
in the Muerto County Cemetery,
opening crypts and mausoleums
where there was evidence
of tampering.
The Sheriff's deputies have
found a reported dozen coffins
robbed of all or part
of their contents.
According to Sheriff Jesus
Maldonado there was instances
in which only the heads
and extremities were removed
and others in which only a hand
or foot had been removed,
with the remainder
of the cadaver left intact.
Maldonado had hinted
that he had information
linking the robberies
to a large and well organized
west coast jewel theft ring.
He declined to suggest
any reason
for them to mutilate
the cadavers...
What are you doing?
Now, you ain't got
no need to worry.
No!
Now, now,
you just cooperate, young lady,
and we'll have no trouble.
Now, listen, this is...
What do you want?
Now, there's,
no need to do that.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
No!
Had to lock up
and get the lights.
Cost of electricity
is enough to drive a man
out of business.
I hope you're not too
uncomfortable down there.
You got nothing to worry about.
You, you just take it easy
and we'll, we'll be there soon.
Now, now, now, now.
There's no,
no need to do that, no.
We'll, we'll
be over this in a bit.
Hang on.
Half-wits.
Little coon shits...
Come here,
you nap-haired idiot!
Where have you been?
I've been out on the road.
You damn fool,
you almost got caught
over at Newt.
No, no, they didn't see me.
They don't know nothing.
I told you to stay away
from that graveyard.
Hey.
I told you and I told you,
I told you never to leave
your brother alone, you...
Get, get at her and get
that girl out of the car.
Get her, get her out of the car.
Get her out of there.
Hopefully your brother
didn't let any of
those kids get away.
Get her in there.
We'll have the whole
county out here.
Don't you got any self-respect?
Look what your brother
did to the door!
Don't he got no,
no pride in his home?
Get her in there.
You damn, fool, you!
You better get
those damn other kids.
Where, where are they, huh?
You goddamn fool, you!
Oh!
I thought you was in a hurry!
Now, where are the kids?
Where are they? Show me!
None of "em get away?
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
Are you sure?
Uh-huh.
You...
You damn fool,
you ruined the door!
Hey, you did good.
She's a nice girl.
You nit-wit.
Get upstairs
and get your Grandpa.
Now, young lady, you just,
you just take it easy
there, now.
Look, we'll, we'll fix you
some supper in a few minutes.
Get back in there!
Get in there!
Now, you just take it easy.
Take it easy.
We'll have you something
to eat right away.
Hey!
Hey, Leatherface!
Give me a hand with Grandpa.
Careful.
Don't drop him.
Help me.
Look, Grandpa, look! Look!
Here, here!
Shut up!
Quiet!
You act like a pack of hounds.
We were just having fun.
You think this is a party?
Please...
You can make them stop.
No, he can't.
Shut your mouths.
Can't be helped, young lady.
- Oh, please...
- Shut up!
You can't let them kill me.
Don't pay him no mind.
You like this face?
You're
crazy!
You got to make them stop!
Please!
He's nothing.
He's just a cook.
Shut up, you bitch hog.
Me and Leatherface
do all the work.
He don't like it.
Ain't that right?
You're just a cook!
Shut your mouth!
You don't understand nothing.
I understand you ain't nothing.
Me and him do all the work.
I, I just can't take no
pleasure in killin'.
Well, there's just some
things you got to do,
don't mean you have to like it.
Oh, please, please...
What do you want?
I'll do anything...anything...
I'll do...I'll do anything
you want.
Make it stop!
No need to torture
the poor girl.
You just shut up!
Remember you're just the cook
and me and him
will handle this.
Then get on with it.
I won't have this.
We ain't in no hurry
because you ain't
going no place.
No...
You hear me?
It heard you
but it don't mean much.
No sense in waiting.
I got to open up in the morning.
I been...I been thinking about
letting Grandpa have some fun.
You always said he's the best.
Oh, he's the best, all right.
Let's let him have a whack.
Hey, Grandpa,
we going to let you
have this one!
Let's let him have a whack.
Now you, you just hush.
It won't hurt none.
Why, old Grandpa is the
best killer there ever was.
Why, it never took more
than one lick, they say.
Why, he did sixty in
five minutes once.
They say he could've done more
if the hook and pull gang
could've gotten the beeves
out of the way faster.
Now, now,
now don't you cry none.
Old Grandpa's the best.
It won't hurt a bit.
No! No!
No! No! No! No!
Oh, please don't!
Please! Please!
Please don't!
No, no!
No!
Hit her, Grandpa.
Hit her.
Come on, Grandpa.
Hit that bitch.
Hit her, Grandpa.
Come on.
No.
Come on there, Grandpa.
Come on, Grandpa,
hit that bitch.
Careful there.
Come on, Grandpa.
You're the best, Grandpa,
get her.
Get the hammer.
Go ahead, go ahead, get her.
Come on.
Give me the hammer
"I get her.
Get her, get her, Grandpa.
Give me that hammer.
I'll get her.
Let me get her!
Help!
Help! Help!
Ah!
Go!