People do not give it credence
that a young girl could leave home
and go off in the winter time
to avenge her father's blood.
But it did happen.
I was just fourteen years of age
when a coward by the name of
Tom Chaney shot my father down.
And robbed him of
his life, and his horse.
And two California gold pieces
that he carried in his trouser band.
Chaney was a hired man.
And Papa had taken
him up to Fort Smith
to help lead back a string of
mustang ponies he'd bought.
In town, Chaney
had fallen to drink,
and cards, and
lost all his money.
He got it into his head
he'd been cheated,
and went back to the boarding
house for his Henry rifle.
When Papa tried to intervene,
Chaney shot him.
Chaney fled.
He could have walked his horse,
for not a soul in that city could
be bothered to give chase.
No doubt Chaney fancied
himself scott free.
But he was wrong.
You must pay for everything in
this world, one way or another.
There is nothing free
except the grace of God.
Is that the man?
That is my father.
If you would like to kiss him,
it would be all right.
He has gone home.
Praise the Lord.
Why is it so much?
The quality of the casket
and of the embalming.
The lifelike appearance
requires time and art.
And the chemicals come dear.
The particulars are in your bill.
If you'd like to kiss him,
it would be all right.
Thank you, the spirit has flown.
Your wire said fifty dollars.
You did not specify that
he was to be shipped.
Well sixty dollars is every cent we have.
That leaves nothing for our board.
Yarnell, you can see to the body's transport
to the train station and accompany it home.
I will have to sleep here tonight.
I still have to collect father's things
and see to some other business.
Your mama didn't say nothing
about you settling no business here.
It's business Mama didn't know about.
It's all right, Yarnell, I dismiss you.
I am not sure.
Tell Mama not to sign
anything until I return home
and see that Papa is buried
in his Mason's apron.
Your terms are agreeable,
if I may pass the night here.
Here, among these people?
- These people?
- I'm expecting three more souls.
Sullivan, Smith, and
His-Tongue-in-the-Rain.
Ladies and gentlemen, beware.
And train up your children in
the way that they should go.
You see what has become of me.
Because of drink,
I killed a man.
In a trifling quarrel
over a pocket knife.
If I had received good
instruction as a child...
Can you point out the sheriff?
Him with the mustaches.
I would be with my wife and children today.
I do not know what is to become of them.
But I hope and pray that she will not slight
them and compel them to go into low company.
Well...
I killed the wrong man, is the
which of why I'm here.
Had I killed the man I meant to,
I don't believed I'd have been convicted.
I see men out there in that
crowd that's worse than me.
Okay.
Before I am hanged,
I would like to say...
Naw, we ain't arrested him.
Ain't caught up to him,
he lit out for the Territory.
I would think that he's throwed in with
Lucky Ned Pepper, whose gang robbed
a mail hack yesterday
on the Poteau River.
Well, why are you
not looking for him?
I have no authority
in the Indian Nation.
Tom Chaney is the business
of the U.S marshals now.
When will they arrest him?
Not soon, I'm afraid.
The marshals are not well-staffed.
And I'll tell you, frankly,
Chaney's at the end of a long
list of fugitives and malefactors.
Could I hire a marshal
to pursue Tom Chaney?
You have a lot of experience
with bounty hunters, do you?
That is a silly question.
I am here to settle my father's affairs.
- All alone?
- Well I am the person for it.
Mama was never any good at sums,
and she could hardly spell 'cat'.
I intend to see
Papa's killer hanged.
Well, nothing prevents you from offering
a reward and so informing a marshal.
It'd have to be real money though,
to be persuasive.
Chaney's across the river,
in Choctaw Nation.
I will see to the money.
Who's the best marshal?
I'd have to weigh that.
William Waters is
the best tracker.
He's half Comanche, and it is
something to see him cut for sign.
The meanest is
Rooster Cogburn.
He's a pitiless man. Double tough.
Fear don't enter into his thinking.
Hmm, loves to pull a cork.
The best is probably L.T. Quinn.
He brings his prisoners in alive.
Now he may let one slip by,
now and again, but he believes that even the
worst of men is entitled to a fair shake.
Where can I find this Rooster?
The place is occupied.
I know it is occupied, Mr. Cogburn.
As I said, I have business with you.
I have prior business.
You've been at it for quite
some time, Mr. Cogburn.
There is no clock on my business.
The hell with you.
How did you stalk me here?
The sheriff told me
to look in the saloon.
The saloon then referred me here.
We must talk.
Women ain't allowed
in the saloon.
I was not there as a customer.
I am fourteen years old.
The place is occupied.
Will be for some time.
Good evening.
If you would like to sleep in a coffin,
I would be honored.
How much are you
paying for cotton?
Nine and a half for low and middlin',
and ten for ordinary.
We got most of ours out early,
and sold to the Woodson brothers
in Little Rock for eleven cents.
Then I suggest you take the balance
of it to the Woodson brothers.
I did take the
balance to Woodson.
We got ten and a half.
Why'd you come here
to tell me this?
I thought we might shop
around up here next year,
but I guess we're doing
alright in Little Rock.
I'm Mattie Ross.
Daughter of Frank Ross.
Aw, tragic thing.
May I say, your
father impressed me
with his manly qualities. He was a close
trader, but he acted the gentleman.
I propose to sell those ponies
back to you that my father bought.
Well that I fear,
is out of the question.
I will see that they are shipped to
you at my earliest convenience.
We don't want the ponies now.
We don't need them.
Well, that hardly concerns me. Your father
bought the ponies and paid for them,
and there's the end of it.
I have the bill of sale.
And I want $300 for Papa's saddle
horse that was stolen from your stable.
You'll have to take that up with
the man who stole the horse.
Tom Chaney stole the horse
while it was in your care.
You are responsible.
Yeah, I admire your sand.
But I believe you'll find I'm
not liable for such claims.
You were the custodian.
If you were a bank
that were robbed,
you could not simply tell
your depositors to go hang.
I do not entertain hypotheticals.
The world as it is is vexing enough.
Secondly, your evaluation
of the horse is high
by about $200.
How old are you?
If anything,
my price is low.
My Judy was a
fine racing mare.
I've seen her jump an eight-rail fence
with a heavy rider. I'm fourteen.
Oh, well, it's all
very interesting.
The ponies are yours,
take them.
Your father's horse was stolen
by a murderous criminal.
I had provided reasonable protection for
the creature as per our implicit agreement.
My watchman had his teeth knocked
out and can take only soup.
I will take you to law.
You have no case.
Lawyer J. Noble Daggett of Dardanelle,
Arkansas may think otherwise.
As might a jury, petitioned by a
widow and three small children.
I will pay $200 to
your father's estate
when I have in my hand a
letter from your lawyer,
absolving me of all liability from
the beginning of the world to date.
I'll take $200 for Judy,
plus one hundred for the ponies,
and $25 for the grey horse
that Tom Chaney left.
He was easily worth forty.
That is $325, total.
The ponies have no part in it.
I will not buy them.
Then the price for
Judy is $325.
I would not pay $325
for winged Pegasus.
As for the grey horse,
it does not belong to you.
The grey horse was lent to
Tom Chaney by my father.
Chaney only had
the use of him.
I will pay $225 and
keep the grey horse.
- I don't want the ponies.
- I can't accept that.
There will be no settlement after
I leave this office. It will go to law.
All right, this is my last offer.
$250. For that, I get the
release previously discussed
and I keep your father's saddle.
The grey horse is
not yours to sell.
The saddle is not for sale.
I will keep it.
Lawyer Daggett will prove the
ownership of the grey horse.
He will come after you with a
- Writ of Replevin.
- A what?
- Writ of Replev...
- All right, now look.
Listen very carefully,
as I will not bargain further.
I will take the ponies back,
and the grey horse, which is mine,
and settle...
for $300. Now you must
take that or leave it,
and I do not much
care which it is.
Well, Lawyer Dagget would not wish
me to consider anything under $325.
But I will settle for $320...
If I am given the
$20 in advance.
Now here's what I have
to say about that saddle.
Frank Ross's daughter...
Oh, my poor child...
Now are you going to be staying with us,
or are you hurrying back home to your mama?
I'll stay here if
you can have me.
I just spent last night
at the undertaker's,
in the company
of three corpses.
I felt like Ezekiel
in the valley of
the dry bones.
Well, God bless you.
Now you'll be rooming
with Grandma Turner.
We're having to double up, what with all the
people in town come to see the hanging.
This was in your
poor father's room.
That is everything.
There are no light
fingers in this house.
Now, if you need something
for to tote the gun around,
I can give you an empty
flour sack for a nickel.
What did you see
when you arrived?
A woman was out in the yard
dead with blow flies on her face.
An old man was inside with his breast blown
open by a scatter gun, and his feet burned.
He was still alive, but just was.
Said it was them two Wharton boys done it.
- Rode up, drunk.
- Objection.
Hearsay.
Dying declaration,
your honor.
Objection's overruled.
Proceed Mr. Cogburn.
Now them two Wharton boys, that'd be
Odus and C.C., throwed down on him,
asked him where his money was,
but he wouldn't tell them.
They lit pine knots and
held them to his feet.
He told them the money
was in the fruit jar.
Under a grey rock at the
corner of the smoke house.
And then?
Well, he died on us. Passed
away in considerable pain.
What'd you do then?
Me and Marshal Potter
went out to the smoke house.
And that rock had been moved.
The jar with the money in it was gone.
- Objection. Speculative.
- Sustained.
You found a flat grey rock in
the corner of the smoke house
with a hollowed out
space beneath it.
If the prosecutor is going to give
evidence, I suggest he be sworn.
Mr. Cogburn, what did you find, if anything,
in the corner of that smokehouse?
Found a flat grey rock with a hollowed
out space under it, nothing there.
- Then what did you...
- No jar or nothing.
And then what did you do?
Well, rode up to the Whartons near where
the North Fork strikes the Canadian...
- What did you find?
- branch of the Canadian.
I had my glass, spotted them two
boys and their old daddy, Aaron,
down the creek bank
with some hogs.
They'd killed a shoat
Had a fire built up under a
wash pot for scalding water.
What did you do?
Announced we was U.S. marshals,
I hollered out to Aaron
I needed to talk
to his two boys.
He raised an ax,
commenced to cussing us and
blackguarding this court.
What did you do then?
I backed away from the ax,
tried to talked some
sense into him.
While this was going on, C.C. he edges over
to the wash pot there, behind the steam,
and picks up a shotgun.
Potter seen him,
but it was too late.
C.C. Wharton pulled out on
Potter with one barrel.
Turned to do the same
for me and I shot him.
And the old man raised
the ax, and I shot him.
Odus lit out,
and I shot him.
C.C. Wharton and Aaron Wharton
were dead when they hit the ground.
Odus was just winged.
Did you find the jar
with $120 in it?
- Leading.
- Sustained.
What happened then?
Found a jar with $120 in it.
What became of
Odus Wharton?
There he sits.
You may ask, Mr. Goudy.
Thank you, Mr. Barlow.
Mr. Cogburn,
in your four years
as a U.S. marshal,
how many men have you shot?
- Never shot nobody that didn't ask for it.
- Well that was not the question.
How many?
Shot or killed?
Let us restrict it to killed, so that
we may have a manageable figure.
About twelve...
or fifteen. Stopping men in flight,
defending myself, et cetera.
Around twelve he says.
Or fifteen.
So many, you cannot
keep a precise count.
I have examined the records
and can supply the accurate figure.
Oh...
I believe them two Wharton boys
makes it twenty-three.
And how many members
of this one family,
the Wharton family,
have you killed?
- Immediate, or...?
- Did you also shoot Dub Wharton, brother?
And Clete Wharton,
half brother?
Well, Clete was selling ardent
spirits to the Cherokee.
He come at me
with a king bolt.
A king bolt?
You were armed, and
he advanced upon you
with nothing more
than a king bolt?
From a wagon tongue?
I've seen men badly torn up with nothing
bigger than a king bolt. I defended myself.
Returning to the other encounter,
with Aaron Wharton and
his two remaining sons.
You sprang from cover
with revolver in hand.
- I did.
- Loaded and cocked.
Well if it ain't loaded
and cocked, it don't shoot.
And like his son, Aaron Wharton
advanced against an armed man.
Well, he was armed.
He had an axe raised.
I believe you testified you backed
away from Aaron Wharton.
- That's right.
- Which direction were you going?
I always go backwards
when I'm backing up.
Very amusing.
Now he advanced on you much
in the manner of Clete Wharton.
Menacing you with that little ol' king bolt,
or rolled up newspaper, or whatever it was.
Yes, sir. He commenced
to cussing and
- laying about a threat.
- And you were backing away.
How many steps before
the shooting started?
Uh, seven to eight steps.
Good, and Wharton keeping pace,
advancing away
from his campfire.
Seven, eight steps.
What would that be?
Fifteen, twenty feet?
I suppose.
Will you explain to
this jury, Mr. Cogburn,
why Mr. Wharton was found immediately
by his wash pot, one arm in the fire,
his sleeve and hand smoldering?
Did you move the body
after you shot him?
Why would I do that?
You did not drag the body over
to the fire and fling his arm in?
- No, sir.
- Two witnesses
who arrived on the scene will
testify to the location of the body.
You do not remember
moving the body.
So it was a cold blooded bushwhack, while
poor Mr. Wharton was tending his campfire.
Objection.
If that's where the body was,
I might have moved him.
I do not remember.
Why would you move
the body, Mr. Cogburn?
Them hogs were moving around.
They might have moved him.
I do not remember.
Son of a bitch.
- Mr. Cogburn.
- What is it?
I'd like to talk to you a minute.
What is it?
They tell me you're
a man with true grit.
What do you want, girl?
Speak up, it's suppertime.
Let me do that.
Your makings are too dry.
I'm looking for the man who shot
and killed my father, Frank Ross,
in front of the
Monarch Boarding House.
The man's name
is Tom Chaney.
They say he's over in Indian territory,
and I need someone to go after him.
What's your name, girl?
My name is Mattie Ross.
We're located in Yell County.
My mother is at home looking
after my sister, Victoria,
and my brother, little Frank.
Best go home to them.
They'll need help
with the churning.
There is a fugitive
warrant out for Chaney.
Government will pay you $2 for bringing
him in plus 10 cents a mile for each of you.
On top of that, I will
pay you a $50 reward.
What are you?
What you got
there in your poke?
My god, a Colt Dragoon.
You're no bigger than a corn nubbin.
What are you doing with a pistol like that?
I intend to kill Tom Chaney with it.
- Kill Tom Chaney?
- If the law fails to do so.
Well that piece will
do the job for you,
if you find a high stump to rest it on,
and a wall to put behind you.
Nobody here knew
my father and I'm
afraid nothing's going to be done
about Chaney, except I do it.
My brother is a child, and my mother
is indecisive and hobbled by grief.
I don't believe
you have $50.
I have a contract
with Colonel Stonehill,
which he will make payment
on tomorrow or the next day.
Once our lawyer countersigns.
Don't believe in fairy tales or sermons
or stories about money, baby sister.
But thanks for the cigarette.
Isn't your mama
expecting you home, dear?
My business is not yet finished.
Mrs. Floyd, have any
rooms opened up?
Grandma Turner's...
the bed is quite narrow.
The second floor
back did open up.
But uh, that gentleman on
the porch has just taken it.
Oh, but don't worry
yourself, dear.
You're not disturbing
Grandma Turner.
My name is LaBoeuf.
I just come from Yell County.
We have no rodeo
clowns in Yell County.
A saucy line will not
get you far with me.
I saw your mother
yesterday morning.
She said for you to
come right on home.
What was your business there?
This is a man I think you know.
You called him
Tom Chaney, I believe
Though in the months I've been tracking him
he has used the name Theron Chelmsford.
John Todd Anderson,
and others.
He dallied in Monroe, Louisiana
and Pine Bluff, Arkansas
before turning up at
your father's place.
Then why did you not catch him at
Pine Bluff, Arkansas or Monroe, Louisiana?
He is a crafty one.
I thought him
slow witted myself.
That was his act.
It was a good one.
Are you some kind of law?
That's right.
I'm a Texas Ranger.
That may make you a
big noise in that state.
In Arkansas you should mind that
your Texas trappings and title
do not make you an object of fun.
Why have you been
ineffectually pursuing Chaney?
He shot and killed a state senator
named Bibbs in Waco, Texas.
Bibbs' family put out a reward.
And how came Chaney to
shoot a state senator?
My understanding is there
was an argument about a dog.
You know anything about the
whereabouts of Chaney?
Well he's in the territory, and I hold out
little hope for you winning your bounty.
- Why is that?
- My man will beat you to it.
I've hired a deputy marshal.
The toughest one they have.
And he's familiar with the Lucky Ned Pepper
gang they say Chaney's tied up with.
Well, I will throw in with
you and your marshal.
- No, Marshal Cogburn and I are fine.
- It'll be to our mutual advantage.
Your marshal, I presume,
knows the territory.
I know Chaney. It's at least a
two-man job to take him in alive.
When Chaney is taken, he's coming
back to Fort Smith to hang.
I'm not having him go to Texas
to hang for shooting some senator.
It is not important
where he hangs, is it?
It is to me.
Is it to you?
It means a great deal
of money to me.
It's been many months' work.
Oh, I'm sorry that you're paid
piecework and not on wages.
And that you have been eluded
the winter long by a half-wit.
You give out very little sugar
with your pronouncements.
When I sat there watching you,
I gave some thought to stealing a kiss,
though you are very young and sick,
and unattractive to boot.
But now I have a mind to give you
five or six good licks with my belt.
One would be as
unpleasant as the other.
If you wet your comb,
you might tame that cowlick.
Madame, I wish you would
leave these matters
entirely to me,
or at the very least,
do me the courtesy of consulting me
before entering such agreements.
I am not scolding you, but I am
saying your headstrong ways
will lead you into a
tight corner one day.
I trust the enclosed document
will let you conclude your business
and return to Yell County.
Yours, J. Noble Daggett.
I was as bad yesterday
as you look today.
I was forced to share a
bed with Grandma Turner.
I'm not acquainted
with Grandma Turner.
She is a resident of the city. It does
not surprise me that she carries disease.
This malarial place has
ruined my health,
as it has my finances.
I owe you money.
You have not traded poorly.
Oh, certainly not.
I'm paying you for a
horse I do not possess,
and I bought back a
string of useless ponies
which I cannot sell again.
You're forgetting
the grey horse.
Crow bait.
You are looking at the
thing in the wrong light.
I am looking at it in the light
of God's eternal truth.
Your illness is putting you down
in the dumps.
You will soon find another
buyer for the ponies.
Well I have a tentative
offer of $10 per head
From the "Pfitzer Soap
Works" of Little Rock
It would be a shame to destroy
such spirited horse flesh.
So it would. I'm confident
the deal will fall through.
Look here, I need a pony and I
will pay $10 for one of them.
No, that's a lot price.
No, no, it...
Wait a minute.
Are we trading again?
This one is beautiful.
He don't know
he got a rider.
You're too light.
He thinks he's got
a horsefly on him.
He's very spirited.
I'll call him "Little Blackie".
That's a good name.
What does he
like for a treat?
Well, ma'am, he's a horse.
So he likes apples.
Thank Mr. Stonehill for me.
No, ma'am, I ain't supposed
to utter your name.
See, sleep.
That is fine.
I will wake him.
Marshal Cogburn.
It is I, Mattie Ross,
your employer.
How long 'till you're
ready to go?
Go where?
To the Indian Territory
to pursue Tom Chaney.
Oh, you're the grieved girl
with stories of El Dorado.
Huh. How much
money you got there?
I said $50 to achieve Chaney.
You did not believe me?
I did not know.
You're a hard one to figure.
How long for you to
make ready to depart?
Well, hold on, sis.
Though I remember your offer,
I do not remember agreeing to it.
If I'm to go up against Ned Pepper,
I'll need $100.
That much I can tell you. $100.
To retrieve your man, $100.
I will take that $50 in advance.
It'll be for expenses.
You are trying to
take advantage of me.
I am giving you
the children's rate.
I'm not a sharper.
I'm an old man sleeping in a rope bed
in a room behind a Chinese grocery.
- I have nothing.
- You want to be kept in whiskey.
I don't need to buy that.
I'd confiscate it.
I'm an officer of the court.
Ah, thank you.
$100. That's the rate.
Then I shall not niggle.
Can we depart this afternoon?
We?
You're not going.
That ain't no part of it.
You have misjudged me if you think
I'm silly enough to give you $50
and watch you simply ride off.
I am a bonded U.S. marshal.
That weighs but little with me.
I will see the thing done.
Damn ducks. Can't go
after Ned Pepper.
Man's a hard man, and to look
after a baby at the same time...
I am not a baby.
Won't be stopping
at boarding houses,
where there's a warm bed
and hot grub on the table.
I'll be grabbing a
saddle. Eating light.
When the sleeping is done,
it'll take place on the ground.
Well I have slept
out at night before.
Papa took me and little Frank 'coon
hunting last summer on the Petit Jean.
We were in the woods all night.
We sat around a big fire
and told ghost stories.
We had a good time.
'Coon hunting?
This ain't no 'coon hunt.
It is the same idea
as a 'coon hunt.
Don't come within forty
miles of being a coon hunt.
You are just trying to make your
work sound harder than it is.
Here's the money.
Now I aim to get Tom Chaney,
and if you are not game, I will
find somebody who is game.
All I've heard out of
you so far is talk.
I know you can drink whiskey,
and snore and spit and wallow in
filth and bemoan your station.
The rest has been braggadocio.
They told me you had grit
and that is why I came to you.
I'm not paying for talk.
I can get all the talk I need and
more at the Monarch Boarding House.
Leave your money.
Meet me here at 7:00 tomorrow morning
and we can begin our 'coon hunt.
Dearest Mother,
I am about to embark
on a great adventure.
I have learned that Tom
Chaney has fled into the wild.
And I shall assist the
authorities in pursuit.
You know that Papa would
want me to be firm in the right,
as he always was.
So do not fear on my account.
Though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death,
I shall fear no evil.
The author of all things watches
over me, and I have a fine horse.
Kiss little Frankie for me,
and pinch Violet's cheek.
Their Papa's death
will soon be avenged.
I am off for the
Choctaw Nation.
Where's Marshal Cogburn?
Went away.
Left this.
Here inside is a train
ticket for your return home.
Use it.
By the time you read this, I will be
across the river in the Indian Nation.
Pursuit would be futile.
I will return with
your man, Chaney.
Leave me to my work.
Reuben Cogburn.
Is that Marshal Cogburn?
That is the man.
Who's he with?
I do not know.
Well take me across.
So you're the runaway.
Marshal told me you'd show up.
I'm to present you to the Sheriff.
That is a story. Let go of my horse.
I have business across the river.
If you don't turn around and take me
across, you may find yourself in court,
where you don't want to be.
I have a good lawyer.
Hey!
Go, Little Blackie.
Come on.
That is quite a horse.
I will give you $10 for him.
From the money
you stole from me?
It was not stolen.
I'm out for your man.
I was to accompany you.
If I do not, there is no agreement
and my money was stolen.
Why don't you put this
child back on the ferry.
It's a long road and time's a' wasting.
If I go back, it's to the office of the U.S.
marshals to report the theft of my money.
And "fudel", Marshal Cogburn?
Pursuit would be "fudel"?
It's not spelled F-U-D-E-L.
It's time for your spanking.
Now you will do as
the grown-ups say,
or I will get myself a birch
switch and stripe your leg.
Are you going to let
him do this, Marshal?
No, I don't believe I will.
Put your switch away, LaBoeuf.
I aim to finish what I started.
That'll be the biggest
mistake you ever made,
you Texas brush-popper.
Hoorawed by a little girl.
I am not accustomed
to so large a fire.
In Texas, we make do with
a fire little more than twigs.
Buffalo chips.
Heat the night's
ration of beans.
And it is Ranger policy never to make your
camp in the same place as your cook fire.
Very imprudent to make your
presence known in unsettled country.
How do you know Bagby
will have intelligence?
He has a store.
That makes him an authority
on movements in the Territory?
We have entered a wild place,
and anyone coming in
wanting any kind of supply
cannot pick and
choose his portal.
That is a piece of foolishness.
All the snakes are
asleep this time of year.
They have been
known to wake up.
Well let me have a rope, too.
A snake would not bother you.
You are too little and bony.
You should fetch water for
the morning. Put it by the fire.
- The creek will ice over tonight.
- I'm not going down there again.
If you want any more water,
you can fetch it yourself.
You're lucky to be traveling in a
place where a spring is so handy.
In my country, you could ride for
days and see no ground water.
I have lapped filthy
water from a hoof-print
and was glad to have it.
If I ever meet one
of you Texas boys
who says he has never drank
water out of a horse-track,
I think I'd shake his hand and
give him a Daniel Webster cigar.
You do not believe it?
Oh, I believed it the
first 25 times I heard it.
Maybe... maybe it is true.
Maybe lapping water off
the ground is Ranger policy.
You're getting ready to show
your ignorance now, Cogburn.
I don't mind a little
personal chaffing.
But I won't hear anything against the
Ranger troop from a man like you.
How long you boys been
mounted on sheep down there?
My white Appaloosa
will still be galloping
when that big American stud of
yours is winded and collapsed.
Now make another joke about it.
You're only trying to put on
a show for this girl, Mattie,
with what you must
think is a keen tongue.
This is like women talking.
Yes, that is the way.
Make me out foolish
in this girl's eyes.
I think she has you
pretty well figured.
Would you two like to hear the
story of the Midnight Caller?
One of you is gonna
have to be the caller,
and I will tell you what to say.
And I will do all the
other parts myself.
- Good morning, Marshal.
- Morning.
Where's Mr. LaBoeuf?
Down by the creek
performing his necessaries.
Well, Marshal Cogburn, I welcome
the chance for a private parley.
I gather that you and
Mr. LaBoeuf have come to some...
some sort of agreement.
And as your employer, I believe I
have the right to know the particulars.
The particulars
is that we'll bring Chaney
down to the magistrate,
in San Saba, Texas, where they have a
considerable reward on him, which we split.
I did not want him
brought to Texas
to have a Texas punishment
administered for a Texas crime.
That was not our agreement.
What you want is to have
him caught and punished.
I want him to know he's being
punished for killing my father.
Well, you can let him know that.
You can tell him to his face.
You can spit on him,
make him eat sand out on
the road. I will hold him down.
Or if you want,
I'll flay the flesh off
the soles of his feet.
Find you Indian pepper
you can rub in his wound.
Isn't that a $100 value?
No, it is not.
When I have bought and paid
for something, I will have my way.
Why do you think I'm paying
you if not to have my way?
It's time for you to learn.
You cannot have your way
in every little particular.
If you find I failed to
satisfy your terms,
I'll return your money at
the end of this expedition.
Little Blackie and I are riding back to
the U.S. marshal's office. This is fraud.
God damn it.
What's going on?
This is a business conversation.
Is that what you call it?
Sounds to me you're still being
hoorawed by a little girl.
- You say, hoorawed?
- That was the word.
There is no hoorawing in it.
My agreement with the Marshal
ante-dates yours.
It has the force of law.
The force of law?
This man is a
notorious thumper.
He rode by the light of
the moon with Quantrill.
- And Bloody Bill Anderson.
- Them men were patriots, Texas trash!
They murdered women and
children in Lawrence, Kansas.
That's a God damn lie!
What army was you in, Mister?
I was at Shreveport.
- First with Kirby Smith, then with...
- Yeah? What side was you on?
I was in the army of
Northern Virginia, Cogburn.
And I don't have to hang
my head when I say it.
If you had served with
Captain Quantrill...
Captain! Captain Quantrill?
Indeed!
- Just let this go, LaBoeuf.
- Captain of what?
We're done.
There's not sufficient dollars
in the state of Texas
to make it worth my while to
listen to your opinion.
Our agreement is nullified.
That suits me.
It's each man for himself.
Congratulations, Cogburn.
You've graduated from
marauder to wet nurse.
Adios.
We don't need him,
do we, Marshal?
We'd miss his Sharps carbine,
It's apt to get lively out here.
Hey!
Go on.
You stay here, sister.
I will see Bagby.
Has Chaney been here?
No.
Coke Hays was,
two days ago.
Coke rides with Lucky Ned.
Bought supplies with this.
Well, this is Papa's gold piece.
Tom Chaney,
here we come.
Not the world's only
California gold piece.
They are rare here.
They are rare.
But if it is Chaney's,
just as easily mean that
Lucky Ned and his gang
fell upon him as that
he fell in with them.
Chaney could be a corpse.
That would be a bitter disappointment,
Marshal. What do we do?
Pursue them.
Ned's unfinished business
for the marshals anyhow.
When we have him,
we'll also have Chaney.
Or learn the whereabouts of his body.
Bagby didn't know
which way they went,
but now that we know
they come through here,
they couldn't be going
but one of two ways.
Heading north towards
the Winding Stair Mountains,
or pushing further west.
I expect north.
More to rob.
I found an eating place.
Called the Green Frog.
Started calling myself Burroughs.
But my drinking picked up.
My wife did not care for the
company of my river friends.
She decided to go back
to her first husband.
He was a clerk in
a hardware store.
She said, "Goodbye, Reuben."
"Love of decency does
not abide in you."
A divorced woman
talking about decency.
I told her, "Goodbye, Nola."
"Hope that little nail-selling bastard
keeps you happy this time."
She took my boy with her too.
He never cared for me anyway.
I guess I did speak
awful rough to him.
I did not mean anything by it.
You would not want to see
a clumsier child than Horace.
I bet he broke forty cups.
Is it Chaney?
I would not recognize
the soles of his feet.
Well, you'll have to
clamber up and look.
I'm too old and too fat.
Now the Green Frog
had one billiard table.
Served ladies and
men both. Mostly men.
Tried running it myself for a while,
but couldn't keep good help.
I never did learn
how to buy meat.
That him?
I believe not.
Well, cut him down.
Why?
I might know him.
That's when I went out
to the state plains of Texas.
Shooting buffalo with Vernon Shaftoe
and a Flathead Indian named Ollie.
Now the Mormons had run
Shaftoe out of Great Salt Lake City.
Don't ask me what for.
All a misunderstanding.
Leave it go at that.
Well, the big shaggies...
About all gone now.
Damn shame.
I'd give $3 right now for
a pickled buffalo tongue.
Why did they hang him so high?
I do not know.
Must play in the belief
it'd make him more dead.
I do not know this man.
You hanged him?
Why is he taking the hanged man?
Did he know him?
He did not.
But it is a dead body.
Must be worth something in the trade.
Now my second wife, Edna.
She got the notion she
wanted me to be a lawyer.
Bought this heavy book called
"Daniels on Negotiable Instruments".
Set me to reading it.
Never could get a grip on it.
I was happy enough to set
it aside and leave Texas.
There ain't six trees
between here and Canada.
Nothing else grows but
that has stickers on it.
Ask one of the...
- I knew it.
- Knew what?
We's being followed.
I asked that injun to signal with
a shot if someone was on our trail.
Should we be concerned, Marshal?
Naw, Mr. LaBoeuf is
using us as a bird dog,
in hopes of cutting in once
we've flushed the prey.
Perhaps we could double back over our tracks
and confuse the trail in a clever way.
No, we will wait right here.
Offer our friend a warm hello.
Ask him where he's going.
You are not LaBoeuf.
My name is Forrester.
I practice dentistry in the Nation.
Also veterinary arts and medicine
on those humans that
will sit still for it.
You have your work
cut out for you there.
Traded for him with an Indian who
said he came by him honestly.
I gave up two dental mirrors
and a bottle of expectorant.
Do either of you need
medical attention?
No. Say, it is fixing
to get cold.
You know of anywhere
to take shelter?
I have my bear skin.
You might want to head over
to the Original Greaser Bob's.
He notched a dugout into a
hollow along the Carrillon River.
If you ride the river,
you won't fail to see it.
Greaser Bob, the
original Greaser Bob,
is hunting north of the picket wire
and would not begrudge its use.
- Much obliged.
- Now, I have taken his teeth.
I will entertain an offer
for the rest of him.
Take my jacket.
Creep up onto the roof.
If they're unfriendly, I'll give
you a sign to damp the chimney.
Who's out there?
We're looking for shelter.
No room for
you here. Ride on.
- Who's in there?
- Ride on.
I'm a federal officer.
Who's in there?
A Methodist and
a son of a bitch.
This is Rooster Cogburn.
Columbus Potter and five other
marshals is out here with me.
We got a bucket of coal oil.
In one minute we will burn
your house from both ends.
There's only two of you.
Go ahead and bet
your life on it.
How many of you is in there?
Just the two of us.
But my partner's hit
and he can't walk.
Is that Emmet Quincy?
You said it was a
man on the roof.
I thought it was Potter.
You was always dumb Quincy,
and remain true to form.
This here's an awful lot of sofky.
You boys looking for company?
That was our supper
and breakfast both.
I like a big breakfast.
Sofky always cooks up
bigger than you think.
Hmm. Good store of
whiskey here, as well.
What are you boys up to,
outside of cooking banquets?
Just having our supper.
You don't know who's
outside in weather like this.
Might have been some crazy man.
Anyone can say that
he is a marshal.
My leg hurts.
I'll bet it does.
When was the last time you see
your old pard, Ned Pepper?
I do not know him.
Who is he?
I'm surprised you
don't remember him.
Skinny fellow, nervous and
quick, his lips all messed up.
That don't bring anybody to mind.
There's a new boy
that might be running with Ned.
He's got a powder mark
on his face, black flash.
Calls himself Chaney.
Or Chelmsford, sometimes.
Carries a Henry rifle.
That don't bring anybody to mind.
Black mark, I would
remember that.
You don't remember nothing
no more now, do you Quincy?
What do you know, Moon?
He don't know those
boys you're looking for.
I don't know those boys.
I always try to
help out the law.
By the time I get
to Fort Smith,
that leg will be swelled up
tight as Dick's hat band.
It'll be mortified.
They will cut it off.
And then, if you live, I'll get you two
or three years in the Federal house
- up in Detroit, there.
- What are you trying to get at?
They'll teach you how to
read and write up there,
but the rest won't be so good.
Them boys, they can
be hard on a gimp.
You're trying to get at me.
Now, you give me some
good information on Ned,
I'll take you down to Bagby's store tomorrow
and get that ball taken out of your leg.
Then I'll give you three
days to clear the territory.
We don't know those
boys you're looking for.
- It ain't his leg.
- I was...
Quiet now. It's best you
let me do the talking.
- I would say I...
- We're weary trappers.
Who worked you over
with the ugly stick?
The man, Chaney, with the
marked face, killed my father.
He was a whiskey drinker like you
and it led to killing in the end.
If you answer the Marshal's
questions, he will help you.
I have a good lawyer at home,
and he will help you too.
I'm puzzled by this.
Why is she here?
Don't go jawing with these people, Moon.
Don't you go jawing with that runt.
I don't like you. I hope you go to jail.
My lawyer will not help you.
My leg is giving me fits.
A young fellow like don't
want to lose his leg.
Easy, now.
He's trying to get at you.
- With the truth.
- We seen Ned and Hays two days ago.
Don't you act the fool.
You blow, I will kill you!
I'm played out,
I need a doctor.
We met Ned and
Hays two days ago.
God damn it.
Oh, Lord.
I'm dying.
Do something.
Help me.
I can do nothing for you, son.
You partner's killed you,
and I have done for him.
Don't leave me lying here.
Don't let the wolves rip me up.
I'll see you're buried right.
Tell me about Ned.
Where'd you see him?
Two days ago.
Bagby's store.
They were coming here tonight
to get remounts and sofky.
They just robbed the Katy Flyer
at the Wagoner's switch.
I'm gone.
Send the news to my
brother, George Garrett.
He is a Methodist Circuit
rider in south Texas.
Shall I tell him you've
outlawed up?
It don't matter.
He knows I'm on the scale.
I will meet him later,
walking the streets of glory.
Well, don't be looking for Quincy.
What will we do when
they get here?
When they ride up,
what we want is to get
them all in the dugout.
I'll kill them the last one that goes in,
then we'll have them in a barrel.
You'll shoot him in the back?
It'll give them to know
our intention is serious.
Then I'll call down.
See if they'll be taken alive.
If they won't,
I'll shoot them as
they come out.
I'm hopeful that three of their party being
dead will take the starch out of them.
You display great poise.
Aw, it's just a turkey shoot.
One time, in New Mexico,
we was being pursued
by seven men.
I turned Bo around and,
taking them reins in my teeth,
rode right at them boys, firing them
two Navy Sixes I carry in my saddle.
Well...
I guess they was all married
men who loved their families,
as they scattered
and run for home.
Well that is hard to believe.
- What is?
- One man riding at seven.
Well, it's true.
You go for a man hard
enough and fast enough,
he don't have time to think about how
many is with him. He thinks about himself.
And how he might get clear of that
wrath that's about to set down on him.
Why were they pursuing you?
I robbed a high interest bank.
Can't rob a thief, can you?
Never robbed a citizen.
Never took a man's watch.
It is all stealing.
That's the position they
took in New Mexico.
One man.
Did not figure them
to send a scout.
Damn.
It is LaBoeuf.
Oh, we have to
warn him, Marshal.
Too late.
What will we do, Marshal?
We sit.
What does he do?
Him in the wooly
chaps is Lucky Ned.
Well, that's that.
Well, that didn't pan out.
You managed to put a
kink in my rope, partner.
I'm severely injured.
Yes, you got drug some.
I was also shot
by a rifle.
Well, that's quite possible. The
scheme did not develop as I had planned.
You been shot in the shoulder,
but the bullet passed through.
What happened to your mouth?
I believe I bit myself.
Couple of teeth loose,
and... Oh, yeah.
Tongue bit almost through.
Do you want to see if it will knit,
or shall I just yank it free?
I know a teamster
bit his tongue off being
thrown from a horse.
After a time he learned to make
himself more or less understood.
I'll just yank it free.
What's that now?
Knit. Let it knit.
Ah, very well.
It's impossible to
bind a tongue wound.
Too bad, we just run
across a doctor.
- Marshal?
- of sorts,
but I do not know
where he was headed.
I saw him too, that's
how I came to be here.
Neither of these
men are Chaney.
I know it.
I know them both.
That ugly one is Coke Hays.
Him uglier still is
Clement Parmalee.
Parmalee and his brothers have a
silver claim in Winding Stair Mountains.
And I bet that's where
Lucky Ned's gang is waiting.
Well, we'll sleep here.
We'll follow in the morning.
But we promised to bury
the poor soul inside.
Ground's too hard.
Them men wanted a decent burial, they should
have gotten themselves killed in summer.
Sleep well, Little Blackie.
I have a notion that tomorrow
we will reach our object.
We're hot on the trail.
Seems that we'll overtake Tom Chaney
at the Winding Stair Mountain.
I'd not want to be in his shoes.
As I understand it, Chaney,
or Chelmsford, as he
called himself in Texas,
shot the Senator's dog.
When the Senator remonstrated,
Chelmsford shot him as well.
Now you could argue
that the shooting of the dog was
merely an instance of malum prohibitum.
But the shooting of a senator is
indubitably an instance of malum in se.
Malla-men what?
Malum in se.
The distinction is between an
act that is wrong in itself
and an act that is wrong only
according to our laws and mores.
It is Latin.
I'm struck.
That LaBoeuf
has been shot, trampled, and
nearly severed his tongue.
Not only does he not cease to talk,
but he spills the banks of English.
I was within 300 yards
of Chelmsford once.
The closest I have been.
With a Sharps carbine,
that is within range.
But I was mounted and had
the choice of firing off-hand
or dismounting to shoot from rest,
which would allow Chelmsford
to augment the distance.
I fired mounted,
and fired wild.
You cannot hit a man at 300 yards
if your gun was resting on Gibraltar.
A Sharps carbine is an instrument
of uncanny power and precision.
I have no doubt that
the gun is sound.
My clothes are all ragged and
my language is rough.
My bread is corn dodgers,
both solid and tough.
And yet I'm happy, and live at my ease
On sorghum molasses,
and bacon, and cheese.
Greer County Bachelor.
I do not believe he slept.
Fort Smith is a healthy
distance, LaBoeuf.
I would encourage the
creature you ride to head at her.
Out here a one-armed
man looks like easy prey.
And a one eyed man
who can't shoot?
Why don't you
turn back, Cogburn?
I'll do fine.
I know where the
Parmalee claim is.
I'm uninjured, well provisioned
and we agreed to separate.
In conscience you cannot cite our
agreement. You're the one who shot me.
Mr. LaBoeuf has a point, Marshal.
It is an unfair leg up in any competition
to shoot your opposite number.
God damn it. I do not accept it as
a given that I did shoot LaBoeuf.
There were plenty
of guns going off.
I heard the rifle,
and I felt the ball.
You missed your shot, Cogburn.
Missed my shot!
You are more handicapped without
the eye, than I without the arm.
I can hit a gnat's
eye at 90 yards.
That China-man is running
them cheap shells on me again.
I thought you were going to
say the sun was in your eyes.
That is to say, your eye.
Two at one time.
I'm going to chuck one high.
Go far.
- There.
- There?
- My bullet.
- Your bullet?
If you hit what you aim at,
explain my shoulder.
Gentlemen, shooting cornbread
out here on the prairie
is getting us no closer
to the Ned Pepper gang.
One more.
This will prove it.
Please hold fire.
Find our way back.
Where you've been to...
Lucky Ned?
Lucky Ned!
Very good, Cogburn.
Now what?
Oh, God damn it.
Cogburn does not want me
eating out of his store.
I am assuming you have not eaten
all day. And it is my store, not his.
Let him starve.
He did not track.
He did not shoot.
Except at food stuffs.
That was your initiative.
He did not contribute.
He's a man who walks
in front of bullets.
Mr. LaBoeuf drew single-handed
upon the Lucky Ned Pepper gang
while we fired safely from cover.
- We?
- It is unfair to indict a man
when his jaw is swollen,
and tongue mangled
and who is therefore unable
to rise to his own defense.
I can speak for myself.
I am hardly obliged to answer the ravings
of a drunkard, and it is beneath me.
I shall make my
own camp elsewhere.
It is you who has nothing
to offer, Cogburn.
A sad picture indeed.
This is no longer a man hunt.
It is a debauch.
The Texas Ranger
presses on, alone.
Take the girl.
I bow out.
A fine thing to decide once you brought her
into the middle of the Choctaw Nation.
I bow out. I wash my hands.
Gentlemen, we cannot
fall out in this fashion.
Not so close to our goal,
with Tom Chaney nearly in hand.
In hand?
If he is not in a shallow grave somewhere
between here and Fort Smith,
he is gone.
Long gone.
Thanks to Mr. LaBoeuf,
we missed our shot.
We've barked and
the birds have flown.
Gone, gone, gone.
Lucky Ned and
his cohort gone.
Your $50 gone.
Gone the whiskey,
seized in evidence.
The trail is cold,
if there ever was one.
I'm... I'm a foolish old man who's
been drawn into a wild goose chase
by a harpy in trousers,
and a nincompoop.
Ah, Mr. LaBoeuf.
He can wander the Choctaw
Nation for as long as he likes.
Perhaps the local
Indians will take him in.
Honor his gibbering
by making him chief.
You, sister, may
go where you like.
Our engagement is terminated.
I bow out.
I'm going with you.
No, that is not possible.
Have I held you back?
I have a Colt Dragoon revolver,
which I know how to use.
And I will be no more of a burden
to you than I was to the Marshal.
That is not my worry.
You've earned your spurs.
That is clear now.
You've been an regular
old hand on the trail.
But Cogburn's right,
even if I will not give him the
satisfaction of conceding it.
The trail is cold.
And I am
considerably diminished.
How can you give up now, after the many
months you've dedicated to finding Chaney?
You have shown
great determination.
I misjudged you.
I picked the wrong man.
I would go on in your company,
if there were a clear way to go.
But we'd be striking out blindly.
Chelmsford's gone.
We chased him
right off the map.
There's nothing for it.
I'm bound for Texas.
Time for you to go home, too.
The Marshal, when he sobers,
is your way back.
I will not go back. Not without
Chaney, dead or alive.
I misjudged you as well.
I extend my hand.
Mr. LaBoeuf, please.
Adios.
I know you.
Your name is Mattie.
You're little Mattie,
the bookkeeper.
Isn't that something.
Yes, and I know you,
Tom Chaney.
What are you doing out here?
Come to fetch some water.
No, what are you doing
in these mountains here?
Well, I've not been
formerly deputized,
but I'm acting as an agent for
Marshal Reuben Cogburn
and Judge Parker's court.
I have come to take
you back to Fort Smith.
Well, I will not go.
How do you like that?
There's a posse of officers up
there who will force you to go.
That is interesting news.
And how many is up there?
Right around fifty.
They're all well armed
and they mean business.
What I want you to do now
is to come on across the creek and
walk in front of me up that hill.
I think I'll oblige the
officers to come after me.
Well if you refuse to go,
I will have to shoot you.
Oh.
Well you'd better
cock your piece.
All the way back.
- 'Til it locks.
- I know how to do it.
Will you not go with me?
No, it's just the
other way around.
You're going with me.
I'm... Ah!
I did not think you would do it.
- What do you think now?
- One of my short ribs is broken.
You killed my father when
he was trying to help you.
I have one of the gold pieces you
stole from him. Now give me the other.
- Things aren't going right for me...
- Mattie!
- I'm down here.
- Now I'm shot by a child.
Chaney is taken into custody.
Help me!
Mattie!
Marshal.
Take them horses
you got and move!
Tom, you get on up that hill.
Don't you stop.
Who all's down there?
Marshal Cogburn
and 50 more officers.
You tell me another lie
and I'll stove your head in.
Just the Marshal.
Rooster.
Cogburn!
You hear me?
You answer me, Rooster.
I will kill this girl.
You know I will do it.
The girl is nothing to me.
She's a runaway from Arkansas.
That is all very well.
Do you advise that I kill her?
Do what you think is best, Ned.
She's nothing to
me but a lost child.
Think it over first.
I have already
thought it over.
You'll get mounted double fast.
If I see you riding over that
bald ridge to the northwest,
I will spare the girl.
You have five minutes.
There will be a party of
marshals here soon, Ned.
Let me have the girl and Chaney
and I will mislead them for six hours.
Too thin, Rooster.
Too thin.
Your five minutes is running.
No more talk.
Run up that hill.
Farrell, see to Tom's wounds.
Can I have some
of that bacon?
You help yourself.
Have some of the coffee.
I do not drink coffee.
I am fourteen.
Well we do not have buttermilk,
and we do not have bread.
We are poorly supplied.
- Where is she?
- What are you doing here?
- I ought to wring your scrawny neck.
- You let that go.
What happened, huh?
I will tell you, and you will
see that I am in the right.
Tom Chaney there shot
my father to death
at Fort Smith and
robbed him of
two gold pieces and
stole his mare.
I was informed Mr. Cogburn had grit
and I hired him to find the murderer.
A few minutes ago I came upon
Chaney watering the horses.
He would not be taken in
charge and I shot him.
If I had killed him, I would not now
be in this fix, but my revolver misfired.
They will do it.
It'll embarrass you every time.
Most girls like to play pretties,
but you like guns, do ya?
I do not care a thing in
the world about guns.
If I did, I would have
one that worked.
I was shot in an ambush, Ned.
The horses was blowing, making noise.
It was that officer that got me.
How can you sit there and
tell such a big story?
That pit is a hundred feet deep,
and I will throw you in it.
I will leave you to
scream and rot.
- Now how do you like that?
- No you won't.
This man will not let
you have your way.
He's your boss and you
have to do as he tells you.
Ain't nothing going my way.
Was that Rooster that
waylaid us night before last?
It was Marshal Cogburn
and myself.
You and Cogburn?
Quite the posse.
Let us move, Ned.
In good time, Doctor.
What happened to
Quincy and the kid?
They're both dead.
I was in the very middle of it,
it was a terrible thing to see.
Please, let us move, Ned.
The Marshal's gone.
Do you need a good lawyer?
I need a good judge.
What happened to Coke Hays?
The old fellow shot
off his horse.
Dead as well.
His depredations have
come to an end.
Your friend Rooster does
not collect many prisoners.
He is not my friend.
He's abandoned me
to a congress of louts.
You do not varnish your opinion.
Are we off?
Let us cut up the winnings
from the Katy Flyer.
There'll be time for
that at the old place.
- I will mount the grey.
- I have other plans for you.
Must I double mount
with the doctor?
- Move.
- No.
Too chancey with two men
up if it comes to a race.
Tom, you wait here with the girl.
When we reach Ma's house, I'll send
Farrell back with a fresh mount.
You will be out by dark.
We'll meet you at the old place.
I do not like that.
Let me ride with you, Ned.
Just out of here, anyway.
No. We are short a horse.
The marshals will come swarming.
Hours, if they come here at all.
They'll think that we've all gone.
I am not staying here
by myself with Tom Chaney.
That's the way I will have it.
He will kill me.
You heard him say it. He's killed my
father, and now you will let him kill me.
He will do no such thing.
Tom, you know the crossing at Cypress
Forks, near the log meeting house.
When you're mounted, you take
the girl and leave her there.
You understand, Tom?
Any harm comes to that child,
you'll not get paid.
Harold, let me ride up with you.
Harold, I will pay you
$50 out of my winnings.
I am not heavy.
Do the calf again, Harold.
Everything is against me.
You have no reason to whine.
You act as the bandit chief
instructed and no harm comes to me,
you will get your winnings
at the old place.
Lucky Ned has left me. I'm sure to
be caught when I leave on foot.
Must think over my position
and how I may improve it.
Where's the second
California gold piece?
What have you done
with Papa's mare?
Keep still.
Are you thinking
about the old place?
Look here, if you let me go,
I will swear to an affidavit,
and once you are brought to justice,
it may go easier on you.
I tell you, I can do better.
I don't need your affidavit.
All I need is your silence.
Your father was a
busybody like you.
In honesty, I do not
regret shooting him.
He thought Tom
Chaney was small.
And you...
You would give
me an affidavit...
You're all against
me, everybody...
That is Chelmsford.
Strange to be so
close to him at last.
Mr. LaBoeuf, how is
it that you are here?
I heard a shot.
Went down to the river.
Cogburn outlined a plan.
Mind your footing,
there's a pit there.
His part
I fear is rash.
He returns for Lucky Ned.
Hello, Rooster!
Will you give us the road?
One against four is ill-advised.
He would not be dissuaded.
Hello, Ned. How many
men is with the girl?
Just Chaney.
Our agreement is in force.
She was in excellent health
when last I saw her.
Farrell, I want you and
your brother to stand clear.
You as well, Doctor.
Have no interest in you today.
What is your intention, Rooster?
You think one on
four is a dogfall?
I mean to kill you in
one minute, Ned.
Or see you hanged at Fort Smith
at Judge Parker's convenience.
Which will you have?
I call that bold talk
from a one-eyed fat man.
Fill your hand,
you son of a bitch.
Shoot them, Mr. LaBoeuf.
Too far, moving too fast.
Well, Rooster,
I'm shot to pieces.
Seems neither of us
gets to see Judge Parker.
Oh, Lord.
Wahoo!
Some bully shot.
That was 400 yards, at least.
Well,
the Sharps carbine is a...
Stand up, Tom Chaney.
M... Mr. LaBoeuf.
Are you alive?
Mr. LaBoeuf!
Mr. LaBoeuf.
Are you there?
I'm here.
Can you clamber out?
I cannot.
There are snakes.
They awake?
Yes.
I'm bit.
Does Mr. LaBoeuf survive?
He does. Even a blow to the head could
silence him for only a few short minutes.
Where are you bit?
Look away, Mattie.
I have her.
Up with us.
Here Mr. LaBoeuf, take her.
She's snake bit.
We're off.
I'll send help for
you soon as I can.
Don't wander off.
We are not leaving him.
We must get you to a doc, sis,
or you're not going to make it.
I'm in your debt for
that shot, pard.
Never doubt the
Texas Ranger.
Come on.
Ever stalwart.
We must stop.
Little Blackie is played out.
We have miles yet.
Come on, you.
No!
That's it, come on now.
No, stop.
He's getting away.
Who's getting away, sis?
Chaney.
No... No!
No, no, no.
Oh, no.
No, stop.
I'm growing old.
A quarter-century
is a long time.
By the time we reached
Bagby's store,
my hand had turned black.
I was not awake
when I lost the arm.
The Marshal had stayed
with me, I was told,
'til I was out of danger.
But he departed before
I came around.
Once home, I wrote him
with an invitation
to come by the next time he
found himself near Yell County.
And collect the
$50 I still owed him.
I did not hear back
from Marshal Cogburn.
And he did not appear.
Then one day, I received a note from
the Marshal, with a flyer enclosed.
He said he was traveling
with a Wild West show.
Getting older and fatter.
Would I like to come visit him
when the show came to Memphis,
and swap stories with
an old trail mate.
He would understand if the
journey were too long.
Brief though his note was,
it was rife with misspellings.
Yes'm?
I am Cole Younger.
This is Mr. James.
It grieves me to tell you that
you have missed Rooster.
He passed away
three days ago
when the show was
at Jonesboro, Arkansas.
Buried him there in a
Confederate cemetery.
Reuben had a complaint,
what he referred to as "night hoss".
And I believe the warm
weather was too much for him.
We had some lively times.
What was the nature
of your acquaintance?
I knew the marshal long ago.
We, too, had...
lively times.
Thank you, Mr. Younger.
Keep your seat, trash.
I had the body removed to our plot
and I had visited it over the years.
No doubt people talk about that.
They say, "Well, she
hardly knew the man."
"Isn't she a cranky old maid."
It is true, I have not married.
I never had time to fool with it.
I heard nothing more of
the Texas officer, LaBoeuf.
If he is yet alive, I would be
pleased to hear from him.
I judge he would be
in his seventies now.
And nearer eighty
than seventy.
I expect some of the starch
has gone out of that cowlick.
Time just gets away from us.
What a fellowship,
what a joy divine,
Leaning on the everlasting arms.
What a blessedness,
what a peace is mine,
Leaning on the everlasting arms.
Leaning, leaning,
Safe and secure from all alarms.
Leaning on the everlasting arms.
Oh, how sweet to walk
in this pilgrim way,
Leaning on the everlasting arms
Oh, how bright the path
grows from day to day,
Leaning on the everlasting arms.
Leaning, leaning,
Safe and secure from all alarms.
I'm leaning on the everlasting arms.
Lawman666
www.addic7ed.com